{
  "sections": [
    {
      "wordsets": [
        {
          "title": "5.1",
          "definitions": {
            "ADHERE": {
              "word": "ADHERE",
              "phonetic": "(ad-hEr')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to stick, hold fast </p><p>To ADHERE to something is to stick to it. Physical objects can ADHERE to other objects, and people can ADHERE to goals, beliefs, causes, and the like. </p><p>“The glue made the paper ADHERE to the table.</p><p>“She ADHERED to her position even after she had been proved wrong.</p><p>“I try to ADHERE to the Golden Rule in my everyday life.” </p><p>The most common mistake on the Pretest is to choose loosen as the meaning of ADHERE. This is a confusion of a word with its opposite. </p><p>Other forms of the word: ADHERENCE, n. ADHERENT, n. </p><p>Usage: ADHERE is usually followed by <i class=“def-ital\">to</i>.</p>"
            },
            "CONTEMPTUOUS": {
              "word": "CONTEMPTUOUS",
              "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn'-temp-chU-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">showing CONTEMPT, scornful  </p><p>CONTEMPT is an attitude in which you despise or look down on someone or something. </p><p>“He felt nothing but CONTEMPT for students who cheated on tests.</p><p>” CONTEMPTUOUS is an adjective from CONTEMPT; it means “showing or feeling CONTEMPT.” See <i class=“def-ital\">-ous</i> under Suffixes. </p><p>“She was CONTEMPTUOUS of people who used any means to get their own way.” </p><p>“The baseball coach was CONTEMPTUOUS of my attempt to throw a curveball.” </p><p>The most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest is <i class=“def-ital\">disgusting</i>. This may be due to confusion between CONTEMPTUOUS and CONTEMPTIBLE. CONTEMPTIBLE means “worthy of scorn or CONTEMPT.” </p><p>“Beating the dog severely was a CONTEMPTIBLE action. We are all CONTEMPTUOUS of such disgraceful behavior.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: CONTEMPT, n. CONTEMPTIBLE, adj.</p>"
            },
            "CORDIAL": {
              "word": "CORDIAL",
              "phonetic": "(kor'-jÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">warm, heartfelt, sincere </p><p>CORDIAL comes from the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">heart</i>. CORDIAL means “coming from the heart\"; the word is used about warm, sincere people and what they do or say. See <i class=“def-ital\">-al</i> under Suffixes. </p><p>“Our host gave us a CORDIAL greeting when we arrived for the party.” </p><p>“She was not very CORDIAL to us when we told her we didn’t have enough money to pay the bill.” </p><p>“You are CORDIALLY invited to a fashion show next Saturday evening.” </p><p>CORDIALITY is warm affection or kindness. </p><p>“Her CORDIALITY to the stranger made him feel like one of the family.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: CORDIALITY, n.</p>"
            },
            "DISGRUNTLE": {
              "word": "DISGRUNTLE",
              "phonetic": "(dis-gruhn'-tÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to dissatisfy, make discontented  </p><p>DISGRUNTLE is related to the word <i class=“def-ital\">grunt</i>. Someone who is DISGRUNTLED has been put into a bad humor, has been made dissatisfied and discontented. </p><p>“The workers were DISGRUNTLED at having to come in on their day off.” </p><p>“The DISGRUNTLED students complained to the teacher about the unfair test.” </p><p>“Jim was DISGRUNTLED to find out that someone else was going to play instead of him.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: DISGRUNTLEMENT, n. </p><p>Usage: DISGRUNTLE is usually used in the form DISGRUNTLED.</p>"
            },
            "EXORBITANT": {
              "word": "EXORBITANT",
              "phonetic": "(eg-zor'-bÔøΩ-tÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">unreasonable, excessive, extravagant </p><p>See <i class=“def-ital\">ex-</i> under Prefixes and <i class=“def-ital\">-ant</i> under Suffixes. An <i class=“def-ital\">orbit</i> is a track or path, especially the path through space taken by an artificial satellite, the moon, or a planet. Something which is EXORBITANT is off the track, outside the usual course things take. The word is used about prices, claims, demands, and similar things to show that they are far beyond their usual limits. </p><p>“I wanted to buy the hat, but I thought the price was EXORBITANT.” </p><p>“Her demands were so EXORBITANT that we wouldn’t even consider them.” </p><p>“His claims for the new drug were EXORBITANT: he said it would cure any disease.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: EXORBITANCE, n.</p>"
            },
            "HOARD": {
              "word": "HOARD",
              "phonetic": "(herd)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a hidden supply, secret accumulation </p><p>A HOARD is a hidden supply of something valuable saved up for future use. </p><p>“The squirrel kept a HOARD of nuts in the hollow trunk of the tree.” </p><p>“They found a HOARD of gold coins which someone had hidden away in the cellar.” </p><p>To HOARD something is to save it up, to gather it into a HOARD, sometimes in a greedy way. </p><p>“Expecting a food shortage, people started to HOARD flour and sugar.” </p><p>“The pirates HOARDED their treasure.”</p>"
            },
            "JEST": {
              "word": "JEST",
              "phonetic": "(jest)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a joke, funny remark </p><p>JEST is a rather formal word for <i class=“def-ital\">joke.</i> </p><p>“Only a few of his JESTS were funny.” </p><p>To say something “in JEST” is to say it in fun, without being serious. </p><p>A JESTER is someone who makes JESTS; it was especially used about a professional fool or clown who worked for a king or nobleman. </p><p>“He was the court JESTER. He had to make everyone laugh even when he was sad.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: JESTER, n.</p>"
            },
            "MAUL": {
              "word": "MAUL",
              "phonetic": "(mol)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to handle roughly and injuriously, beat, bruise </p><p>A MAUL is a heavy hammer. MAUL also used to be the name of a heavy club used as a weapon. To MAUL someone is to treat or handle him roughly, as if you were hitting him with a heavy club. </p><p>“The vicious mob MAULED the foreigners.” </p><p>“He went too close to the cage and was MAULED by the tiger.”</p>"
            },
            "RENOWN": {
              "word": "RENOWN",
              "phonetic": "(ri-nown')",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">fame, celebrity, distinction, honor </p><p>RENOWN is widespread fame and honor. RENOWN is a very positive word; it suggests that the fame is due to great accomplishments or virtues. </p><p>“She is a writer of great RENOWN. She has won all kinds of awards.” </p><p>“The city enjoys considerable RENOWN for its many fine museums and parks.” </p><p>“Despite the actor’s RENOWN the play was not very popular.” </p><p>RENOWNED means “having RENOWN,” <i class=“def-ital\">famous</i>. </p><p>“The RENOWNED general is paying us a visit.” </p><p>“Her pies are RENOWNED for their great flavor.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: RENOWNED, adj.</p>"
            },
            "SLIPSHOD": {
              "word": "SLIPSHOD",
              "phonetic": "(slip'-shod)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">careless, sloppy </p><p>SLIPSHOD used to mean “wearing slippers or shoes that are run down at the heels.” From this idea of wearing old slippers SLIPSHOD has come to mean generally <i class=“def-ital\">careless</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">sloppy</i>. </p><p>“I will not pay for such SLIPSHOD work; you’ll have to do it over again.” </p><p>“She is SLIPSHOD in her use of words.” </p><p>“He made a SLIPSHOD attempt to straighten up his room.” </p><p>Many people think SLIPSHOD means <i class=“def-ital\">incomplete</i>. The two words are close, since a SLIPSHOD job might involve leaving the work <i class=“def-ital\">incomplete</i>. The emphasis in SLIPSHOD, however, is on the sloppiness and lack of care.</p>"
            },
            "SUFFICE": {
              "word": "SUFFICE",
              "phonetic": "(S;;l-fls')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to be enough, be sufficient, be adequate SUFFICE is a verb related to the word SUFFICIENT. To SUFFICE is to be SUFFICIENT, to be enough for a particular need or purpose. </p><p>“A few pages SUFFICED to show us that the book wasn’t very good.” </p><p>“He said that he would like twenty dollars, but that ten would SUFFICE.” </p><p>“Words cannot SUFFICE to make you understand how important this is.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: SUFFICIENT, adj.</p>"
            },
            "SURPLUS": {
              "word": "SURPLUS",
              "phonetic": "(ser'-pluhs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">excess, extra, left over </p><p>That which is SURPLUS is left over after use or need has been satisfied. It is more than what is necessary. </p><p>“Fewer people came than we expected, so we were left with SURPLUS food.” </p><p>“The farmers were able to sell their SURPLUS wheat.” </p><p>“Manufacturers could not get rid of their SURPLUS stock even at reduced prices.” </p><p>SURPLUS is also a noun; it is the amount that is greater than what is needed. </p><p>“One year there is a shortage of sugar, and the next year there’s a SURPLUS.” </p><p>“If you produce more than is required, you’ll be stuck with the SURPLUS.”</p>"
            },
            "UNITY": {
              "word": "UNITY",
              "phonetic": "(yU'-n:l-tE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">oneness; agreement </p><p>UNITY is related to the words <i class=“def-ital\">unify</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">unite.</i> All come from the Latin word meaning one. The basic meaning of UNITY is <i class=“def-ital\">oneness.</i> The word is applied to a whole which is made up of many different parts working together. </p><p>“The removal of any one part would spoil the UNITY of the design.” </p><p>“The various states sought UNITY with one another in their struggle against England.” </p><p>Often UNITY stresses the cooperation and agreement that this oneness brings. </p><p>“Despite their different backgrounds they lived and worked in UNITY.”</p>"
            },
            "CONTEMPLATIVE": {
              "word": "CONTEMPLATIVE",
              "phonetic": "(kon'-t:lm-plA-tiv)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">thoughtful, meditative, reflective </p><p>To CONTEMPLATE something is to think deeply about it or to look at it thoughtfully. </p><p>“She CONTEMPLATED the statue for hours.” </p><p>“He CONTEMPLATED the best way to escape from prison.” </p><p>CONTEMPLATIVE is the adjective from CONTEMPLATE. See <i class=“def-ital\">-ive</i> under Suffixes. A CONTEMPLATIVE person is inclined to think deeply about things. </p><p>“Whenever she was in a CONTEMPLATIVE mood she would sit and gaze out at the ocean for hours at a time.” </p><p>“His brother is energetic and quick to act, but Bill is very CONTEMPLATIVE. He likes to reflect upon things.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: CONTEMPLATE, v. CONTEMPLATION, n.</p>"
            },
            "CONTEMPORARY": {
              "word": "CONTEMPORARY",
              "phonetic": "(k:ln-tem'-p:l-rer-E)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">occurring at the same time, simultaneous; modern, current </p><p>Something which is CONTEMPORARY lives, exists, or occurs at the same time as something else. </p><p>“Shakespeare’s life was CONTEMPORARY with Francis Bacon’s.” </p><p>“The revival of learning in the Renaissance was CONTEMPORARY with the early explorations of America.” </p><p>“CONTEMPORARY authors all described the ancient king as being short and ugly.” </p><p>CONTEMPORARY also means <i class=“def-ital\">modern, up-to-date-</i> that is, existing at the same time we do. </p><p>“Jane decided to sell all her antique furniture and re- decorate her home in a more CONTEMPORARY style.” </p><p>CONTEMPORARY is also a noun which is used about people who live at the same time. </p><p>“Roberta and my sister, Lorraine, were CONTEMPORARIES at Columbia University.”</p>"
            }
          },
          "id": "1",
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Began to ADHERE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "loosen",
                    "heat up",
                    "cross",
                    "stick",
                    "melt"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADHERE",
                  "correct": "stick"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONTEMPTUOUS remark.",
                  "answers": [
                    "scornful",
                    "disgusting",
                    "complimentary",
                    "clever",
                    "silly"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONTEMPTUOUS",
                  "correct": "scornful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CORDIAL remarks.",
                  "answers": [
                    "witty",
                    "warm",
                    "chance",
                    "unfriendly",
                    "silly"
                  ],
                  "word": "CORDIAL",
                  "correct": "warm"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Everyone was DISGRUNTLED.",
                  "answers": [
                    "confused",
                    "disliked",
                    "dissatisfied",
                    "quiet",
                    "contented"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISGRUNTLE",
                  "correct": "dissatisfied"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXORBITANT claims.",
                  "answers": [
                    "loud",
                    "incorrect",
                    "roundabout",
                    "strange",
                    "unreasonable"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXORBITANT",
                  "correct": "unreasonable"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Discovered the HOARD.",
                  "answers": [
                    "food",
                    "cave",
                    "hidden supply",
                    "old man",
                    "secret passage"
                  ],
                  "word": "HOARD",
                  "correct": "hidden supply"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Strange JEST.",
                  "answers": [
                    "joke",
                    "show",
                    "song",
                    "warning",
                    "laugh"
                  ],
                  "word": "JEST",
                  "correct": "joke"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We will MAUL them.",
                  "answers": [
                    "join",
                    "threaten",
                    "laugh at",
                    "beat",
                    "soak"
                  ],
                  "word": "MAUL",
                  "correct": "beat"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "General RENOWN.",
                  "answers": [
                    "neglect",
                    "knowledge",
                    "opinion",
                    "agreement",
                    "fame"
                  ],
                  "word": "RENOWN",
                  "correct": "fame"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SLIPSHOD work.",
                  "answers": [
                    "incomplete",
                    "efficient",
                    "careless",
                    "unnecessary",
                    "tidy"
                  ],
                  "word": "SLIPSHOD",
                  "correct": "careless"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Will it SUFFICE?",
                  "answers": [
                    "help",
                    "finish",
                    "feel pain",
                    "need more",
                    "be enough"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUFFICE",
                  "correct": "be enough"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SURPLUS material.",
                  "answers": [
                    "useless",
                    "excess",
                    "military",
                    "old",
                    "needed"
                  ],
                  "word": "SURPLUS",
                  "correct": "excess"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "A certain UNITY.",
                  "answers": [
                    "oneness",
                    "strength",
                    "belief",
                    "area",
                    "distance"
                  ],
                  "word": "UNITY",
                  "correct": "oneness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONTEMPLATIVE people.",
                  "answers": [
                    "tricky",
                    "nasty",
                    "thoughtful",
                    "careless",
                    "active"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONTEMPLATIVE",
                  "correct": "thoughtful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONTEMPORARY ideas.",
                  "answers": [
                    "old-fashioned changeable",
                    "ancient",
                    "current",
                    "future",
                    null
                  ],
                  "word": "CONTEMPORARY",
                  "correct": "current"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Does peanut butter ADHERE to bread?",
                  "word": "ADHERE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would you like a person to show CONTEMPT for you?",
                  "word": "CONTEMPTUOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a CORDIAL person likely to be friendly to you?",
                  "word": "CORDIAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are happy people usually DISGRUNTLED?",
                  "word": "DISGRUNTLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most people like to pay EXORBITANT prices for food?",
                  "word": "EXORBITANT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it usually easy to find someone else's HOARD?",
                  "word": "HOARD",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a JEST supposed to make people laugh?",
                  "word": "JEST",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does MAULING a person cause him injury?",
                  "word": "MAUL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an evil person usually have great RENOWN?",
                  "word": "RENOWN",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most people like to buy a television that had been built in a SLIPSHOD manner?",
                  "word": "SLIPSHOD",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would fifty dollars SUFFICE to buy a new car?",
                  "word": "SUFFICE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do you have a SURPLUS of money when you're broke?",
                  "word": "SURPLUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do arguments increase UNITY?",
                  "word": "UNITY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you CONTEMPLATE when you are by yourself?",
                  "word": "CONTEMPLATIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is George Washington CONTEMPORARY with us?",
                  "word": "CONTEMPORARY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {}
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "He always ADHERED to the principle that honesty is the best policy.",
                  "word": "ADHERE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "I'm CONTEMPTUOUS of him because of the terrible things he does.",
                  "word": "CONTEMPTUOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His CORDIALITY offended all of us; he never spoke to us the entire time we were at his house.",
                  "word": "CORDIAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Ann was DISGRUNTLED when she learned that she would not be allowed to enter the contest.",
                  "word": "DISGRUNTLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "No one believed his claims until he showed how EXORBITANT they were.",
                  "word": "EXORBITANT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The old man was very generous; he always HOARDED money.",
                  "word": "HOARD",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He only made that remark in JEST; please don't be upset by it.",
                  "word": "JEST",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The boxer was MAULED by his larger and more experienced opponent.",
                  "word": "MAUL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "This artist is RENOWNED for her skillful use of bright colors.",
                  "word": "RENOWN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "I have never seen anyone looking so SLIPSHOD; her hair was freshly combed and her clothes were nicely cleaned and pressed.",
                  "word": "SLIPSHOD",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He was a light eater. He thought that two carrots SUFFICED for dinner.",
                  "word": "SUFFICE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Last year there was a SURPLUS of gasoline, but thi,!} year there is hardly any.",
                  "word": "SURPLUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "A meter is a UNITY of length.",
                  "word": "UNITY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She is CONTEMPLATIVE of anyone who isn't as pretty as she is.",
                  "word": "CONTEMPLATIVE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The author was widely admired by his CONTEMPORARIES, but after his death his reputation went down.",
                  "word": "CONTEMPORARY",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "ADHERE",
                  "answers": [
                    "find",
                    "join",
                    "attach"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADHERE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONTEMPTUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "despising",
                    "scornful",
                    "envious"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONTEMPTUOUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CORDIAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "wise",
                    "sociable",
                    "kindly"
                  ],
                  "word": "CORDIAL",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DISGRUNTLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "upset",
                    "displease",
                    "confuse"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISGRUNTLE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXORBITANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "immediate",
                    "excessive",
                    "extreme"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXORBITANT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HOARD",
                  "answers": [
                    "hide",
                    "seek",
                    "guard"
                  ],
                  "word": "HOARD",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "JEST",
                  "answers": [
                    "sing",
                    "kid",
                    "joke"
                  ],
                  "word": "JEST",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MAUL",
                  "answers": [
                    "bother",
                    "bruise",
                    "beat"
                  ],
                  "word": "MAUL",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RENOWN",
                  "answers": [
                    "glory",
                    "pleasure",
                    "honor"
                  ],
                  "word": "RENOWN",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SLIPSHOD",
                  "answers": [
                    "untidy",
                    "negligent",
                    "dishonest"
                  ],
                  "word": "SLIPSHOD",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SUFFICE",
                  "answers": [
                    "delight",
                    "satisfy",
                    "fulfill"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUFFICE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SURPLUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "left over",
                    "unnecessary",
                    "used up"
                  ],
                  "word": "SURPLUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "UNITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "whole",
                    "harmony",
                    "variety"
                  ],
                  "word": "UNITY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONTEMPLATIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "thoughtful",
                    "decisive",
                    "serious"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONTEMPLATIVE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONTEMPORARY",
                  "answers": [
                    "simultaneous",
                    "constant",
                    "present day"
                  ]
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "5.2",
          "definitions": {
            "OBSESS": {
              "word": "OBSESS",
              "phonetic": "(ob-ses')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to trouble continuously, haunt, beset </p><p>OBSESS was originally used about an army besieging a town or a fortress, or an evil spirit haunting or possessing a person. From these uses the word has developed its current sense, “to trouble or distress continuously, to influence unreasonably.” Now OBSESS is only used about ideas, fears, emotions, and other mental actions. </p><p>“She was OBSESSED by the idea that someone was out to kill her.” </p><p>“These suspicions OBSESSED him so much that he couldn’t sleep at night.” </p><p>“We were OBSESSED with the desire to become state champions.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: OBSESSION, n. OBSESSIVE, adj.</p>"
            },
            "EXULT": {
              "word": "EXULT",
              "phonetic": "(eg-zuhlt')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to rejoice, be very glad, be elated </p><p>EXULT comes from a Latin word meaning to <i class=“def-ital\">leap up.</i> Someone who EXULTS is so happy that he could jump for joy. EXULT means about the same as <i class=“def-ital\">rejoice,</i> but EXULT is even stronger, suggesting happiness and triumph that can scarcely be contained. </p><p>“We EXULTED over winning the championship.” </p><p>“They EXULTED in their good luck.” </p><p>EXULTATION is the noun from EXULT, meaning <i class=“def-ital\">great joy, jubilation.</i> </p><p>“We were full of EXULTATION when we passed the course.” </p><p>EXULTANT is the adjective from EXULT. </p><p>“The crowd was EXULTANT over the news.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: EXULTANT, adj. EXULTATION, n.</p>"
            },
            "MEDITATE": {
              "word": "MEDITATE",
              "phonetic": "(med'-::>-tAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to reflect, think, contemplate, ponder </p><p>To MEDITATE is to think deeply and seriously. </p><p>“He used to take long walks and MEDITATE upon the meaning of life.” </p><p>“She wanted to take some time to MEDITATE on these problems before making a decision.” </p><p>To MEDITATE something is to consider it or plan it in your mind. </p><p>“He MEDITATED revenge for all the wrongs that had been done to him.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: MEDITATION, n. MEDITATIVE, adj. </p><p>Usage: MEDITATE is often followed by <i class=“def-ital\">on or upon.</i></p>"
            },
            "DISINTEGRATE": {
              "word": "DISINTEGRATE",
              "phonetic": "(dis-in'-tÔøΩgrAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to break up, fall apart </p><p>When something DISINTEGRATES, it breaks up into small pieces. See <i class=“def-ital\">dis-</i> under Prefixes. </p><p>“The building DISINTEGRATED from the force of the explosion.” </p><p>“The rocks slowly DISINTEGRATED after centuries of storms and heat.” </p><p>To DISINTEGRATE something is to break it apart. </p><p>“One blow of his ax DISINTEGRATED the table.” </p><p>The most commonly marked incorrect answer on the Pre- test is <i class=“def-ital\">go away,</i> perhaps because DISINTEGRATE looks a little like <i class=“def-ital\">disappear.</i> Other forms of the word: DISINTEGRATION, n.</p>"
            },
            "SUMMIT": {
              "word": "SUMMIT",
              "phonetic": "(suhm'-it)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">the top, highest point, acme </p><p>The SUMMIT is the peak or highest point of something. </p><p>“After hours of climbing they reached the SUMMIT of the mountain.” </p><p>“He was at the SUMMIT of his powers when he was struck down by the illness.” </p><p>A SUMMIT <i class=“def-ital\">talk</i> or SUMMIT <i class=“def-ital\">meeting</i> is a conference of the highest-level officials of governments, such as the president of the United States and the prime minister of Great Britain.</p>"
            },
            "PROFICIENT": {
              "word": "PROFICIENT",
              "phonetic": "(pr::>-fish'-gnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">skillful, expert, adept </p><p>PROFICIENT means <i class=“def-ital\">very skilled</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">expert</i> at doing something. The word usually suggests that this skill is the result of training and practice. </p><p>“She worked hard to become a PROFICIENT typist.” </p><p>“Bob is very PROFICIENT at gardening. His roses have won prizes.” </p><p>“Sally is quite PROFICIENT in the art of making up excuses. She always has one ready when she hasn’t done something she’s supposed to do.” </p><p>The noun from PROFICIENT is PROFICIENCY, which means <i class=“def-ital\">skill.</i> </p><p>“She lacks PROFICIENCY in speaking a foreign language, but otherwise she’s perfect for the job.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: PROFICIENCY, n.</p>"
            },
            "CHRONIC": {
              "word": "CHRONIC",
              "phonetic": "(kron'-ik)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">constant, continual, long- lasting </p><p>CHRONIC comes from the Greek word for <i class=“def-ital\">time.</i> Some- thing that is CHRONIC lasts for a long time without change. The word is used especially about diseases or conditions which are difficult to cure or improve. </p><p>“She has CHRONIC arthritis in her hands and is con- stantly in pain.” </p><p>“The school was hampered by a CHRONIC shortage of money.” </p><p>CHRONIC is also used about a person who has a constant habit or disease. </p><p>“He is a CHRONIC complainer. He is always finding fault with something.” </p><p>“He has been a CHRONIC cigarette smoker for thirty years.” </p><p>The most popular wrong answer on the Pretest is <i class=“def-ital\">medical,</i> probably because CHRONIC is used so often about diseases. People who choose <i class=“def-ital\">medical</i> have seen the word CHRONIC used, but haven’t been able to narrow it down to its specific meaning.</p>"
            },
            "INDUCE": {
              "word": "INDUCE",
              "phonetic": "(in-dUs')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to persuade, influence, prevail upon; to bring about, cause </p><p>To INDUCE someone to do something is to lead or cause him to do it, usually by showing him the advantages that will result. </p><p>“We finally INDUCED him to be quiet by offering him an ice cream cone.” </p><p>“Nothing would INDUCE her to enter the haunted house.” </p><p>When used about things, INDUCE means to <i class=“def-ital\">bring about</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">cause.</i> </p><p>“His illness was INDUCED by poison gas.” </p><p>“The drug INDUCED a state of sleepiness.” </p><p>An INDUCEMENT is something which INDUCES, a <i class=“def-ital\">motive</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">incentive.</i> </p><p>“We offered to double his salary as an INDUCE- MENT for him to join our company.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: INDUCEMENT, n.</p>"
            },
            "PUNY": {
              "word": "PUNY",
              "phonetic": "(pyU'-nE)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">feeble, weak, small </p><p>Someone who is PUNY is smaller and weaker than normal. The word is usually used in an insulting manner. PUNY is also used about things and actions, and means <i class=“def-ital\">insignificant, petty.</i> </p><p>“Although very PUNY at birth, the puppy survived to become a champion.” </p><p>“His PUNY efforts to entertain the group were a complete flop.” </p><p>“They said he was too PUNY to make the football team.”</p>"
            },
            "PRECINCT": {
              "word": "PRECINCT",
              "phonetic": "(prE'-singkt)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a district, region </p><p>A PRECINCT is an <i class=“def-ital\">area</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">district.</i> In the United States, PRECINCT is most often used about a particular section of a town or city used for election or administrative purposes. </p><p>“We vote in the twelfth PRECINCT.” </p><p>“The policeman worked in the fourth PRECINCT.” </p><p>The word is also used in the plural for any area bounded by walls or other limits. </p><p>“You are now within the sacred PRECINCTS of the temple.” </p><p>Or the word can mean “the area immediately surrounding a place.” </p><p>“The king allowed no commoners in the PRECINCTS of his castle.”</p>"
            },
            "CLICHE": {
              "word": "CLICHE",
              "phonetic": "(klE-shA')",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a trite phrase, worn-out expression </p><p>Note the pronunciation. </p><p>A CLICHE is a phrase or expression which has been used so much that it has become trite, worn out, and stale. </p><p>“His speech was so full of CLICHES that we wondered if he had ever had one original thought.” </p><p>“You must try to avoid using CLICHES in your com- positions. Think of new ways to express your ideas.” </p><p>Some examples of CLICHES are “fresh as a daisy,” “last but not least,” “pretty as a picture,” and “hook, line, and sinker.”</p>"
            },
            "SULLEN": {
              "word": "SULLEN",
              "phonetic": "(suhl'-::m)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">gloomy, ill-humored, sulky </p><p>Someone who is SULLEN is moody, silent, and often bad-tempered. </p><p>“He was a SULLEN boy who always acted as if you had just insulted him.” </p><p>“Jane became very SULLEN when her parents refused to let her go to the party.” </p><p>“He gave them a SULLEN look and walked out of the house, slamming the door behind him.” </p><p>When used about things, SULLEN means <i class=“def-ital\">gloomy</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">dismal.</i> </p><p>“The sky was dark and SULLEN. It looked like rain.”</p>"
            },
            "PROLOGUE": {
              "word": "PROLOGUE",
              "phonetic": "(prO'-log)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">an introduction </p><p>A PROLOGUE is an introduction, especially one that comes before the beginning of a book or a play. See <i class=“def-ital\">pro-</i> under Prefixes. </p><p>“We recited the PROLOGUE to the Declaration of In- dependence.” </p><p>“Even though this book itself is very interesting, its PROLOGUE is very dull.” </p><p>PROLOGUE can also be used loosely about the introduction or first part of something. </p><p>“This small battle was a PROLOGUE to the long war that was about to start.” </p><p>Usage: PROLOGUE is sometimes spelled PROLOG.</p>"
            },
            "RELATE": {
              "word": "RELATE",
              "phonetic": "(ri-lAt')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to tell; to connect logically </p><p>RELATE is used in two different ways. To RELATE a story or experience is to tell it, to give an account of it. </p><p>“He RELATED how he had come to be president of the company.” </p><p>“She RELATED the story of the Headless Horseman.” </p><p>To RELATE one thing <i class=“def-ital\">to</i> another thing is to make or show a connection, or relationship, between them. </p><p>“It is hard to RELATE your results to what we already know.” </p><p>In an extended sense, when used about a person RE- LATE means “to have a meaningful RELATIONSHIP.” </p><p>“Helen found that she could RELATE very well to Phil even though he was much older.” </p><p>RELATED is an adjective which means <i class=“def-ital\">connected.</i> </p><p>“We didn’t know the two events were RELATED until much later.” People who are RELATED are connected by blood. “We are distantly RELATED. She is my third cousin.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: RELATED, adj. RELATIONSHIP, n.</p>"
            },
            "INTIMATE": {
              "word": "INTIMATE",
              "phonetic": "(in'-t::>-mit)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">very close, personal, private </p><p>INTIMATE is used in several senses, all with the general meaning of <i class=“def-ital\">close, personal, private. INTIMATE friends are very close, very deep friends. An INTIMATE conversation is a private, personal talk that you would not want to be overheard. A person who has an INTIMATE knowledge of a subject knows it extremely well, is deeply familiar with it. The INTIMATE details of an event or a per- son’s life are the private, secret matters that few people know about. </p><p>“The mechanic had an INTIMATE understanding of how cars work.” </p><p>“No one ever learned the INTIMATE secrets of her life.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: INTIMACY, n.</p>"
            }
          },
          "id": "2",
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Began to OBSESS him.",
                  "answers": [
                    "leave",
                    "hurt",
                    "upset",
                    "hate",
                    "haunt"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBSESS",
                  "correct": "haunt"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To EXULT over it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "worry",
                    "argue",
                    "cry",
                    "rejoice",
                    "laugh"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXULT",
                  "correct": "rejoice"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Time to MEDITATE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "speak",
                    "decide",
                    "reflect",
                    "get better",
                    "sleep"
                  ],
                  "word": "MEDITATE",
                  "correct": "reflect"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Starting to DISINTEGRATE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "break up",
                    "come together",
                    "shake",
                    "age",
                    "go away"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISINTEGRATE",
                  "correct": "break up"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Near the SUMMIT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "side",
                    "middle",
                    "end",
                    "bottom",
                    "top"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUMMIT",
                  "correct": "top"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Very PROFICIENT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "clumsy",
                    "expensive",
                    "skillful",
                    "lovely",
                    "friendly"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROFICIENT",
                  "correct": "skillful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CHRONIC problems.",
                  "answers": [
                    "constant",
                    "medical",
                    "new",
                    "past",
                    "foolish"
                  ],
                  "word": "CHRONIC",
                  "correct": "constant"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We INDUCED him to go.",
                  "answers": [
                    "begged",
                    "persuaded",
                    "forced",
                    "allowed",
                    "helped"
                  ],
                  "word": "INDUCE",
                  "correct": "persuaded"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PUNY men.",
                  "answers": [
                    "comical",
                    "mighty",
                    "sad",
                    "feeble",
                    "bad-smelling"
                  ],
                  "word": "PUNY",
                  "correct": "feeble"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Various PRECINCTS.",
                  "answers": [
                    "towns",
                    "policemen",
                    "districts",
                    "examples",
                    "jails"
                  ],
                  "word": "PRECINCT",
                  "correct": "districts"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Another CLICHE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "French recipe",
                    "average person",
                    "joke",
                    "old speech",
                    "trite phrase"
                  ],
                  "word": "CLICHE",
                  "correct": "trite phrase"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SULLEN men.",
                  "answers": [
                    "evil",
                    "cheerful",
                    "gloomy",
                    "thoughtful",
                    "selfish"
                  ],
                  "word": "SULLEN",
                  "correct": "gloomy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Read the PROLOGUE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "plan",
                    "introduction",
                    "speech",
                    "play",
                    "ending"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROLOGUE",
                  "correct": "introduction"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He RELATED the story.",
                  "answers": [
                    "waited for",
                    "told",
                    "thought up",
                    "heard",
                    "knew"
                  ],
                  "word": "RELATE",
                  "correct": "told"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INTIMATE conversation.",
                  "answers": [
                    "serious",
                    "general",
                    "important",
                    "long",
                    "private"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTIMATE",
                  "correct": "private"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Could the desire to make money OBSESS a person?",
                  "word": "OBSESS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an EXULTANT person be angry?",
                  "word": "EXULT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you MEDITATE upon something you don't understand?",
                  "word": "MEDITATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you DISINTEGRATE glass with a hammer?",
                  "word": "DISINTEGRATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do mountains have SUMMITS?",
                  "word": "SUMMIT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Should a doctor be PROFICIENT?",
                  "word": "PROFICIENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a CHRONIC problem usually be solved easily?",
                  "word": "CHRONIC",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can pepper INDUCE sneezing in people?",
                  "word": "INDUCE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a PUNY person be able to lift heavy weights?",
                  "word": "PUNY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can people live in a PRECINCT?",
                  "word": "PRECINCT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could the phrase \"cold as ice\" be considered a CLICHE?",
                  "word": "CLICHE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a child be SULLEN?",
                  "word": "SULLEN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do PROLOGUES come at the end?",
                  "word": "PROLOGUE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are brothers RELATED?",
                  "word": "RELATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do most people have hundreds of INTIMATE friends?",
                  "word": "INTIMATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "He ordered them to OBSESS their poor behavior.",
                  "word": "OBSESS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The good news was so unexpected that they couldn't hide their EXULTATION.",
                  "word": "EXULT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "For a long time she has MEDITATED quitting her job.",
                  "word": "MEDITATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They said they were DISINTEGRATED and wouldn't be able to go to the movies.",
                  "word": "DISINTEGRATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Jim gave a quick SUMMIT of his reasons for leaving.",
                  "word": "SUMMIT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He is not very PROFICIENT in math, so I doubt that he'll want to become an engineer.",
                  "word": "PROFICIENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Bill is a CHRONIC liar. He only lies when he absolutely has to.",
                  "word": "CHRONIC",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They INDUCED the number of students by transferring some to another school.",
                  "word": "INDUCE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "What a PUNY chicken; there's very little meat on its bones.",
                  "word": "PUNY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "More than half of the crimes in the city are committed in that one PRECINCT.",
                  "word": "PRECINCT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His speech was so full of CLICHES that I don't think he wrote one original line himself.",
                  "word": "CLICHE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The SULLEN sky seemed to add to our unhappiness.",
                  "word": "SULLEN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "As a PROLOGUE to the fashion show there was a brief speech about the history of clothes.",
                  "word": "PROLOGUE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We must speed things up. The project has become very RELATED recently.",
                  "word": "RELATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He developed an INTIMATE understanding of how governments work.",
                  "word": "INTIMATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "OBSESS",
                  "answers": [
                    "trouble",
                    "pretend",
                    "worry"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBSESS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXULT",
                  "answers": [
                    "elate",
                    "amuse",
                    "delight"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXULT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MEDITATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "discuss",
                    "contemplate",
                    "wonder"
                  ],
                  "word": "MEDITATE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DISINTEGRATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "tremble",
                    "break",
                    "crash"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISINTEGRATE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SUMMIT",
                  "answers": [
                    "greatest",
                    "newest",
                    "highest"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUMMIT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROFICIENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "competent",
                    "generous",
                    "capable"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROFICIENT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CHRONIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "temporary",
                    "continued",
                    "habitual"
                  ],
                  "word": "CHRONIC",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INDUCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "cause",
                    "influence",
                    "improve"
                  ],
                  "word": "INDUCE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PUNY",
                  "answers": [
                    "weak",
                    "young",
                    "small"
                  ],
                  "word": "PUNY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PRECINCT",
                  "answers": [
                    "source",
                    "area",
                    "section"
                  ],
                  "word": "PRECINCT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CLICHE",
                  "answers": [
                    "overused",
                    "stale",
                    "ancient"
                  ],
                  "word": "CLICHE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SULLEN",
                  "answers": [
                    "cross",
                    "afraid",
                    "glum"
                  ],
                  "word": "SULLEN",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROLOGUE",
                  "answers": [
                    "beginning",
                    "decision",
                    "preparation"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROLOGUE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RELATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "remember",
                    "tell",
                    "connect"
                  ],
                  "word": "RELATE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INTIMATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "personal",
                    "close",
                    "unusual"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTIMATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "5.3",
          "definitions": {
            "CONCUR": {
              "word": "CONCUR",
              "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-ker')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to agree; to happen together </p><p>To CONCUR with someone is to agree with him, to have the same opinion as he does. </p><p>“Everyone CONCURRED that this was the only ac- tion that could be taken.” </p><p>“The two of us did not CONCUR in our opinion of the movie.” </p><p>CONCUR can also mean “to happen or work together.” </p><p>“His father’s death and his accident CONCURRED, making it impossible for him to start college this se- mester.” </p><p>The noun from CONCUR is CONCURRENCE, which means <i class=“def-ital\">agreement.</i> </p><p>“With her parents’ CONCURRENCE she decided to take a year off from school.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: CONCURRENCE, n. CONCURRENT, adj.</p>"
            },
            "INITIAL": {
              "word": "INITIAL",
              "phonetic": "(i-ni'-shÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">beginning, first </p><p>INITIAL comes from a Latin word meaning <i class=“def-ital\">beginning.</i> This is also the source of the word <i class=“def-ital\">initiate,</i> which means to <i class=“def-ital\">begin, set going.</i> INITIAL means “of or at the beginning.” </p><p>“My INITIAL feeling was that he was being unfair, but later I changed my mind.” </p><p>“His INITIAL act as king was to release all the politi- cal prisoners.” </p><p>“INITIALLY we opposed the idea, but now we are in favor of it.” </p><p>INITIALS are the beginning letters of names. </p><p>“The INITIALS ‘U.S.A.’ stand for the United States of America.”</p>"
            },
            "ABDUCT": {
              "word": "ABDUCT",
              "phonetic": "(ab-duhkt')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to kidnap, carry off </p><p>To ABDUCT a person is to carry him off by force and illegally, to <i class=“def-ital\">kidnap</i> him. </p><p>“Two men ABDUCTED the child and held him for ransom.” </p><p>“The rich businessman was ABDUCTED yesterday by three masked men.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Harm</i> is often chosen as the meaning of ABDUCT in the Pretest. A person who is ABDUCTED may also be <i class=“def-ital\">harmed,</i> but ABDUCT means only to <i class=“def-ital\">kidnap.</i> Other forms of the word: ABDUCTION, n.</p>"
            },
            "ADVERSARY": {
              "word": "ADVERSARY",
              "phonetic": "(ad'-vÔøΩr-ser-E)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">an enemy, opponent </p><p>An ADVERSARY is an enemy or opponent, someone you fight with or have a contest with. </p><p>“Those two hated each other from the day they met, and they’ve been ADVERSARIES ever since.” </p><p>“Try to be nicer to people; don’t act as if everyone were your ADVERSARY.” </p><p>“Although the two lawyers often were ADVERSARIES in court, they were the best of friends otherwise.” </p><p>People often think an ADVERSARY is a partner, which is almost opposite in meaning.</p>"
            },
            "SABER": {
              "word": "SABER",
              "phonetic": "(sA'-bÔøΩr)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a sword </p><p>A SABER is a heavy military sword with a curved blade. It is also a fencing or dueling sword. </p><p>“The officer swung his SABER at the advancing enemy.” </p><p>“He stood at attention before the general, his SABER at his side.” </p><p>“SABER rattling” is a threatening display of military power of any kind. </p><p>“The enemy put thousands of troops on our borders and made insulting speeches about us. This SABER rattling didn’t bother us a bit.’’</p>"
            },
            "ARID": {
              "word": "ARID",
              "phonetic": "(ar'-ÔøΩd)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">dry, barren, parched </p><p>ARID means “without moisture,” <i class=“def-ital\">dry.</i> ARID is usually a somewhat stronger word than <i class=“def-ital\">dry.</i> Something that is ARID is totally dry and lifeless. When used about land, the word means specifically “without enough rainfall to grow crops.” </p><p>“Farmers couldn’t survive in the ARID regions of the West.” </p><p>ARID can also be used in a general sense to mean <i class=“def-ital\">lifeless, barren, monotonous.</i> </p><p>“The book’s treatment of history was rather ARID-it was just a listing of dates and names.” </p><p>“She fell asleep during the ARID discussion of the rules for the meeting.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: ARIDITY, n.</p>"
            },
            "CASCADE": {
              "word": "CASCADE",
              "phonetic": "(kas-kAd')",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a waterfall </p><p>A CASCADE is a fall of water over steep, slanted rocks, as in a river or stream. It is not just a straight fall of water but one that is broken up into a series of stages or steps. </p><p>“Halfway up the mountain we came upon a CASCADE of clear water that rushed over a series of jagged rocks high above us.” </p><p>CASCADE can be used about anything that falls or rushes forth in great quantity. </p><p>“The end of the symphony was truly magnificent, with its CASCADE of sound filling every corner of the huge auditorium.” </p><p>CASCADE can also be used as a verb meaning “to fall or pour down as if in a waterfall.” </p><p>“Yards of gorgeous lace CASCADED down the front of the bridal gown.”</p>"
            },
            "DILIGENT": {
              "word": "DILIGENT",
              "phonetic": "(dil'-ÔøΩjÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">hard-working, industrious, tireless </p><p>Someone who is DILIGENT works hard and carefully at something. He doesn’t let up or make silly mistakes. </p><p>“We will only hire DILIGENT employees. We want people who will put in a good day’s work.” </p><p>“They searched DILIGENTLY for the lost ring all day, but finally had to give up.” </p><p>“The DILIGENT student did his homework faithfully every night.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: DILIGENCE, n.</p>"
            },
            "ACCUSATION": {
              "word": "ACCUSATION",
              "phonetic": "(ak-yU-zA'-shJn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a charge </p><p>To ACCUSE a person is to declare that he is guilty of having done something wrong or evil, to charge him with something. </p><p>“The teacher ACCUSED him of stealing the watch.” </p><p>“I was ACCUSED of being one of the gang.” </p><p>If you are ACCUSED of a crime, it doesn’t mean you are guilty. It just means someone thinks you are guilty. </p><p>ACCUSATION is the noun from ACCUSE. It is a <i class=“def-ital\">charge,</i> a declaration of wrongdoing. </p><p>“There was an ACCUSATION in the newspaper that the mayor had accepted a bribe.” </p><p>“He denied all the ACCUSATIONS against him.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: ACCUSE, v.</p>"
            },
            "MEANDER": {
              "word": "MEANDER",
              "phonetic": "(mE-an'-dÔøΩr)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to wander, ramble, follow a winding course </p><p>The MEANDER was a river in ancient Asia noted for its winding course. As a verb, MEANDER means to <i class=“def-ital\">wander aimlessly,</i> without a destination. The word can be used about people, and about things like roads or rivers. </p><p>“The path MEANDERED through the forest.” </p><p>“After dinner they MEANDERED through the park for a while.” </p><p>“He MEANDERED from town to town, heading nowhere in particular.”</p>"
            },
            "ENCOMPASS": {
              "word": "ENCOMPASS",
              "phonetic": "(en-kuhm'-pÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to include, surround, encircle, envelop </p><p>One meaning of COMPASS is <i class=“def-ital\">limits</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">boundaries.</i> </p><p>“This subject is well within the COMPASS of our study.” </p><p>To ENCOMPASS something is to include it within a par- ticular COMPASS, to <i class=“def-ital\">encircle</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">enclose</i> it. </p><p>“These mountains ENCOMPASS the valley.” </p><p>“This book ENCOMPASSES the entire history of opera\"-that is, the entire history is included in the book. </p><p>“The study of art ENCOMPASSES painting, drawing, and sculpture.”</p>"
            },
            "EMBRYONIC": {
              "word": "EMBRYONIC",
              "phonetic": "(em-brE-on'-ik)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">undeveloped, im- mature, rudimentary </p><p>An EMBRYO is an animal in the early stages of its devel- opment before birth. The adjective from EMBRYO is EMBRYONIC, which means “like an EMBRYO.” See <i class=“def-ital\">-ic</i> under Suffixes. Since an EMBRYO is very young and un- developed, EMBRYONIC can apply to anything which is in its earliest stages, which hasn’t developed enough to be recognizable. Just as an EMBRYO turns into a mature adult, something which is called EMBRYONIC should be capable of developing into something much larger and more complete. </p><p>“The plans are still EMBRYONIC: it will take us a while to complete them.” </p><p>“When the industry was in its EMBRYONIC stages few people realized how important it would become.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: EMBRYO, n.</p>"
            },
            "AFFILIATE": {
              "word": "AFFILIATE",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩfil'-E-At)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to ally, associate </p><p>The Latin word <i class=“def-ital\">filius</i> means <i class=“def-ital\">son.</i> AFFILIATE comes from a Latin word which means “to adopt as a son.” In English the word has come to mean “to enter into associa- tion” or “to join as a member.” AFFILIATE usually sug- gests a close relationship, but one in which the various people or parts stay at least somewhat separate. </p><p>“Our team tried to AFFILIATE itself with the local softball league.” </p><p>“He is not AFFILIATED with any company. He works for himself.” </p><p>“The national organization has many local branches AFFILIATED with it.” </p><p>AFFILIATE is also a noun, pronounced :rfll’-E-:it. </p><p>“Channel 3 is an AFFILIATE of the CBS television network.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: AFFILIATION, n.</p>"
            },
            "BISECT": {
              "word": "BISECT",
              "phonetic": "(bl-sekt')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to cut in two, halve, split To BISECT something is to cut it into two, usually equal, pieces. The <i class=“def-ital\">bi-</i> part of the word means <i class=“def-ital\">two,</i> as in <i class=“def-ital\">bicycle</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">binoculars.<i class=“def-ital\">- The <i class=“def-ital\">-sect</i> part means <i class=“def-ital\">cut,</i> as in <i class=“def-ital\">dissect</i> (to cut apart) and <i class=“def-ital\">intersect</i> (to cut across). “The new road will BISECT the town neatly, passing right through the center of it.” “The 90¬∞ angle was BISECTED to make two 45¬∞ an- gles.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Double</i> is the most common incorrect answer on the Pre- test. People who choose it know that <i class=“def-ital\">bi-</i> means <i class=“def-ital\">two,</i> but don’t know its special use in BISECT.</p>"
            },
            "WRETCHED": {
              "word": "WRETCHED",
              "phonetic": "(rech'-ÔøΩd)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">miserable, foul, poor </p><p>A WRETCHED person is very unhappy or unlucky. </p><p>“I felt WRETCHED when I woke up this morning, but now I’m somewhat better.” </p><p>“This WRETCHED woman has had a hard life.” </p><p>A WRETCHED thing is of very poor quality. </p><p>“This book is WRETCHED. It is the worst I’ve ever read.” </p><p>“They live in a WRETCHED shack with no heat or running water.” </p><p>A WRETCH is a miserable person, either one who is very unfortunate or one who is very evil. </p><p>“Those poor WRETCHES are doomed to die very soon.” </p><p>“Some hateful WRETCH thought it would be fun to burn our house down.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: WRETCH, n.</p>"
            }
          },
          "id": "3",
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Will he CONCUR?",
                  "answers": [
                    "help",
                    "agree",
                    "decide",
                    "be there",
                    "argue"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONCUR",
                  "correct": "agree"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The INITIAL reports.",
                  "answers": [
                    "beginning",
                    "clever",
                    "shortened",
                    "final",
                    "latest"
                  ],
                  "word": "INITIAL",
                  "correct": "beginning"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To ABDUCT her.",
                  "answers": [
                    "save",
                    "admit",
                    "threaten",
                    "kidnap",
                    "harm"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABDUCT",
                  "correct": "kidnap"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His usual ADVERSARY.",
                  "answers": [
                    "partner",
                    "target",
                    "messenger",
                    "argument",
                    "opponent"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADVERSARY",
                  "correct": "opponent"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His SABER.",
                  "answers": [
                    "armor",
                    "spear",
                    "sword",
                    "cannon",
                    "fur"
                  ],
                  "word": "SABER",
                  "correct": "sword"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ARID places.",
                  "answers": [
                    "dry",
                    "rainy",
                    "bare",
                    "hot",
                    "green"
                  ],
                  "word": "ARID",
                  "correct": "dry"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Marvelous CASCADE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "stream",
                    "sunbeam",
                    "waterfall",
                    "mountain",
                    "tomb"
                  ],
                  "word": "CASCADE",
                  "correct": "waterfall"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DILIGENT teacher.",
                  "answers": [
                    "low-paid",
                    "strict",
                    "careless",
                    "wise",
                    "hard-working"
                  ],
                  "word": "DILIGENT",
                  "correct": "hard-working"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Another ACCUSATION.",
                  "answers": [
                    "remark",
                    "decision",
                    "charge",
                    "suggestion",
                    "problem"
                  ],
                  "word": "ACCUSATION",
                  "correct": "charge"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Tendency to MEANDER.",
                  "answers": [
                    "mumble",
                    "wander",
                    "dream",
                    "sleep",
                    "despair"
                  ],
                  "word": "MEANDER",
                  "correct": "wander"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "What does it ENCOMPASS?",
                  "answers": [
                    "point to",
                    "leave out",
                    "mean",
                    "include",
                    "matter"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENCOMPASS",
                  "correct": "include"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EMBRYONIC plans.",
                  "answers": [
                    "exciting",
                    "productive",
                    "undeveloped",
                    "complete",
                    "unusual"
                  ],
                  "word": "EMBRYONIC",
                  "correct": "undeveloped"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "No longer AFFILIATED.",
                  "answers": [
                    "separated",
                    "allied",
                    "admired",
                    "pleased",
                    "ashamed"
                  ],
                  "word": "AFFILIATE",
                  "correct": "allied"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BISECT it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "double",
                    "meet",
                    "decrease",
                    "halve",
                    "change"
                  ],
                  "word": "BISECT",
                  "correct": "halve"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They were WRETCHED.",
                  "answers": [
                    "captured",
                    "alert",
                    "soaked",
                    "sick",
                    "miserable"
                  ],
                  "word": "WRETCHED",
                  "correct": "miserable"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Do people usually get upset when someone CONCURS with them?",
                  "word": "CONCUR",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is December the INITIAL month of the year?",
                  "word": "INITIAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it against the law to ABDUCT someone?",
                  "word": "ABDUCT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would ADVERSARIES usually help each other?",
                  "word": "ADVERSARY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you cut someone with a SABER?",
                  "word": "SABER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a desert be ARID?",
                  "word": "ARID",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would molasses CASCADE out of the jar?",
                  "word": "CASCADE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are lazy people usually DILIGENT?",
                  "word": "DILIGENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are people who are ACCUSED of murder always guilty?",
                  "word": "ACCUSATION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do runners usually MEANDER toward the finish line?",
                  "word": "MEANDER",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does the atmosphere ENCOMPASS the earth?",
                  "word": "ENCOMPASS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an EMBRYONIC project be nearly finished?",
                  "word": "EMBRYONIC",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a person AFFILIATE himself with a political party?",
                  "word": "AFFILIATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a river BISECT a city?",
                  "word": "BISECT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do most people like to eat WRETCHED food?",
                  "word": "WRETCHED",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "No one CONCURRED with Jim's opinion that the earth is flat.",
                  "word": "CONCUR",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Their INITIAL findings were supported by later research.",
                  "word": "INITIAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Jane ABDUCTED to us that we weren't trying hard enough.",
                  "word": "ABDUCT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Poor people love this senator because he is their leading ADVERSARY in Congress.",
                  "word": "ADVERSARY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The scar on his face is the result of a SABER duel.",
                  "word": "SABER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Everyone became excited and angry during the ARID debate.",
                  "word": "ARID",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Her long hair fell over her shoulders in beautiful CASCADES.",
                  "word": "CASCADE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Jane was so DILIGENT we knew that nothing would get done while she was in charge.",
                  "word": "DILIGENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She was terribly upset by the ACCUSATION that she had lied.",
                  "word": "ACCUSATION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The speaker MEANDERED us to the point where we were all bored.",
                  "word": "MEANDER",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He ENCOMPASSED the dog by letting it run free.",
                  "word": "ENCOMPASS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His idea was at such an EMBRYONIC stage that we didn't know if it was any good or not.",
                  "word": "EMBRYONIC",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Our organization is not AFFILIATED with any other group.",
                  "word": "AFFILIATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He BISECTED the pie with a knife.",
                  "word": "BISECT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "That WRETCH made our lives miserable for years.",
                  "word": "WRETCHED",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "CONCUR",
                  "answers": [
                    "agree",
                    "consent",
                    "expect"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONCUR",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INITIAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "recent",
                    "first",
                    "earliest"
                  ],
                  "word": "INITIAL",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ABDUCT",
                  "answers": [
                    "steal",
                    "kidnap",
                    "chase"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABDUCT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ADVERSARY",
                  "answers": [
                    "opponent",
                    "soldier",
                    "rival"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADVERSARY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SABER",
                  "answers": [
                    "sword",
                    "arrow",
                    "blade"
                  ],
                  "word": "SABER",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ARID",
                  "answers": [
                    "waterless",
                    "aged",
                    "dull"
                  ],
                  "word": "ARID",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CASCADE",
                  "answers": [
                    "fall",
                    "pour",
                    "fly"
                  ],
                  "word": "CASCADE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DILIGENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "careful",
                    "busy",
                    "slow"
                  ],
                  "word": "DILIGENT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ACCUSATION",
                  "answers": [
                    "blame",
                    "admission",
                    "criticism"
                  ],
                  "word": "ACCUSATION",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MEANDER",
                  "answers": [
                    "ramble",
                    "search",
                    "stray"
                  ],
                  "word": "MEANDER",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ENCOMPASS",
                  "answers": [
                    "contain",
                    "describe",
                    "encircle"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENCOMPASS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EMBRYONIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "new",
                    "small",
                    "different"
                  ],
                  "word": "EMBRYONIC",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AFFILIATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "remember",
                    "join",
                    "associate"
                  ],
                  "word": "AFFILIATE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BISECT",
                  "answers": [
                    "smash",
                    "cut",
                    "split"
                  ],
                  "word": "BISECT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "WRETCHED",
                  "answers": [
                    "unhappy",
                    "dumb",
                    "disgusting"
                  ],
                  "word": "WRETCHED",
                  "correct": "1"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        }
      ],
      "reviewTest": {
        "wordList": [
          {
            "word": "ABDUCT",
            "answer": "abducted"
          },
          {
            "word": "CONTEMPORARY",
            "answer": "contemplative"
          },
          {
            "word": "EXORBITANT",
            "answer": "exorbitant"
          },
          {
            "word": "MEDITATE",
            "answer": "meditated"
          },
          {
            "word": "RELATE",
            "answer": "related"
          },
          {
            "word": "ACCUSATION",
            "answer": "accusation"
          },
          {
            "word": "CONTEMPTUOUS",
            "answer": "contemplative"
          },
          {
            "word": "HOARD",
            "answer": "hoard"
          },
          {
            "word": "OBSESS",
            "answer": "obsessed"
          },
          {
            "word": "SABER",
            "answer": "saber"
          },
          {
            "word": "ADHERE",
            "answer": "adhere"
          },
          {
            "word": "DILIGENT",
            "answer": "diligent"
          },
          {
            "word": "INTIMATE",
            "answer": "intimate"
          },
          {
            "word": "PROFICIENT",
            "answer": "proficient"
          },
          {
            "word": "SLIPSHOD",
            "answer": "slipshod"
          },
          {
            "word": "CASCADE",
            "answer": "cascade"
          },
          {
            "word": "EMBRYONIC",
            "answer": "embryonic"
          },
          {
            "word": "JEST",
            "answer": "jests"
          },
          {
            "word": "PUNY",
            "answer": "puny"
          },
          {
            "word": "SUFFICE",
            "answer": "suffice"
          },
          {
            "word": "CONCUR",
            "answer": "concur"
          },
          {
            "word": "ENCOMPASS",
            "answer": "encompassed"
          },
          {
            "word": "ADVERSARY",
            "answer": "adversary"
          },
          {
            "word": "CLICHE",
            "answer": "cliche"
          },
          {
            "word": "EXULT",
            "answer": "exulted"
          },
          {
            "word": "PRECINCT",
            "answer": "precinct"
          },
          {
            "word": "SUMMIT",
            "answer": "summit"
          },
          {
            "word": "AFFILIATE",
            "answer": "affiliated"
          },
          {
            "word": "CORDIAL",
            "answer": "cordial"
          },
          {
            "word": "INDUCE",
            "answer": "induced"
          },
          {
            "word": "PROLOGUE",
            "answer": "prologue"
          },
          {
            "word": "SURPLUS",
            "answer": "surplus"
          },
          {
            "word": "ARID",
            "answer": "arid"
          },
          {
            "word": "CONTEMPLATIVE",
            "answer": "contemplative"
          },
          {
            "word": "INITIAL",
            "answer": "initial"
          },
          {
            "word": "RENOWN",
            "answer": "renown"
          },
          {
            "word": "UNITY",
            "answer": "unity"
          },
          {
            "word": "BISECT",
            "answer": "bisected"
          },
          {
            "word": "DISGRUNTLE",
            "answer": "disgruntled"
          },
          {
            "word": "MAUL",
            "answer": "mauled"
          },
          {
            "word": "SULLEN",
            "answer": "sullen"
          },
          {
            "word": "WRETCHED",
            "answer": "wretched"
          },
          {
            "word": "CHRONIC",
            "answer": "chronic"
          },
          {
            "word": "DISINTEGRATE",
            "answer": "disintegrated"
          },
          {
            "word": "MEANDER",
            "answer": "meandered"
          }
        ],
        "questions": [
          {
            "part1": "I have to",
            "part2": "with you. You're right, Jim is not a very good baseball player.",
            "correct": "concur",
            "word": "CONCUR"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He was so",
            "part2": "about getting his work done on time that they gave him a raise.",
            "correct": "diligent",
            "word": "DILIGENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Algebra and geometry are",
            "part2": "in the overall field of mathematics.",
            "correct": "encompassed",
            "word": "ENCOMPASS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He was",
            "part2": "by the need to prove he wasn't a coward.",
            "correct": "obsessed",
            "word": "OBSESS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Although he doesn't enjoy driving he is quite",
            "part2": "at it, and he has never had an accident.",
            "correct": "proficient",
            "word": "PROFICIENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Bill used to be rather",
            "part2": ", but lately he has gained a lot of weight and become much stronger.",
            "correct": "puny",
            "word": "PUNY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "She",
            "part2": "a humorous story about traveling in Europe.",
            "correct": "related",
            "word": "RELATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He used a special glue to make the shelf",
            "part2": "to the refrigerator.",
            "correct": "adhere",
            "word": "ADHERE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Their prices are so",
            "part2": "that I'm surprised they ever sell anything.",
            "correct": "exorbitant",
            "word": "EXORBITANT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The speaker made a few",
            "part2": "about how fat he was, and then became serious.",
            "correct": "jests",
            "word": "JEST"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He said that fifty people would not",
            "part2": "for the job. He needed at least a hundred.",
            "correct": "suffice",
            "word": "SUFFICE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The two poets were",
            "part2": "with each other; they were both born in the same year, and died in the same year.",
            "correct": "contemporary",
            "word": "CONTEMPLATIVE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "A group of daring criminals",
            "part2": "the mayor and demanded a million dollars for his safe return.",
            "correct": "abducted",
            "word": "ABDUCT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The fencer cut his opponent on the arm with his",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "saber",
            "word": "SABER"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The newspaper reporter somehow learned the",
            "part2": "secrets of his personal life.",
            "correct": "intimate",
            "word": "INTIMATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Bill was",
            "part2": "of the other students because he was so much smarter than they were.",
            "correct": "contemptuous",
            "word": "CONTEMPLATIVE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He kept a(n)",
            "part2": "of old coins in a strongbox that no one knew about.",
            "correct": "hoard",
            "word": "HOARD"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "of water pouring down the side of the mountain was a beautiful sight.",
            "correct": "cascade",
            "word": "CASCADE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "When they arrested him, he denied the",
            "part2": "that he had robbed the bank.",
            "correct": "accusation",
            "word": "ACCUSATION"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Even the most",
            "part2": "workers occasionally do something carefully and correctly.",
            "correct": "slipshod",
            "word": "SLIPSHOD"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The plan is still rather",
            "part2": "; when it is more developed you will understand it better.",
            "correct": "embryonic",
            "word": "EMBRYONIC"
          },
          {
            "part1": "She",
            "part2": "a great deal about whether or not to go to college.",
            "correct": "meditated",
            "word": "MEDITATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The policeman talked to the man for a long time and finally",
            "part2": "him to come in from the window ledge.",
            "correct": "induced",
            "word": "INDUCE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Their marriage was a happy one, and they lived together in",
            "part2": "and harmony for many, many years.",
            "correct": "unity",
            "word": "UNITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "All of us are",
            "part2": "at the low pay we are receiving.",
            "correct": "disgruntled",
            "word": "DISGRUNTLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "boy refused to speak to anyone when he didn't get his way.",
            "correct": "sullen",
            "word": "SULLEN"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He came in all bruised and bleeding. He said he had been",
            "part2": "by some vicious teenagers.",
            "correct": "mauled",
            "word": "MAUL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The land in that region is so",
            "part2": "that only a very few plants can survive.",
            "correct": "arid",
            "word": "ARID"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "results showed him ahead, but in the final results his opponent had won.",
            "correct": "initial",
            "word": "INITIAL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We tried to help some of the",
            "part2": "people who were left homeless by the flood.",
            "correct": "wretched",
            "word": "WRETCHED"
          },
          {
            "part1": "This charity used to be",
            "part2": "with the United Way, but it no longer has anything to do with that organization.",
            "correct": "affiliated",
            "word": "AFFILIATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "There was a(n)",
            "part2": "at the start of the play, during which an actor explained that it was a true story.",
            "correct": "prologue",
            "word": "PROLOGUE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His",
            "part2": "was so powerful that Brett had little chance of defeating him.",
            "correct": "adversary",
            "word": "ADVERSARY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "It is better to gain honor and",
            "part2": "for your achievements while still alive than to become famous after you're dead.",
            "correct": "renown",
            "word": "RENOWN"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Jane",
            "part2": "slowly through the store, not looking for anything in particular.",
            "correct": "meandered",
            "word": "MEANDER"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We can't fit all our stuff into our new small apartment, so we're going to sell our",
            "part2": "furniture before we move.",
            "correct": "surplus",
            "word": "SURPLUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He was at the",
            "part2": "of his career during his forties.",
            "correct": "summit",
            "word": "SUMMIT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The railroad tracks passed through the middle of town and",
            "part2": "it exactly.",
            "correct": "bisected",
            "word": "BISECT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "They",
            "part2": "over their good luck in finding the buried treasure.",
            "correct": "exulted",
            "word": "EXULT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Her feet are always sore. It's been a(n)",
            "part2": "problem for her for some time now.",
            "correct": "chronic",
            "word": "CHRONIC"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Ray is a(n)",
            "part2": "sort of person. He will spend a whole afternoon just thinking about the nature of life.",
            "correct": "contemplative",
            "word": "CONTEMPLATIVE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The police said there is a high burglary rate in this particular",
            "part2": "; in other areas of the city the problem isn't so bad.",
            "correct": "precinct",
            "word": "PRECINCT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "She thought it was quite an original expression, but to me it was just another",
            "part2": "",
            "correct": "cliche",
            "word": "CLICHE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The force of the explosion completely",
            "part2": "the building.",
            "correct": "disintegrated",
            "word": "DISINTEGRATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Our old friend greeted us with a(n)",
            "part2": "smile and handshake.",
            "correct": "cordial",
            "word": "CORDIAL"
          }
        ],
        "type": "fitb"
      }
    },
    {
      "wordsets": [
        {
          "title": "5.4",
          "definitions": {
            "INSTIGATE": {
              "word": "INSTIGATE",
              "phonetic": "(in'-st:;,-gAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to urge on, stir up, goad, incite </p><p>To INSTIGATE is to urge on, usually for some evil purpose. You can INSTIGATE a person. </p><p>“They INSTIGATED the people to riot in the streets.” </p><p>Or you can INSTIGATE an action. </p><p>“They INSTIGATED the war by spreading lies about both countries.” </p><p>“We must discover who INSTIGATED the plot to murder the king.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: INSTIGATION, n. INSTIGATOR, n.</p>"
            },
            "HAMPER": {
              "word": "HAMPER",
              "phonetic": "(ham'-pJr)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to obstruct, block, impede, interfere with, hinder </p><p>To HAMPER something is to hold it back, to make diffi- culties for it in some way. To HAMPER is not to stop something completely, but simply to make it harder to do or finish. </p><p>“Their opposition HAMPERED our work but couldn’t prevent it.” </p><p>“The team was HAMPERED by a lack of time to prac- tice.” </p><p>“His quick temper doesn’t help him on the job; in fact, I think it HAMPERS his effectiveness.”</p>"
            },
            "ALLIANCE": {
              "word": "ALLIANCE",
              "phonetic": "(:;,-I1'-;;,ns)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a union, association, connection </p><p>An ALLIANCE is a union of two or more people or countries who agree to act together for their mutual benefit. </p><p>“The North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) is a military ALLIANCE of Western nations.” </p><p>“We couldn’t understand the sudden ALLIANCE be- tween David and Bob, because they had been un- friendly for years.” </p><p>An ALLY is someone who is in a union or association with another. </p><p>“We became ALLIES when we decided that neither of us could win without the other.” </p><p>“During World War II, the United States and Great Britain were ALLIES.” Other forms of the word: ALLY, n., v.</p>"
            },
            "BOMBARD": {
              "word": "BOMBARD",
              "phonetic": "(born-bahrd')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to shell </p><p>BOMBARD comes from the word BOMB and means “to attack with explosive weapons,” to <i class=“def-ital\">shell.</i> </p><p>“The enemy troops BOMBARDED the building with hand grenades.” </p><p>“The battleships BOMBARDED several towns along the coast.” </p><p>BOMBARD can also be used in a more general sense to mean “to attack vigorously.” </p><p>“The teacher was BOMBARDED with questions about the final exam.” </p><p>“The sanitation department was BOMBARDED with complaints when its workers went on strike.” </p><p>BOMBARDMENT is the act of BOMBARDING. </p><p>“The entire city was a mass of crumbling ruins as a result of the BOMBARDMENT by enemy aircraft.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: BOMBARDMENT, n.</p>"
            },
            "LAPSE": {
              "word": "LAPSE",
              "phonetic": "(laps)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a slight error, slip; a fall, decline; a passing of time </p><p>LAPSE comes from a Latin word meaning to <i class=“def-ital\">fall,</i> also the source of the words <i class=“def-ital\">collapse, relapse,</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">elapse.</i> LAPSE is used in several different senses. A LAPSE is a slight mistake or slip. </p><p>“There were a few LAPSES in his performance, but overall it was quite good.” </p><p>“He had a sudden memory LAPSE and could not re- call his friend’s name.” </p><p>A LAPSE is also a falling or decline to a lower degree or standard. </p><p>“After they behaved well all day there was a brief LAPSE into their former rudeness.” </p><p>It is also a period of time that has passed, an interval. </p><p>“There was a LAPSE of ten minutes before they started the show again.”</p>"
            },
            "IMPOVERISH": {
              "word": "IMPOVERISH",
              "phonetic": "(im-pov'-rish)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to make poor, reduce to poverty </p><p>IMPOVERISH comes from the Latin word for poor, also the source of the English word <i class=“def-ital\">poverty.</i> To IMPOVERISH someone is to make him very poor. </p><p>“The Depression IMPOVERISHED many families.” </p><p>You can IMPOVERISH something by removing its strength, richness, or other good qualities. </p><p>“This town will be IMPOVERISHED by the loss of these two fine men.” </p><p>“The soil was IMPOVERISHED by planting the same crops year after year.” </p><p>IMPOVERISH is often used in the form of an adjective, IMPOVERISHED. </p><p>“The IMPOVERISHED farmers asked for loans so that they could keep their land.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: IMPOVERISHED, adj.</p>"
            },
            "EXCAVATE": {
              "word": "EXCAVATE",
              "phonetic": "(eks'-kÔøΩvAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to dig out, hollow out, unearth </p><p>See <i class=“def-ital\">ex-</i> under Prefixes and <i class=“def-ital\">-ate1</i> under Suffixes. To EXCAVATE something is to make a <i class=“def-ital\">cave</i> out of it, to hollow it out, to remove the earth from it. </p><p>“They EXCAVATED a large area for the foundation of the building.” </p><p>“WE EXCAVATED a long tunnel through the moun- tain.” </p><p>EXCAVATE is also used in a slightly different sense, to mean “to uncover by digging.” </p><p>“The archaeologists EXCAVATED the ancient city, which had been buried for thousands of years.” </p><p>An EXCAVATION is the act of EXCAVATING, or the hole made by EXCAVATING. </p><p>“They examined the entire EXCAVATION before al- lowing the engineers to complete the tunnel.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: EXCAVATION, n.</p>"
            },
            "DEEM": {
              "word": "DEEM",
              "phonetic": "(dEm)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to consider, believe, think </p><p>DEEM means “to have as an opinion,” to <i class=“def-ital\">consider</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">believe.</i> </p><p>“They DEEM him the best person for the job.” </p><p>“I DEEM it best that I continue in school rather than go to work right away.” </p><p>“She DEEMS it her duty to help.” </p><p>Usage: DEEM is a rather formal word, and would not be used often in ordinary conversation.</p>"
            },
            "UNRULY": {
              "word": "UNRULY",
              "phonetic": "(uhn-rU'-IE)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">wild, disorderly, uncontrollable </p><p>The basic meaning of UNRULY is “not obeying the rules.” See <i class=“def-ital\">un-</i> under Prefixes. Usually the word is ap- plied to people who are wild or difficult to control. </p><p>“After two hours of sitting quietly and listening to the speech, the children started to become UNRULY.” </p><p>“The UNRULY mob shouted and jeered at the police- men who were trying to keep order.” </p><p>“These children are not evil, just excited and UNRULY.” </p><p>Many people think UNRULY means <i class=“def-ital\">angry.</i> The two words are close in meaning, but someone could be disor- derly without being <i class=“def-ital\">angry.</i></p>"
            },
            "INFILTRATE": {
              "word": "INFILTRATE",
              "phonetic": "(in'-fil-trAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to pass into or through by filtering </p><p>A <i class=“def-ital\">filter</i> is an article or substance which allows certain things to pass through it and keeps out others. A cigarette filter, for example, lets smoke through but keeps out some impurities from the tobacco. </p><p>To INFILTRATE is to pass into something through a filter, or as if through a filter. See <i class=“def-ital\">in-1</i> under Prefixes and <i class=“def-ital\">-ate1</i> under Suffixes. The word is often used about soldiers entering enemy territory in small groups through weak points in the enemy defenses. </p><p>“The general decided to INFILTRATE enemy territory rather than to launch a full-scale attack.” </p><p>INFILTRATE is used generally about people entering someplace or something secretly. </p><p>“The FBI agent INFILTRATED the terrorist group.” </p><p>“He believed the organization had been INFILTRATED by Communist spies.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: INFILTRATION, n.</p>"
            },
            "HUMILITY": {
              "word": "HUMILITY",
              "phonetic": "(hyU-mil'-ÔøΩ-tE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">modesty, lack of pride </p><p>HUMILITY comes from the adjective HUMBLE. A HUMBLE person has a low or modest opinion of himself, is not proud or self-important. HUMILITY is the quality of being HUMBLE. See <i class=“def-ital\">-ity</i> under Suffixes. </p><p>“Her HUMILITY was genuine. She really didn’t think she was very important.” </p><p>“We all felt greater HUMILITY after meeting this brilliant and saintly man.” </p><p>“With deep HUMILITY he said that other people deserved the award more than he.”</p>"
            },
            "ESPIONAGE": {
              "word": "ESPIONAGE",
              "phonetic": "(es'-pE-ÔøΩ-nahzh)",
              "pos": "n.,",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">adj.: spying, the use of spies </p><p>ESPIONAGE is from a French word meaning to <i class=“def-ital\">spy.</i> ESPIONAGE is <i class=“def-ital\">spying,</i> the secret observation of people, governments, and the like. </p><p>“The Russians accused him of ESPIONAGE.” </p><p>“They set up a large network of ESPIONAGE agents.” </p><p>ESPIONAGE can be used about the actual spying itself, or the general system of using spies to collect information. </p><p>“Their ESPIONAGE system was good at uncovering information but bad at understanding it.”</p>"
            },
            "DISPATCH": {
              "word": "DISPATCH",
              "phonetic": "(dis-pach')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to send, send away; to get through or done; to kill </p><p>To DISPATCH something is to send it away, usually quickly or for a special purpose. See <i class=“def-ital\">dis-</i> under Prefixes. </p><p>“He DISPATCHED a telegram reporting the king’s death.” </p><p>“The police DISPATCHED a patrol car to the scene of the robbery.” </p><p>The word can also mean “to get through quickly” and is used about things like work or food. </p><p>“He DISPATCHED the first job in under an hour and started immediately on the second.” </p><p>In a special sense, DISPATCH can also mean to <i class=“def-ital\">kill,</i> especially rapidly and efficiently. “The executioner DISPATCHED him with one blow of the ax.” </p><p>Usage: DISPATCH is sometimes spelled DESPATCH.</p>"
            },
            "CIVILITY": {
              "word": "CIVILITY",
              "phonetic": "(sÔøΩ-vil'-ÔøΩ-tE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">politeness, courtesy </p><p>To be CIVIL is to be polite. The word often suggests merely adequate politeness rather than great courtesy. </p><p>“It was all he could do to be CIVIL with the rude cus- tomers.” </p><p>CIVILITY is the state of being CIVIL, <i class=“def-ital\">politeness.</i> See <i class=“def-ital\">-ity</i> under Suffixes. </p><p>“She greeted the stranger with CIVILITY but without enthusiasm.” </p><p>“We admired his CIVILITY toward people he hated.” </p><p>CIVILITIES, the plural form, are polite acts or expres- sions. </p><p>“The two men exchanged CIVILITIES and then got quickly down to work.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Patience</i> is the most commonly chosen incorrect answer. CIVILITY might include <i class=“def-ital\">patience,</i> but the two words aren’t synonyms. Other forms of the word: CIVIL, adj.</p>"
            },
            "RAUCOUS": {
              "word": "RAUCOUS",
              "phonetic": "(ro'-kÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">harsh, hoarse, grating RAUCOUS is used mainly about sounds. The word means “disagreeably loud and harsh.” It often suggests that this loud noise is the result of disorderly behavior. </p><p>“We listened to the RAUCOUS noise of the crows outside our window.” </p><p>“The neighbors complained about the RAUCOUS party across the hall.” </p><p>“The RAUCOUS laughter stopped suddenly when the teacher entered the room.” </p><p>The most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest is deep. <i class=“def-ital\">Deep</i> can also be used about sounds and voices, but deep sounds are not always loud and grating.</p>"
            }
          },
          "id": "4",
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "INSTIGATE the violence.",
                  "answers": [
                    "end",
                    "increase",
                    "look into",
                    "stir up",
                    "join in"
                  ],
                  "word": "INSTIGATE",
                  "correct": "stir up"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To HAMPER it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "forbid",
                    "block",
                    "help",
                    "inspect",
                    "compliment"
                  ],
                  "word": "HAMPER",
                  "correct": "block"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Unusual ALLIANCE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "delay",
                    "part",
                    "meeting",
                    "breakup",
                    "union"
                  ],
                  "word": "ALLIANCE",
                  "correct": "union"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BOMBARD the city.",
                  "answers": [
                    "shell",
                    "flood",
                    "enter",
                    "build",
                    "guard"
                  ],
                  "word": "BOMBARD",
                  "correct": "shell"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "An occasional LAPSE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "remark",
                    "victory",
                    "error",
                    "crime",
                    "criticism"
                  ],
                  "word": "LAPSE",
                  "correct": "error"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPOVERISHED areas.",
                  "answers": [
                    "wasteful",
                    "ugly",
                    "poor",
                    "rich",
                    "empty"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPOVERISH",
                  "correct": "poor"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXCAVATE the tomb.",
                  "answers": [
                    "cover",
                    "build",
                    "discover",
                    "dig out",
                    "restore"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXCAVATE",
                  "correct": "dig out"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We DEEM it to be unnecessary.",
                  "answers": [
                    "consider",
                    "wish",
                    "expect",
                    "like",
                    "remember"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEEM",
                  "correct": "consider"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "UNRULY spectators.",
                  "answers": [
                    "unexcited",
                    "angry",
                    "wild",
                    "late",
                    "unfriendly"
                  ],
                  "word": "UNRULY",
                  "correct": "wild"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INFILTRATED enemy territory.",
                  "answers": [
                    "sealed off",
                    "attacked",
                    "passed into",
                    "sailed around",
                    "blew up"
                  ],
                  "word": "INFILTRATE",
                  "correct": "passed into"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Admired his HUMILITY.",
                  "answers": [
                    "quietness",
                    "usefulness",
                    "confidence",
                    "calmness",
                    "modesty"
                  ],
                  "word": "HUMILITY",
                  "correct": "modesty"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "A case of ESPIONAGE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "spying",
                    "lying",
                    "stealing",
                    "destruction",
                    "murder"
                  ],
                  "word": "ESPIONAGE",
                  "correct": "spying"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DISPATCH them.",
                  "answers": [
                    "ruin",
                    "sell",
                    "call for",
                    "send",
                    "lead"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISPATCH",
                  "correct": "send"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Treated with CIVILITY.",
                  "answers": [
                    "amusement",
                    "love",
                    "patience",
                    "politeness",
                    "rudeness"
                  ],
                  "word": "CIVILITY",
                  "correct": "politeness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RAUCOUS voices.",
                  "answers": [
                    "deep",
                    "funny",
                    "harsh",
                    "soft",
                    "far-off"
                  ],
                  "word": "RAUCOUS",
                  "correct": "harsh"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Do the police usually INSTIGATE crimes?",
                  "word": "INSTIGATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would wearing mittens HAMPER a person who is trying to play the guitar?",
                  "word": "HAMPER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do ALLIES fight against each other?",
                  "word": "ALLIANCE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can someone be BOMBARDED with requests?",
                  "word": "BOMBARD",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a \"slip of the tongue\" be a LAPSE?",
                  "word": "LAPSE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an IMPOVERISHED area be quite wealthy?",
                  "word": "IMPOVERISH",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a shovel be used in making an EXCAVATION?",
                  "word": "EXCAVATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "If someone DEEMS a book to be terrible, does he dislike it?",
                  "word": "DEEM",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are UNRULY children quiet and well-behaved?",
                  "word": "UNRULY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would it be easy to INFILTRATE a place that was well-guarded?",
                  "word": "INFILTRATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do most people admire HUMILITY?",
                  "word": "HUMILITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do countries practice ESPIONAGE during wartime?",
                  "word": "ESPIONAGE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you DISPATCH a letter?",
                  "word": "DISPATCH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most salesmen try to be CIVIL with their customers?",
                  "word": "CIVILITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can laughter be RAUCOUS?",
                  "word": "RAUCOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "The protest group INSTIGATED the demonstration against the new tax.",
                  "word": "INSTIGATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He was HAMPERED by his inability to read.",
                  "word": "HAMPER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It was only a temporary ALLIANCE; when the battle was over they went back to being enemies.",
                  "word": "ALLIANCE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The company BOMBARDED him with letters demanding that he pay his bills.",
                  "word": "BOMBARD",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "After a LAPSE of three years he started to skate again.",
                  "word": "LAPSE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We IMPOVERISHED them not to come with us.",
                  "word": "IMPOVERISH",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They EXCAVATED a tomb that was thousands of years old.",
                  "word": "EXCAVATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The teacher DEEMED him the best student in the school.",
                  "word": "DEEM",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The UNRULY crowd refused to obey the police officers.",
                  "word": "UNRULY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He INFILTRATED his father's wallet looking for money.",
                  "word": "INFILTRATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He had a great sense of HUMILITY; he could make us laugh any time he wanted.",
                  "word": "HUMILITY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The enemy bribed him to become an ESPIONAGE agent.",
                  "word": "ESPIONAGE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The newspaper DISPATCHED a photographer to take pictures of the event.",
                  "word": "DISPATCH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The soldiers ordered all the CIVILITY to leave the area at once.",
                  "word": "CIVILITY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He ran his hands over the cold, RAUCOUS sides ofthe cave.",
                  "word": "RAUCOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "INSTIGATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "start",
                    "urge",
                    "expect"
                  ],
                  "word": "INSTIGATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HAMPER",
                  "answers": [
                    "bother",
                    "hurt",
                    "discover"
                  ],
                  "word": "HAMPER",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ALLIANCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "friendship",
                    "hope",
                    "assistance"
                  ],
                  "word": "ALLIANCE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BOMBARD",
                  "answers": [
                    "attack",
                    "shell",
                    "defend"
                  ],
                  "word": "BOMBARD",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LAPSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "fall",
                    "slip",
                    "shake"
                  ],
                  "word": "LAPSE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPOVERISH",
                  "answers": [
                    "terrify",
                    "beggar",
                    "weaken"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPOVERISH",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXCAVATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "bury",
                    "dig",
                    "uncover"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXCAVATE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DEEM",
                  "answers": [
                    "wonder",
                    "believe",
                    "decide"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEEM",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "UNRULY",
                  "answers": [
                    "quiet",
                    "disorderly",
                    "disobedient"
                  ],
                  "word": "UNRULY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INFILTRATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "enter",
                    "penetrate",
                    "connect"
                  ],
                  "word": "INFILTRATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HUMILITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "meekness",
                    "happiness",
                    "modesty"
                  ],
                  "word": "HUMILITY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ESPIONAGE",
                  "answers": [
                    "combat",
                    "secrecy",
                    "information"
                  ],
                  "word": "ESPIONAGE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DISPATCH",
                  "answers": [
                    "kill",
                    "transmit",
                    "find"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISPATCH",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CIVILITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "permission",
                    "friendliness",
                    "graciousness"
                  ],
                  "word": "CIVILITY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RAUCOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "rough",
                    "loud",
                    "weird"
                  ],
                  "word": "RAUCOUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "5.5",
          "definitions": {
            "RENDEZVOUS": {
              "word": "RENDEZVOUS",
              "phonetic": "(ron'-dA-vU)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a meeting, meeting-place </p><p>Note the pronunciation. RENDEZVOUS comes from a French phrase which means “Present yourselves.” A RENDEZVOUS is a place where people arrange to meet. The word is often used as a military term for the place where ships or troops are to assemble. </p><p>“I’ll meet you at four o’clock at the RENDEZVOUS.” </p><p>A RENDEZVOUS can also be the meeting itself. </p><p>“We arranged a RENDEZVOUS for four o’clock.” </p><p>“I had a RENDEZVOUS with them at the restaurant.” </p><p>RENDEZVOUS is also a verb. </p><p>“We will RENDEZVOUS at the usual place.” </p><p>On the Pretest, many people select <i class=“def-ital\">journey</i> as the synonym for RENDEZVOUS, perhaps because you have to travel to reach a RENDEZVOUS.</p>"
            },
            "RESOLUTE": {
              "word": "RESOLUTE",
              "phonetic": "(rez'-:;,-IUt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">determined, firm, resolved </p><p>One meaning of the word RESOLVE is to <i class=“def-ital\">decide</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">determine.</i> </p><p>“He RESOLVED that he would be famous by age thirty.” </p><p>RESOLUTE is the adjective from RESOLVE, and is used about people. Someone who is RESOLUTE is firm and determined in a course of action or belief. </p><p>“The senators were RESOLUTE in their opposition to the bill.” </p><p>“The RESOLUTE men said that if it was necessary they would wait all day to see him.” </p><p>“He stood RESOLUTE against all the enemies of the nation.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: RESOLUTION,n. RESOLVE,v.</p>"
            },
            "RESTRICT": {
              "word": "RESTRICT",
              "phonetic": "(ri-strikt')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to limit, restrain </p><p>To RESTRICT means “to put limits on, to keep within bounds.” The word is used about both people and things. </p><p>“Their parents RESTRICT them to one cookie for dessert.” </p><p>“Bicycles are RESTRICTED to certain paths in the park.” </p><p>“His speech was largely RESTRICTED to the topic of international trade.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Stop</i> is often chosen as the meaning of RESTRICT,but you can RESTRICT something without entirely <i class=“def-ital\">stopping</i> it. </p><p>“The sale of alcohol is RESTRICTED to persons over eighteen years of age.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: RESTRICTION,n.</p>"
            },
            "ILLICIT": {
              "word": "ILLICIT",
              "phonetic": "(i-lis'-it)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">unlawful, not allowed, not permitted </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Licit</i> is a rather rare word which means <i class=“def-ital\">legal, lawful.</i> It comes from a Latin word meaning “It is allowed.” ILLICIT is the opposite of <i class=“def-ital\">licit.</i> It means “not allowed,” <i class=“def-ital\">unlawful, illegal.</i> See <i class=“def-ital\">in-2</i> under Prefixes. </p><p>“The ILLICIT sale of drugs is a major problem.” </p><p>“The company was accused of ILLICIT business practices.”</p>"
            },
            "SARCASTIC": {
              "word": "SARCASTIC",
              "phonetic": "(sahr-kas'-tik)",
              "pos": "adj",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">biting, caustic, ironical </p><p>SARCASTIC and its noun SARCASM come from a Greek word meaning “to tear flesh,to bite one’s lips in rage, thus to sneer.” SARCASM is biting language, remarks that hurt by making fun of someone or something. </p><p>“No one liked him because he always treated everyone with SARCASM.” </p><p>SARCASTIC means “full of SARCASM,” and is used about people and the things they say or do. </p><p>“He was a SARCASTIC fellow, always ready to insult people. ” </p><p>“The teacher’s SARCASTIC remarks made the little girl cry.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: SARCASM,n.</p>"
            },
            "MINUSCULE": {
              "word": "MINUSCULE",
              "phonetic": "(min'-:;,s-kyUI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">tiny, very small, insignificant </p><p>Note the spelling. Many people think the word begins with <i class=“def-ital\">mini-.</i> MINUSCULE comes from the word <i class=“def-ital\">minus,</i> and means <i class=“def-ital\">very small, tiny.</i> </p><p>“The painting is MINUSCULE. You need a magnifying glass just to see it.” </p><p>“He made up for his MINUSCULE size by being extremely quick and clever.” </p><p>MINUSCULE as a noun has a specific meaning, referring to small letters in printing as opposed to capital letters.</p>"
            },
            "STUPEFY": {
              "word": "STUPEFY",
              "phonetic": "{stU'-pg-fl)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to stun, astonish </p><p>When something STUPEFIES you, it is so amazing or frightening or powerful that it takes away your senses and leaves you confused and dazed. </p><p>“We were all STUPEFIED by the news that all along our friend had actually been an enemy spy.” </p><p>“Her announcement STUPEFIED me. I didn’t know what to do or say next.” </p><p>“The movie was STUPEFYINGLY dull\"-that is, it was so dull that it would almost put you to sleep.</p>"
            },
            "INVIGORATE": {
              "word": "INVIGORATE",
              "phonetic": "(in-vig'-g-rAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to strengthen, refresh, enliven </p><p>See <i class=“def-ital\">in-1</i> under Prefixes and <i class=“def-ital\">-ate1</i> under Suffixes. <i class=“def-ital\">Vigor</i> is strength, energy, active good health. </p><p>“After a good night’s sleep she awoke refreshed and full of vigor.” </p><p>To INVIGORATE is to fill with <i class=“def-ital\">vigor.</i> </p><p>“Just breathing that nice fresh air is enough to INVIG- ORATE me.” </p><p>“The new members tried to INVIGORATE the club by organizing all sorts of activities.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: INVIGORATING, adj.</p>"
            },
            "PERSEVERE": {
              "word": "PERSEVERE",
              "phonetic": "(per-sg-vEr')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to persist, keep on, continue </p><p>To PERSEVERE in something is to keep at it, especially in the face of difficulty or opposition. The word usually suggests that this is a good quality, that the person who PERSEVERES should be praised for not giving up. </p><p>“I know things are hard for us now, but I’m sure if we PERSEVERE they will improve in the end.” </p><p>“The course was difficult, but he PERSEVERED in his studies, and finally he passed.” </p><p>“Despite her parents’ opposition, she PERSEVERED in trying to become a doctor.” </p><p>PERSEVERANCE is steady persistence. </p><p>“You must have PERSEVERANCE if you want to be- come a top athlete, because it takes years of training and practice.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: PERSEVERANCE, n.</p>"
            },
            "WAFT": {
              "word": "WAFT",
              "phonetic": "(wahft)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to move lightly and smoothly, float </p><p>To WAFT is to move or carry lightly and smoothly, usually through the air or on water. WAFT can be used about smells and sounds as well as physical objects. </p><p>“The breeze WAFTED the smell of roses into the room.” </p><p>“A leaf WAFTED gently to the ground.” </p><p>“The gentle waves WAFTED her ball slowly out to sea.” </p><p>“The distant shouts of children playing WAFTED in through the open window.”</p>"
            },
            "HAGGARD": {
              "word": "HAGGARD",
              "phonetic": "(hag'-grd)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">having a worn, tired appearance; gaunt </p><p>Someone who is HAGGARD looks tired and worn out from worry, lack of sleep, lack of food, or the like. His eyes might be bloodshot, his face might be thin and lined, his clothing might be rumpled. </p><p>“After losing his job, he came home looking HAG- GARD and discouraged.” </p><p>“She felt sorry for the beggar when she saw his dirty clothes and HAGGARD face.” </p><p>“He looked HAGGARD after waiting at the hospital all night.”</p>"
            },
            "PLIANT": {
              "word": "PLIANT",
              "phonetic": "(pll-gnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">easily bent, flexible, yielding, adaptable </p><p>PLIANT comes from a Latin word meaning to bend. Something that is PLIANT can be bent easily without breaking. </p><p>“The wax was very PLIANT and could be easily molded or shaped.” </p><p>When used about people, PLIANT means “easily influenced, open to suggestions.” </p><p>“Our boss proved to be quite PLIANT and agreed to all our requests.” </p><p>“The PLIANT students did whatever the teacher told them to do.” </p><p>“Our father isn’t PLIANT at all. We can never make him change his mind.” </p><p>PLIANT is close in meaning to a very similar word, <i class=“def-ital\">pliable,</i> which also means “easily bent or influenced.”</p>"
            },
            "VAGABOND": {
              "word": "VAGABOND",
              "phonetic": "(vag'-ÔøΩ-bond)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a wanderer, tramp, hobo </p><p>A VAGABOND is a person with no home, a carefree wanderer who never settles down. The word usually suggests the pleasures of this kind of life rather than the problems. </p><p>“He was a happy VAGABOND, traveling here and there, wherever he pleased.” </p><p>“The life of a VAGABOND seems very appealing to one who is stuck in a dull job.” </p><p>VAGABOND is also used as an adjective, meaning <i class=“def-ital\">wandering.</i> </p><p>“We went on a VAGABOND tour of Europe.”</p>"
            },
            "INGRAINED": {
              "word": "INGRAINED",
              "phonetic": "(in-grAnd')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">deep-rooted, deeply fixed </p><p>See <i class=“def-ital\">in-1</i> under Prefixes. One meaning of <i class=“def-ital\">grain</i> is “the natural appearance and texture of wood.” Something which is INGRAINED is not just on the surface but worked into the <i class=“def-ital\">grain.</i> The word is particularly used about beliefs or characteristics that are deeply rooted in a person or group. </p><p>“Almost always, habits and prejudices are deeply INGRAINED.” </p><p>“His INGRAINED honesty kept him from even con- sidering taking a bribe.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: INGRAIN, v.</p>"
            },
            "RELENT": {
              "word": "RELENT",
              "phonetic": "(ri-lent')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to give in, yield </p><p>To RELENT is to become less harsh, to let up or give in. The word is usually used about people. </p><p>“The teacher finally RELENTED and told Bill he didn’t have to stay after school.” </p><p>“She begged her mother to let her go to the dance, but her mother wouldn’t RELENT.” </p><p>“When he saw her crying, he RELENTED and let her keep the toy.” </p><p>Someone who is RELENTLESS does not or cannot RE- LENT, is harsh and persistent. </p><p>“They begged him to stop teasing the child, but he was RELENTLESS.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: RELENTLESS, adj.</p>"
            }
          },
          "id": "5",
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Arranged the RENDEZVOUS.",
                  "answers": [
                    "divorce",
                    "party",
                    "discussion",
                    "meeting",
                    "journey"
                  ],
                  "word": "RENDEZVOUS",
                  "correct": "meeting"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RESOLUTE men.",
                  "answers": [
                    "uncertain",
                    "dangerous",
                    "hopeful",
                    "determined",
                    "military"
                  ],
                  "word": "RESOLUTE",
                  "correct": "determined"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To RESTRICT it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "oppose",
                    "stop",
                    "limit",
                    "review",
                    "support"
                  ],
                  "word": "RESTRICT",
                  "correct": "limit"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ILLICIT practices.",
                  "answers": [
                    "poor",
                    "risky",
                    "unlawful",
                    "unnecessary",
                    "proper"
                  ],
                  "word": "ILLICIT",
                  "correct": "unlawful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SARCASTIC remarks.",
                  "answers": [
                    "unbelievable",
                    "silly",
                    "biting",
                    "dangerous",
                    "brilliant"
                  ],
                  "word": "SARCASTIC",
                  "correct": "biting"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MINUSCULE majority.",
                  "answers": [
                    "temporary",
                    "sufficient",
                    "usual",
                    "great",
                    "tiny"
                  ],
                  "word": "MINUSCULE",
                  "correct": "tiny"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Their actions STUPEFY me.",
                  "answers": [
                    "please",
                    "stun",
                    "concern",
                    "thrill",
                    "frighten"
                  ],
                  "word": "STUPEFY",
                  "correct": "stun"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It INVIGORATED him.",
                  "answers": [
                    "cured",
                    "pleased",
                    "weakened",
                    "changed",
                    "strengthened"
                  ],
                  "word": "INVIGORATE",
                  "correct": "strengthened"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We must PERSEVERE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "persist",
                    "improve",
                    "get angry",
                    "argue",
                    "give up"
                  ],
                  "word": "PERSEVERE",
                  "correct": "persist"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It WAFTED in.",
                  "answers": [
                    "sneaked",
                    "floated",
                    "hurried",
                    "danced",
                    "dropped"
                  ],
                  "word": "WAFT",
                  "correct": "floated"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His HAGGARD appearance.",
                  "answers": [
                    "neat",
                    "silly",
                    "ugly",
                    "strange",
                    "worn"
                  ],
                  "word": "HAGGARD",
                  "correct": "worn"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They were PLIANT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "useful",
                    "very soft",
                    "stiff",
                    "layered",
                    "easily bent"
                  ],
                  "word": "PLIANT",
                  "correct": "easily bent"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Watched the VAGABOND.",
                  "answers": [
                    "wanderer",
                    "dirty child",
                    "thin man",
                    "clown",
                    "housewife"
                  ],
                  "word": "VAGABOND",
                  "correct": "wanderer"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INGRAINED beliefs.",
                  "answers": [
                    "past",
                    "deep-rooted",
                    "strange",
                    "annoying",
                    "new"
                  ],
                  "word": "INGRAINED",
                  "correct": "deep-rooted"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They may RELENT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "attack",
                    "worry",
                    "return",
                    "give in",
                    "show up"
                  ],
                  "word": "RELENT",
                  "correct": "give in"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a parking lot be a RENDEZVOUS?",
                  "word": "RENDEZVOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a RESOLUTE person change his mind often?",
                  "word": "RESOLUTE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is everyone allowed to see a movie that is RESTRICTED?",
                  "word": "RESTRICT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is mountain climbing usually an ILLICIT action?",
                  "word": "ILLICIT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a SARCASTIC person usually lovable?",
                  "word": "SARCASTIC",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are atoms MINUSCULE?",
                  "word": "MINUSCULE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most people be STUPEFIED if they were given a check for a million dollars?",
                  "word": "STUPEFY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would staying up all night INVIGORATE most people?",
                  "word": "INVIGORATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does a man who tries for ten years to get through college show PERSERVERANCE",
                  "word": "PERSEVERE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can an aroma WAFT into a room?",
                  "word": "WAFT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a person who hasn't slept for days usually look HAGGARD?",
                  "word": "HAGGARD",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a steel bar PLIANT?",
                  "word": "PLIANT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a VAGABOND like to hold a steady job?",
                  "word": "VAGABOND",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a strong habit be INGRAINED in a person?",
                  "word": "INGRAINED",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it likely that a lazy person would be RELENTLESS in pursuing a job?",
                  "word": "RELENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "We all arranged to RENDEZVOUS at midnight in the old barn.",
                  "word": "RENDEZVOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It was RESOLUTE that they would go to the beach this weekend.",
                  "word": "RESOLUTE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She RESTRICTED them that smoking was not allowed here.",
                  "word": "RESTRICT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The police charged him with the ILLICIT sale of liquor.",
                  "word": "ILLICIT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She was very SARCASTIC to go into the house by herself.",
                  "word": "SARCASTIC",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The MINUSCULE church towered above the houses in the area.",
                  "word": "MINUSCULE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "I was STUPEFIED to find out that I had actually won first prize in the contest.",
                  "word": "STUPEFY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The knowledge that he was almost finished INVIGORATED him and kept him going.",
                  "word": "INVIGORATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Even if you are not successful at first, you must PERSEVERE.",
                  "word": "PERSEVERE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The sound of the beautiful music WAFTED across the lake.",
                  "word": "WAFT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He looked very HAGGARD after running the marathon.",
                  "word": "HAGGARD",
                  "correct": ".true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "John is very PLIANT. He will go along with whatever the rest of the group wants.",
                  "word": "PLIANT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Each summer the students became VAGABONDS, roaming through the countryside and having a good time.",
                  "word": "VAGABOND",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She has practiced that piece on the piano for so long that it has become INGRAINED in her mind.",
                  "word": "INGRAINED",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She RELENTED him severely for not trying.",
                  "word": "RELENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "RENDEZVOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "appointment",
                    "date",
                    "voyage"
                  ],
                  "word": "RENDEZVOUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RESOLUTE",
                  "answers": [
                    "stubborn",
                    "typical",
                    "persistent"
                  ],
                  "word": "RESOLUTE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RESTRICT",
                  "answers": [
                    "hold back",
                    "give in",
                    "keep out"
                  ],
                  "word": "RESTRICT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ILLICIT",
                  "answers": [
                    "forbidden",
                    "dangerous",
                    "illegal"
                  ],
                  "word": "ILLICIT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SARCASTIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "hurtful",
                    "insulting",
                    "brilliant"
                  ],
                  "word": "SARCASTIC",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MINUSCULE",
                  "answers": [
                    "little",
                    "young",
                    "small"
                  ],
                  "word": "MINUSCULE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "STUPEFY",
                  "answers": [
                    "delight",
                    "astonish",
                    "daze"
                  ],
                  "word": "STUPEFY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INVIGORATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "refresh",
                    "stimulate",
                    "clean"
                  ],
                  "word": "INVIGORATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PERSEVERE",
                  "answers": [
                    "endure",
                    "continue",
                    "appear"
                  ],
                  "word": "PERSEVERE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "WAFT",
                  "answers": [
                    "move",
                    "burn",
                    "float"
                  ],
                  "word": "WAFT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HAGGARD",
                  "answers": [
                    "short",
                    "tired",
                    "weary"
                  ],
                  "word": "HAGGARD",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PLIANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "elastic",
                    "agreeable",
                    "various"
                  ],
                  "word": "PLIANT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VAGABOND",
                  "answers": [
                    "traveler",
                    "marcher",
                    "wanderer"
                  ],
                  "word": "VAGABOND",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INGRAINED",
                  "answers": [
                    "large",
                    "deep",
                    "firm"
                  ],
                  "word": "INGRAINED",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RELENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "yield",
                    "accept",
                    "hope"
                  ],
                  "word": "RELENT",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "5.6",
          "definitions": {
            "COMPOSURE": {
              "word": "COMPOSURE",
              "phonetic": "(kÔøΩm-pO'-zhÔøΩr)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">calmness, self- possession </p><p>The verb COMPOSE has several different meanings. One has to do with mental states, and means to <i class=“def-ital\">calm</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">get under control.</i> </p><p>“It took him a while to COMPOSE himself after he almost had an accident.” </p><p>COMPOSURE is the noun from this meaning of COMPOSE. COMPOSURE means <i class=“def-ital\">calmness, self-possession.</i> </p><p>“She managed to keep her COMPOSURE despite the intense pressure of the job.” </p><p>“The witness lost his COMPOSURE and started shouting when the lawyer accused him of being a liar.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: COMPOSE,v. COMPOSED,adj.</p>"
            },
            "PROPHECY": {
              "word": "PROPHECY",
              "phonetic": "(prof'-ÔøΩ-sE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a prediction, foretelling </p><p>A PROPHECY is a prediction of what will happen in the future. People who have the power of PROPHECY are supposed to be able to tell what is going to happen. </p><p>“She made several PROPHECIES about events in the coming year.” </p><p>“His PROPHECY that the farmers would suffer a terrible drought did not come true.” </p><p>A PROPHET is someone who makes PROPHECIES. To PROPHESY(pronounced prot’‚ùñ-sl)is to make a PROPHECY. Notice the difference in spelling. </p><p>“He PROPHESIED that the world would come to an end,but no one believed his PROPHECY.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: PROPHESY,v. PROPHET,n. PROPHETIC,adj.</p>"
            },
            "EXEMPT": {
              "word": "EXEMPT",
              "phonetic": "(eg-zempt')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to grant freedom (from a duty), release, excuse </p><p>To EXEMPT someone is to release him from a duty which others have to carry out or a burden which others have to bear. The word is usually applied to legal obligations. </p><p>“They EXEMPTED him from military service be- cause of his poor eyesight.” </p><p>“Why was she EXEMPTED from paying taxes?” </p><p>EXEMPT is also used as an adjective. </p><p>“Persons EXEMPT from the draft had to perform some kind of alternate service.” </p><p>“We thought the camera was EXEMPT from customs duties.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: EXEMPTION,n. </p><p>Usage: EXEMPT is usually used with from.</p>"
            },
            "MAGISTERIAL": {
              "word": "MAGISTERIAL",
              "phonetic": "(maj-ÔøΩ-stEr'-E-ÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">commanding, authoritative See <i class=“def-ital\">-al</i> under Suffixes. MAGISTERIAL comes from the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">master</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">teacher.</i> MAGISTERIAL means “like a master” and refers to the authority and air of command that a master of something would show. </p><p>“He had a MAGISTERIAL attitude that suggested he was used to giving orders instead of receiving them.” </p><p>The word is often used in a negative sense, suggesting that this air of command is rather overbearing. </p><p>“He spoke in a MAGISTERIAL tone, as if his were the only opinions worth hearing.”</p>"
            },
            "MARINER": {
              "word": "MARINER",
              "phonetic": "(mar'-ÔøΩ-nÔøΩr)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a sailor, seaman </p><p>See <i class=“def-ital\">-er</i> under Suffixes. MARINER comes from <i class=“def-ital\">mare,</i> the Latin word for sea and also the source of the word <i class=“def-ital\">marine.</i> A MARINER is someone who sails the sea, a <i class=“def-ital\">sailor.</i> The word is particularly used about someone who navi- gates or assists in navigating a ship. </p><p>On the Pretest, many people think MARINER means <i class=“def-ital\">swimmer.</i> These people know that MARINER has something to do with the sea, but aren’t sure what. </p><p>Usage: MARINER is a literary word and would not often be used in ordinary speech.</p>"
            },
            "APPALLING": {
              "word": "APPALLING",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩpol'-ing)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">horrifying, frightful, dreadful, shocking </p><p>The verb APPALL is related to the word <i class=“def-ital\">pale.</i> Something that APPALLS you shocks or horrifies you so much that you turn pale. </p><p>“The news of the president’s assassination APPALLED everyone.” </p><p>Something that is APPALLING fills you with emotions that may range from horror to dismay, usually because it is so bad or unpleasant. </p><p>“The disaster was APPALLING: over seven thousand people died.” </p><p>“The dog got loose while the family was out and made an APPALLING mess in the house.” </p><p>“Mary showed an APPALLING lack of manners when she slammed the door in the woman’s face.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: APPALL, v.</p>"
            },
            "EMIT": {
              "word": "EMIT",
              "phonetic": "{i-mit')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to send out, send forth, throw off, utter </p><p>See <i class=“def-ital\">ex-</i> under Prefixes. EMIT means to <i class=“def-ital\">send out.</i> The word is often used about light, heat, and sound. </p><p>“The fire EMITS a great deal of smoke.” </p><p>“The loudspeaker EMITS an awful noise.” </p><p>EMIT is also used about words, orders, and opinions. </p><p>“The crowd EMITTED a groan.” </p><p>The word is not usually used about people. You would not say: </p><p>“The policeman EMITTED the trespassers.” </p><p>EMIT can easily be confused with <i class=“def-ital\">admit,</i> although the two words are just about opposites in meaning. EMIT is to send out; <i class=“def-ital\">admit</i> is to let in. A restaurant would not want to <i class=“def-ital\">admit</i> a customer who might EMIT a lot of loud noise. </p><p>Other forms of the word: EMISSION, n.</p>"
            },
            "PETITION": {
              "word": "PETITION",
              "phonetic": "(pg-tish'-::m)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">an appeal, formal request </p><p>A PETITION is an <i class=“def-ital\">appeal</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">request,</i> usually a formal written request asking for something from someone in power. </p><p>“All the students signed a PETITION asking the school committee not to fire the teacher.” </p><p>“The mayor listened to their PETITION for more police and agreed to look into the matter.” </p><p>PETITION is also a verb. </p><p>“The mother PETITIONED the king to release her son from prison.” </p><p>“The prisoner PETITIONED the court for a new trial.”</p>"
            },
            "VILE": {
              "word": "VILE",
              "phonetic": "(vii)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">wretched, disgusting, foul </p><p>A person or thing that is VILE is disgustingly evil. </p><p>“The police called it one of the VILEST crimes they had ever seen.” </p><p>VILE is also used about things that are disgustingly filthy or low. </p><p>“The VILE conditions and VILE smell in the restaurant’s kitchen shocked everyone.” </p><p>“When he was upset his language would become VILE and he would curse everyone and everything.” </p><p>VILE is a very strong word and should be used about people or things that are almost unspeakably bad. </p><p>The most popular wrong answer is <i class=“def-ital\">dangerous.</i> VILE conditions are not necessarily <i class=“def-ital\">dangerous.</i> They are certainly foul and wretched.</p>"
            },
            "MERIT": {
              "word": "MERIT",
              "phonetic": "(mer'-it)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to deserve, earn, be worthy of </p><p>To MERIT something is to deserve or be worthy of it. </p><p>“This painting MERITS first prize.” </p><p>“Her suggestion MERITS careful consideration.” </p><p>“His criticism of Jane was MERITED. She really was rude.” </p><p>MERIT is also a noun, meaning <i class=“def-ital\">worth</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">excellence.</i> </p><p>“His plan has great MERIT, but it isn’t perfect.” </p><p>“He got that job by MERIT, not because he knew someone.” </p><p>The most commonly chosen incorrect answer is <i class=“def-ital\">win.</i> You can <i class=“def-ital\">win</i> something without having MERITED it, though, and you can MERIT something without <i class=“def-ital\">winning</i> it. “We thought he MERITED first prize, but he only came in third.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: MERITORIOUS, adj.</p>"
            },
            "EMINENT": {
              "word": "EMINENT",
              "phonetic": "(em'-g-ngnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">distinguished, prominent, outstanding, noteworthy </p><p>The basic meaning of EMINENT is “standing out.” EMI- NENT is related to the word <i class=“def-ital\">mountain,</i> and is sometimes used about actual physical size. Usually,though,the word is used about people and it means “standing above others in quality or fame.” </p><p>“Even the most EMINENT physicians couldn’t discover what was wrong with him.” </p><p>“The EMINENT author spoke about the future of the novel.” </p><p>When used about qualities, EMINENT means <i class=“def-ital\">remarkable</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">conspicuous.</i> </p><p>“Everyone praised the EMINENT fairness of the judge’s decision.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: EMINENCE,n.</p>"
            },
            "YIELD": {
              "word": "YIELD",
              "phonetic": "(yEld)",
              "pos": "v.to",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">give, give up, give way The basic meaning of YIELD is to <i class=“def-ital\">give- or <i class=“def-ital\">give up.</i> The word is used in a wide variety of senses. When a tree YIELDS fruit,it gives or produces it. When a car YIELDS to another,it gives way so that the other one can go first. An enemy who YIELDS gives up or surrenders. To YIELD to temptation is to give in to it. </p><p>“The door YIELDED when she pushed against it.” </p><p>“The teacher YIELDED to their request and called off the test.” </p><p>YIELD is also a noun. </p><p>“That one bush has a YIELD of ten pounds of ber- ries.”</p>"
            },
            "NOVICE": {
              "word": "NOVICE",
              "phonetic": "(nov'-is)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a beginner, inexperienced person </p><p>NOVICE comes from the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">new,</i> also the source of the words <i class=“def-ital\">novel</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">novelty.</i> A NOVICE is a person who is new at doing something, <i class=“def-ital\">a beginner.</i> The word was first used about someone who has just entered a religious order, but is now used about any inexperienced beginner. </p><p>“She is just a NOVICE at playing the piano, so don’t expect her to be very good.” </p><p>“He can type very well for a NOVICE.”</p>"
            },
            "JOCULAR": {
              "word": "JOCULAR",
              "phonetic": "(jok'-yg-lgr)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">humorous, merry, jolly JOCULAR is related to the word <i class=“def-ital\">joke.</i> A JOCULAR person likes to make jokes. He is jolly and enjoys keeping other people amused. </p><p>“The JOCULAR teacher kept the students laughing while they learned.” </p><p>JOCULAR words or actions are said or done as a joke. </p><p>“The speaker started off with some JOCULAR re- marks to put his audience in a good mood.</p><p>” The noun from JOCULAR is JOCULARITY, which is the quality of being humorous and jolly. </p><p>“His JOCULARITY was quite out of place on such a solemn occasion.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: JOCULARITY, n.</p>"
            },
            "HARROWING": {
              "word": "HARROWING",
              "phonetic": "(har'-0-ing)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">distressing, agonizing, painful, frightening </p><p>A HARROW is a farming tool which cuts into and levels off ground. To HARROW something is to draw a HAR- ROW over it. The word has come to mean to <i class=“def-ital\">distress</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">disturb</i> a person as if he were being cut into by a HARROW. HARROWING is the adjective from this meaning of HARROW. It means <i class=“def-ital\">distressing, painful,</i> especially to the mind or the feelings. </p><p>“Being attacked by the bear was a HARROWING experience.” </p><p>“He told us a HARROWING tale of torture and suffering.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: HARROW,n.,v.</p>"
            }
          },
          "id": "6",
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Noticed her COMPOSURE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "position",
                    "cleverness",
                    "anger",
                    "calmness",
                    "happiness"
                  ],
                  "word": "COMPOSURE",
                  "correct": "calmness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Strange PROPHECY.",
                  "answers": [
                    "prediction",
                    "religion",
                    "knowledge",
                    "result",
                    "sickness"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROPHECY",
                  "correct": "prediction"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Did we EXEMPT him?",
                  "answers": [
                    "reward",
                    "claim",
                    "request",
                    "stop",
                    "release"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXEMPT",
                  "correct": "release"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MAGISTERIAL tone.",
                  "answers": [
                    "commanding",
                    "unpleasant",
                    "strange",
                    "mild",
                    "critical"
                  ],
                  "word": "MAGISTERIAL",
                  "correct": "commanding"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Excellent MARINER.",
                  "answers": [
                    "swimmer",
                    "minister",
                    "sailor",
                    "scientist",
                    "soldier"
                  ],
                  "word": "MARINER",
                  "correct": "sailor"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Your APPALLING statements.",
                  "answers": [
                    "irritating",
                    "unfriendly",
                    "polite",
                    "exciting",
                    "horrifying"
                  ],
                  "word": "APPALLING",
                  "correct": "horrifying"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To EMIT the sound.",
                  "answers": [
                    "cause",
                    "send out",
                    "cover up",
                    "increase",
                    "let in"
                  ],
                  "word": "EMIT",
                  "correct": "send out"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Know about his PETITION.",
                  "answers": [
                    "struggle",
                    "problem",
                    "appeal",
                    "loss",
                    "threat"
                  ],
                  "word": "PETITION",
                  "correct": "appeal"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VILE conditions.",
                  "answers": [
                    "strange",
                    "pleasant",
                    "old",
                    "dangerous",
                    "wretched"
                  ],
                  "word": "VILE",
                  "correct": "wretched"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To MERIT it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "wm",
                    "accept",
                    "want",
                    "deserve",
                    "refuse"
                  ],
                  "word": "MERIT",
                  "correct": "deserve"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EMINENT people.",
                  "answers": [
                    "distinguished",
                    "unusual",
                    "average",
                    "dangerous",
                    "little-known"
                  ],
                  "word": "EMINENT",
                  "correct": "distinguished"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They will YIELD.",
                  "answers": [
                    "give up",
                    "help",
                    "stand",
                    "move in",
                    "scream"
                  ],
                  "word": "YIELD",
                  "correct": "give up"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They were NOVICES.",
                  "answers": [
                    "beggars",
                    "saints",
                    "beginners",
                    "unknowns",
                    "experts"
                  ],
                  "word": "NOVICE",
                  "correct": "beginners"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Always JOCULAR.",
                  "answers": [
                    "helpful",
                    "serious",
                    "humorous",
                    "bright",
                    "excited"
                  ],
                  "word": "JOCULAR",
                  "correct": "humorous"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HARROWING stories.",
                  "answers": [
                    "complicated",
                    "distressing",
                    "comical",
                    "soothing",
                    "disgusting"
                  ],
                  "word": "HARROWING",
                  "correct": "distressing"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a person who lost his temper every ten minutes lack COMPOSURE?",
                  "word": "COMPOSURE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does a PROPHECY deal with future events?",
                  "word": "PROPHECY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most students like to be EXEMPT from doing homework?",
                  "word": "EXEMPT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do children usually have a MAGISTERIAL air?",
                  "word": "MAGISTERIAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a MARINER usually be found on board a ship?",
                  "word": "MARINER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most people be APPALLED at winning a prize?",
                  "word": "APPALLING",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does the sun EMIT light?",
                  "word": "EMIT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are PETITIONS always successful?",
                  "word": "PETITION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a hospital want its operating room to be in VILE condition?",
                  "word": "VILE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are suggestions that have MERIT worthless?",
                  "word": "MERIT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are all lawyers EMINENT?",
                  "word": "EMINENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it polite for someone to YIELD his seat to an old person?",
                  "word": "YIELD",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a NOVICE at tennis likely to be a good player?",
                  "word": "NOVICE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are comedians usually JOCULAR?",
                  "word": "JOCULAR",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is listening to music usually a HARROWING experience?",
                  "word": "HARROWING",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "We all listened to the musician's beautiful COMPOSURE.",
                  "word": "COMPOSURE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He PROPHESIED that we lost six games last season.",
                  "word": "PROPHECY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Because of his bad back they EXEMPTED him from physical work.",
                  "word": "EXEMPT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His MAGISTERIAL tone prompted us to obey him.",
                  "word": "MAGISTERIAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Several MARINERS were drowned when the ship sank.",
                  "word": "MARINER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Everyone was stunned by the APPALLING news that the earthquake had destroyed the town.",
                  "word": "APPALLING",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The crowd EMITTED a cheer as the fireworks went off.",
                  "word": "EMIT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The player PETITIONED the school to let him rejoin the team.",
                  "word": "PETITION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Sue's VILE personality charmed everyone.",
                  "word": "VILE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He MERITED his opponent by three points in the match.",
                  "word": "MERIT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His years of study and writing had made him an EMINENT authority in his field.",
                  "word": "EMINENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She YIELDED to the child's demands and let him stay up later.",
                  "word": "YIELD",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Tom may be only a NOVICE, but he's good learner and should improve quickly.",
                  "word": "NOVICE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Their constant JOCULARITY kept the meeting from being a very serious one.",
                  "word": "JOCULAR",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Andy had a HARROWING dream in which his house caught fire.",
                  "word": "HARROWING",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "COMPOSURE",
                  "answers": [
                    "calmness",
                    "sadness",
                    "relaxation"
                  ],
                  "word": "COMPOSURE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROPHECY",
                  "answers": [
                    "expectation",
                    "prediction",
                    "demand"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROPHECY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXEMPT",
                  "answers": [
                    "allow",
                    "excuse",
                    "order"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXEMPT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MAGISTERIAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "suggesting",
                    "demanding",
                    "ordering"
                  ],
                  "word": "MAGISTERIAL",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MARINER",
                  "answers": [
                    "pilot",
                    "sailor",
                    "marine"
                  ],
                  "word": "MARINER",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "APPALLING",
                  "answers": [
                    "displeasing",
                    "disgusting",
                    "horrifying"
                  ],
                  "word": "APPALLING",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EMIT",
                  "answers": [
                    "eject",
                    "nod",
                    "utter"
                  ],
                  "word": "EMIT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PETITION",
                  "answers": [
                    "demand",
                    "request",
                    "beg"
                  ],
                  "word": "PETITION",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VILE",
                  "answers": [
                    "crippled",
                    "wicked",
                    "filthy"
                  ],
                  "word": "VILE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MERIT",
                  "answers": [
                    "size",
                    "value",
                    "worth"
                  ],
                  "word": "MERIT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EMINENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "outstanding",
                    "important",
                    "peculiar"
                  ],
                  "word": "EMINENT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "YIELD",
                  "answers": [
                    "refuse",
                    "surrender",
                    "produce"
                  ],
                  "word": "YIELD",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NOVICE",
                  "answers": [
                    "stranger",
                    "apprentice",
                    "beginner"
                  ],
                  "word": "NOVICE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "JOCULAR",
                  "answers": [
                    "happy",
                    "amusing",
                    "sweet"
                  ],
                  "word": "JOCULAR",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HARROWING",
                  "answers": [
                    "painful",
                    "unpleasant",
                    "strange"
                  ],
                  "word": "HARROWING",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        }
      ],
      "reviewTest": {
        "wordList": [
          {
            "word": "ALLIANCE",
            "answer": "alliance"
          },
          {
            "word": "IMPOVERISH",
            "answer": "impoverished"
          },
          {
            "word": "MERIT",
            "answer": "merited"
          },
          {
            "word": "RAUCOUS",
            "answer": "raucous"
          },
          {
            "word": "SARCASTIC",
            "answer": "sarcastic"
          },
          {
            "word": "CIVILITY",
            "answer": "civility"
          },
          {
            "word": "INSTIGATE",
            "answer": "instigated"
          },
          {
            "word": "MINUSCULE",
            "answer": "minuscule"
          },
          {
            "word": "RENDEZVOUS",
            "answer": "rendezvous"
          },
          {
            "word": "VILE",
            "answer": "vile"
          },
          {
            "word": "COMPOSURE",
            "answer": "composure"
          },
          {
            "word": "INVIGORATE",
            "answer": "invigorated"
          },
          {
            "word": "NOVICE",
            "answer": "novice"
          },
          {
            "word": "RESOLUTE",
            "answer": "resolute"
          },
          {
            "word": "WAFT",
            "answer": "wafted"
          },
          {
            "word": "DISPATCH",
            "answer": "dispatched"
          },
          {
            "word": "LAPSE",
            "answer": "lapses"
          },
          {
            "word": "PERSEVERE",
            "answer": "persevere"
          },
          {
            "word": "RESTRICT",
            "answer": "restricted"
          },
          {
            "word": "YIELD",
            "answer": "yielded"
          },
          {
            "word": "EMIT",
            "answer": "emit"
          },
          {
            "word": "APPALLING",
            "answer": "appalling"
          },
          {
            "word": "EXCAVATE",
            "answer": "excavated"
          },
          {
            "word": "HUMILITY",
            "answer": "humility"
          },
          {
            "word": "MAGISTERIAL",
            "answer": "magisterial"
          },
          {
            "word": "RELENT",
            "answer": "relented"
          },
          {
            "word": "BOMBARD",
            "answer": "bombarded"
          },
          {
            "word": "EXEMPT",
            "answer": "exempt"
          },
          {
            "word": "ILLICIT",
            "answer": "illicit"
          },
          {
            "word": "MARINER",
            "answer": "Mariner"
          },
          {
            "word": "STUPEFY",
            "answer": "stupefied"
          },
          {
            "word": "DEEM",
            "answer": "deemed"
          },
          {
            "word": "HAGGARD",
            "answer": "haggard"
          },
          {
            "word": "INFILTRATE",
            "answer": "infiltrate"
          },
          {
            "word": "PETITION",
            "answer": "petition"
          },
          {
            "word": "UNRULY",
            "answer": "unruly"
          },
          {
            "word": "EMINENT",
            "answer": "eminent"
          },
          {
            "word": "HAMPER",
            "answer": "hampered"
          },
          {
            "word": "INGRAINED",
            "answer": "ingrained"
          },
          {
            "word": "PLIANT",
            "answer": "pliant"
          },
          {
            "word": "VAGABOND",
            "answer": "vagabond"
          },
          {
            "word": "ESPIONAGE",
            "answer": "espionage"
          },
          {
            "word": "HARROWING",
            "answer": "harrowing"
          },
          {
            "word": "JOCULAR",
            "answer": "jocular"
          },
          {
            "word": "PROPHECY",
            "answer": "prophecy"
          }
        ],
        "questions": [
          {
            "part1": "He manages to keep his",
            "part2": "even when everyone else is upset and worried.",
            "correct": "composure",
            "word": "COMPOSURE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The teacher",
            "part2": "three of us to see what was causing all the noise downstairs.",
            "correct": "dispatched",
            "word": "DISPATCH"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Wally's back operations",
            "part2": "his family; they owed the hospital thousands of dollars.",
            "correct": "impoverished",
            "word": "IMPOVERISH"
          },
          {
            "part1": "A border dispute broke up the previously strong",
            "part2": "between the two countries.",
            "correct": "alliance",
            "word": "ALLIANCE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He tried not to be",
            "part2": "but he often couldn't help making fun in a cruel way of other people.",
            "correct": "sarcastic",
            "word": "SARCASTIC"
          },
          {
            "part1": "A quick swim always",
            "part2": "him and made him feel as good as new.",
            "correct": "invigorated",
            "word": "INVIGORATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "When volcanoes erupt, they",
            "part2": "tons of lava and gas.",
            "correct": "emit",
            "word": "EMIT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He was such a(n)",
            "part2": "at the job that he didn't even know the name of the machine he was supposed to run.",
            "correct": "novice",
            "word": "NOVICE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "On her diet she is",
            "part2": "to salt-free foods.",
            "correct": "restricted",
            "word": "RESTRICT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The apartment is so",
            "part2": "I don't know how anyone could live in it; there is garbage everywhere.",
            "correct": "vile",
            "word": "VILE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Because they weren't allowed to see each other, they had to arrange a secret",
            "part2": "for late that night.",
            "correct": "rendezvous",
            "word": "RENDEZVOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "After all their work the miners only found a(n)",
            "part2": "amount of gold-barely enough to fill a bottlecap.",
            "correct": "minuscule",
            "word": "MINUSCULE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The gentle breeze",
            "part2": "the clouds across the sky.",
            "correct": "wafted",
            "word": "WAFT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Her fiery speech",
            "part2": "the workers to go on strike.",
            "correct": "instigated",
            "word": "INSTIGATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He had one or two",
            "part2": "as he recited the poem, but overall he had it memorized quite well.",
            "correct": "lapses",
            "word": "LAPSE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We must treat all people we meet with",
            "part2": ", even if we do not particularly like them.",
            "correct": "civility",
            "word": "CIVILITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We were awakened by the",
            "part2": "sounds of the men shouting to each other and banging rubbish cans together.",
            "correct": "raucous",
            "word": "RAUCOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We must be",
            "part2": "and not give in to their demands.",
            "correct": "resolute",
            "word": "RESOLUTE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The principal promised to",
            "part2": "in his efforts to improve the school.",
            "correct": "persevere",
            "word": "PERSEVERE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Her great performance",
            "part2": "a gold medal.",
            "correct": "merited",
            "word": "MERIT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He",
            "part2": "his place in line to someone who was in a hurry.",
            "correct": "yielded",
            "word": "YIELD"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We need a material that is",
            "part2": "enough to bend easily around this metal rod.",
            "correct": "pliant",
            "word": "PLIANT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "My uncle is quite a(n)",
            "part2": "fellow. He always has a funny story or riddle to tell us.",
            "correct": "jocular",
            "word": "JOCULAR"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The store was charged with the",
            "part2": "sale of alcohol to minors.",
            "correct": "illicit",
            "word": "ILLICIT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Jack was so",
            "part2": "by the incredible news that he forgot his own name.",
            "correct": "stupefied",
            "word": "STUPEFY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "By the end of the long hot day all the workers looked very",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "haggard",
            "word": "HAGGARD"
          },
          {
            "part1": "It was a(n)",
            "part2": "experience to be trapped in the house during the flood.",
            "correct": "harrowing",
            "word": "HARROWING"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The students' scores on the reading test were they were by far the worst in the city.",
            "correct": "appalling",
            "word": "APPALLING"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He quit his job, sold his house, and became a(n)",
            "part2": ", traveling constantly throughout the country.",
            "correct": "vagabond",
            "word": "VAGABOND"
          },
          {
            "part1": "They presented the king with a(n)",
            "part2": "asking that taxes be lowered.",
            "correct": "petition",
            "word": "PETITION"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Bill's father wasn't going to let him go to the movies, but finally he",
            "part2": "and said it was all right.",
            "correct": "relented",
            "word": "RELENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "They",
            "part2": "tons of earth from the area in order to make the tunnel.",
            "correct": "excavated",
            "word": "EXCAVATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Despite his success, he kept a sense of",
            "part2": ", thinking that he didn't really deserve it.",
            "correct": "humility",
            "word": "HUMILITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The mayor",
            "part2": "it to be of the utmost importance that everyone be prepared for a flood.",
            "correct": "deemed",
            "word": "DEEM"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The clever spy managed to",
            "part2": "the secret organization.",
            "correct": "infiltrate",
            "word": "INFILTRATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The habit of eating breakfast quickly has become",
            "part2": "in him over the years, and now it's difficult to stop.",
            "correct": "ingrained",
            "word": "INGRAINED"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He was accused of stealing secret documents and committing other acts of",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "espionage",
            "word": "ESPIONAGE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The enemy guns",
            "part2": "us night and day until we were forced to surrender.",
            "correct": "bombarded",
            "word": "BOMBARD"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We are annoyed by his",
            "part2": "attitude. Why does he think he can give us orders?",
            "correct": "magisterial",
            "word": "MAGISTERIAL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Coleridge wrote a long poem about a shipwrecked sailor called \"The Rime of the Ancient",
            "part2": ".\"",
            "correct": "Mariner",
            "word": "MARINER"
          },
          {
            "part1": "This",
            "part2": "scientist has won many prizes for his brilliant studies.",
            "correct": "eminent",
            "word": "EMINENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "crowd surged through the police barriers and shouted insults at the politician.",
            "correct": "unruly",
            "word": "UNRULY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "A hundred years ago he made the remarkable",
            "part2": "that someday men would walk on the moon.",
            "correct": "prophecy",
            "word": "PROPHECY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "A shortage of money",
            "part2": "our efforts to clean up the school.",
            "correct": "hampered",
            "word": "HAMPER"
          },
          {
            "part1": "They decided to",
            "part2": "him from having to pass the height requirement for the police force.",
            "correct": "exempt",
            "word": "EXEMPT"
          }
        ],
        "type": "fitb"
      }
    },
    {
      "wordsets": [
        {
          "title": "5.7",
          "definitions": {
            "ENFEEBLE": {
              "word": "ENFEEBLE",
              "phonetic": "(en-fE'-bÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to cause extreme weakness, make feeble </p><p>FEEBLE means <i class=“def-ital\">very weak, lacking strength.</i> The prefix <i class=“def-ital\">en-</i> means “to cause to be,” as in <i class=“def-ital\">enslave,</i> “to cause to be a slave.” So ENFEEBLE means “to cause to be FEE- BLE.” </p><p>“The long illness ENFEEBLED him.” </p><p>“The animals were ENFEEBLED by lack of food.” </p><p>On the Pretest, many people think ENFEEBLE means <i class=“def-ital\">strengthen,</i> which is opposite in meaning. This may be due to a confusion of the prefix <i class=“def-ital\">en-</i> with <i class=“def-ital\">un-</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">in-,</i> both of which can mean <i class=“def-ital\">not.</i></p>"
            },
            "PROFOUND": {
              "word": "PROFOUND",
              "phonetic": "(prÔøΩfownd')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">deep </p><p>The basic meaning of PROFOUND is <i class=“def-ital\">very deep.</i> The word is sometimes used about physical depth, but it is usually used about interests, ideas, feelings, and the like. PROFOUND often suggests depth of knowledge or wisdom. </p><p>“It was very difficult to awaken him from his PROFOUND sleep.” </p><p>“My father has a PROFOUND interest in painting.” </p><p>“The author showed a PROFOUND understanding of the way governments work.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: PROFUNDITY, n.</p>"
            },
            "CRESTFALLEN": {
              "word": "CRESTFALLEN",
              "phonetic": "(krest'-fol-ÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">discouraged, dejected, disappointed </p><p>A <i class=“def-ital\">crest</i> is the tuft of feathers on the top of a bird’s head. The basic meaning of CRESTFALLEN is “with the crest drooping or falling\"-that is, with the head hanging down. From this the word has come to mean “so disappointed, dejected, or discouraged that you want to hang your head.” </p><p>“Jim was CRESTFALLEN when he heard he hadn’t made the team.” </p><p>“Sally will be CRESTFALLEN if she doesn’t get a new bicycle for Christmas.” </p><p>“The boss told the CRESTFALLEN workers that he couldn’t afford to give them a raise.”</p>"
            },
            "EXALT": {
              "word": "EXALT",
              "phonetic": "(eg-zolt')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to raise high, elevate, glorify </p><p>EXALT comes from the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">high,</i> also the source for the word <i class=“def-ital\">altitude.</i> To EXALT someone is to make him higher, usually in rank, power, or dignity. </p><p>“They EXALTED her by calling her the greatest writer of our time.” </p><p>“In his EXALTED position he has little time for these little problems.” </p><p>The most common mistake on the Pretest is choosing <i class=“def-ital\">thrown out</i> as the meaning of EXALTED. This may be due to confusion about the <i class=“def-ital\">ex-</i> at the beginning of the word, which often means <i class=“def-ital\">out of.</i> Other forms of the word: EXALTATION, n.</p>"
            },
            "REGAL": {
              "word": "REGAL",
              "phonetic": "(rE'-gÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">royal, kingly </p><p>See <i class=“def-ital\">-al</i> under Suffixes. REGAL comes from the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">king,</i> and means “belonging to or like a king.” The word often suggests the splendor and magnificence associated with a king. </p><p>“The king was dressed in all his REGAL splendor for this occasion.” </p><p>“He was disguised as a beggar, but his REGAL atti- tude gave him away.” </p><p>“They had a REGAL feast to celebrate their great vic- tory.”</p>"
            },
            "ALLURE": {
              "word": "ALLURE",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩIUr')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to attract, entice, charm </p><p>ALLURE is related to the word <i class=“def-ital\">lure,</i> and the two words have similar meanings. To ALLURE someone is to attract him with the offer of something valuable or pleasing. </p><p>“The salesman ALLURED us with tales of fabulous wealth if we bought this stock.” </p><p>“The hope of becoming a movie star ALLURES many young women to Hollywood.” </p><p>As a noun, ALLURE is this power of attraction, <i class=“def-ital\">charm.</i> </p><p>“The job offer lacked sufficient ALLURE to tempt her.” </p><p>“The city of Paris holds quite an ALLURE for many tourists.” Other forms of the word: ALLUREMENT, n. ALLURING, adj.</p>"
            },
            "AMICABLE": {
              "word": "AMICABLE",
              "phonetic": "(am'-i-k:)-bÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">friendly, peaceable, neighborly </p><p>AMICABLE is used about people’s actions or attitudes and means “showing good will,” <i class=“def-ital\">friendly.</i> AMICABLE is not a very strong word. It usually doesn’t suggest deep affection, but merely shows that people aren’t disposed to quarrel with one another. </p><p>“Both parties seemed eager for an AMICABLE settlement of their dispute.” </p><p>“The two countries maintained AMICABLE relations despite their disagreements.” </p><p>“We solved our differences AMICABLY and continued to work together.”</p>"
            },
            "GUTTURAL": {
              "word": "GUTTURAL",
              "phonetic": "(guht'-:)-rÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">of the throat. </p><p>Note the spelling. The word is spelled with <i class=“def-ital\">ur,</i> not <i class=“def-ital\">er,</i> in the middle. GUTTURAL comes from the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">throat</i> and means “related to the throat.” The word is usually used about sounds that are produced in the throat and suggests a harsh, unpleasant quality. </p><p>“The sound of the <i class=“def-ital\">ch</i> in <i class=“def-ital\">acht,</i> the German word for ’eight,’ is a GUTTURAL sound\"-that is, it is formed in the throat, not the mouth.</p>"
            },
            "FOLLY": {
              "word": "FOLLY",
              "phonetic": "(fol'-E)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">foolishness, silliness </p><p>FOLLY means <i class=“def-ital\">foolishness, silliness, lack of wisdom.</i> The word often suggests that this foolishness might have bad consequences. </p><p>“Attempting to swim the Atlantic Ocean was an act of FOLLY.” </p><p>“It was FOLLY to ask the boss for a raise.” </p><p>FOLLY has been used about a particular event, place, or building. For example, when Secretary of State Seward advised President Lincoln to purchase Alaska, Alaska be- came known as “Seward’s FOLLY” because it was thought that nothing valuable existed there, and its pur- chase was just a waste of money. It is FOLLY to judge the value of a purchase too quickly.</p>"
            },
            "CONVEY": {
              "word": "CONVEY",
              "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-vA')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to carry, deliver, transport; to communicate, make known </p><p>To CONVEY something is to carry it from one place to another. </p><p>“This pipe CONVEYS water from the well to the house.” </p><p>“Telegraph signals are CONVEYED from one town to another by wires.” </p><p>CONVEY is also used about ideas, information, and feelings and means to <i class=“def-ital\">make known,</i> either directly or indirectly. </p><p>“He CONVEYED his approval by nodding and smiling.” </p><p>“We wish to CONVEY our deepest sympathy to you on the death of your father.” </p><p>A CONVEYANCE is something that carries or transports, a <i class=“def-ital\">vehicle.</i> </p><p>“No public CONVEYANCES were operating during the snowstorm.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: CONVEYANCE, n.</p>"
            },
            "ANNUL": {
              "word": "ANNUL",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩnuhl')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to cancel, nullify, make void ANNUL comes from the Latin word <i class=“def-ital\">nullus,</i> which means “none.” <i class=“def-ital\">Nullus</i> is also the source of the words <i class=“def-ital\">null</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">nullify.</i> To ANNUL something is to make it cease to ex- ist, to put an end to it. The word is most often used about legal agreements. To ANNUL a marriage is to declare that it is not legally valid. </p><p>“The judge ANNULLED the contract between the two companies.” </p><p>ANNUL is also sometimes used in other areas as well. </p><p>“Nothing could ANNUL the startling effect of her sudden appearance in the room.”</p>"
            },
            "PREMONITION": {
              "word": "PREMONITION",
              "phonetic": "(pre-m:)-ni'-shÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a forewarning, feeling of trouble coming, foreboding </p><p>See <i class=“def-ital\">pre-</i> under Prefixes. A PREMONITION is a feeling that something, usually bad, is going to happen. There is no conscious reason for this feeling; it just seems to occur. </p><p>“She had a PREMONITION of the accident.” </p><p>“Sam didn’t pay attention to his PREMONITION that there was danger ahead.” </p><p>“He keeps having strange PREMONITIONS, but none of them seem to come true.”</p>"
            },
            "FLAUNT": {
              "word": "FLAUNT",
              "phonetic": "(flont)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to show off, display, wave defiantly, attract attention to </p><p>To FLAUNT something is to show it off, to attract attention to it by displaying it or waving it around. </p><p>“He didn’t try to hide his bad habits. He FLAUNTED them in front of everyone.” </p><p>“Knowing they couldn’t catch him, the boy FLAUNTED the stolen wallet at them.” FLAUNT is very often confused with <i class=“def-ital\">flout,</i> a word which sounds almost the same but has a very different meaning. To <i class=“def-ital\">flout</i> something is to treat it with contempt, to scoff at it. </p><p>“He thinks we’re stupid; he’s always <i class=“def-ital\">flouting</i> our advice.” </p><p>To FLAUNT is to show off; to <i class=“def-ital\">flout</i> is to treat with contempt.</p>"
            },
            "SIMULATE": {
              "word": "SIMULATE",
              "phonetic": "(sim'-yU-IAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to pretend, pretend to be, imitate </p><p>SIMULATE is related to the word <i class=“def-ital\">similar.</i> To SIMULATE something is to take on its appearance, to pretend to be or have it. </p><p>“The fake fur SIMULATES the appearance and feel of real mink.” </p><p>“John SIMULATED lameness so that people would think he was injured.” </p><p>“Jane SIMULATED considerable reluctance to take the job, although she really was quite eager.” </p><p>“SIMULATED diamonds are much less valuable than real ones.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: SIMULATION, n.</p>"
            },
            "ENCROACH": {
              "word": "ENCROACH",
              "phonetic": "(en-krOch')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to intrude, trespass, enter or take gradually  </p><p>To ENCROACH on or upon something is to advance farther than you are supposed to into it, to <i class=“def-ital\">trespass</i> on it. The word is used about trespassing on actual physical property, and also on things like rights and time. </p><p>“That new fence you built ENCROACHES on my property.” </p><p>“Your speech is too long. It will ENCROACH on my time to speak.” </p><p>ENCROACH is used especially when this trespassing happens gradually or secretly. </p><p>“Step by step the government started to ENCROACH on their rights.” </p><p>“As the years went by the sea ENCROACHED more and more on the land.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: ENCROACHMENT, n. </p><p>Usage: ENCROACH is usually followed by on or upon.</p>"
            }
          },
          "id": "7",
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "It ENFEEBLED them.",
                  "answers": [
                    "frightened",
                    "weakened",
                    "destroyed",
                    "strengthened",
                    "worried"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENFEEBLE",
                  "correct": "weakened"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROFOUND understanding.",
                  "answers": [
                    "different",
                    "some",
                    "new",
                    "deep",
                    "little"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROFOUND",
                  "correct": "deep"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Rather CRESTFALLEN.",
                  "answers": [
                    "suspicious",
                    "angry",
                    "discouraged",
                    "ugly",
                    "excited"
                  ],
                  "word": "CRESTFALLEN",
                  "correct": "discouraged"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We shall be EXALTED.",
                  "answers": [
                    "let in",
                    "impressed",
                    "thrown out",
                    "worn out",
                    "raised high"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXALT",
                  "correct": "raised high"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His REGAL manner.",
                  "answers": [
                    "vain",
                    "polite",
                    "royal",
                    "usual",
                    "poor"
                  ],
                  "word": "REGAL",
                  "correct": "royal"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Tried to ALLURE me.",
                  "answers": [
                    "capture",
                    "attract",
                    "order",
                    "love",
                    "frighten"
                  ],
                  "word": "ALLURE",
                  "correct": "attract"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AMICABLE relations.",
                  "answers": [
                    "friendly",
                    "changeable",
                    "merry",
                    "perfect",
                    "hostile"
                  ],
                  "word": "AMICABLE",
                  "correct": "friendly"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GUTTURAL voice.",
                  "answers": [
                    "high",
                    "sweet",
                    "loud",
                    "throaty",
                    "frightening"
                  ],
                  "word": "GUTTURAL",
                  "correct": "throaty"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "An act of FOLLY.",
                  "answers": [
                    "common sense",
                    "bravery",
                    "foolishness",
                    "happiness",
                    "love"
                  ],
                  "word": "FOLLY",
                  "correct": "foolishness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Try to CONVEY it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "carry",
                    "lift",
                    "spot",
                    "find",
                    "get"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONVEY",
                  "correct": "carry"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To ANNUL the treaty.",
                  "answers": [
                    "ignore",
                    "accept",
                    "renew",
                    "delay",
                    "cancel"
                  ],
                  "word": "ANNUL",
                  "correct": "cancel"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Ignored his PREMONITION.",
                  "answers": [
                    "decision",
                    "forewarning",
                    "plan",
                    "explanation",
                    "advice"
                  ],
                  "word": "PREMONITION",
                  "correct": "forewarning"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He FLAUNTED the thing.",
                  "answers": [
                    "ignored",
                    "feared",
                    "put away",
                    "showed off",
                    "respected"
                  ],
                  "word": "FLAUNT",
                  "correct": "showed off"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SIMULATED knowledge.",
                  "answers": [
                    "improved",
                    "acquired",
                    "pretended",
                    "useless",
                    "genuine"
                  ],
                  "word": "SIMULATE",
                  "correct": "pretended"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ENCROACH on the land.",
                  "answers": [
                    "hunt",
                    "stay",
                    "work",
                    "live",
                    "trespass"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENCROACH",
                  "correct": "trespass"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Can old age ENFEEBLE a person?",
                  "word": "ENFEEBLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an apprentice have a PROFOUND knowledge of his trade?",
                  "word": "PROFOUND",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most people be CRESTFALLEN if they became rich?",
                  "word": "CRESTFALLEN",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do you EXALT someone by insulting him?",
                  "word": "EXALT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are most people REGAL?",
                  "word": "REGAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would the idea of catching a disease ALLURE many people?",
                  "word": "ALLURE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would people be friendly during an AMICABLE discussion?",
                  "word": "AMICABLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a scream a GUTTURAL sound?",
                  "word": "GUTTURAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it FOLLY to try to pass another car on a curve?",
                  "word": "FOLLY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a boat a CONVEYANCE?",
                  "word": "CONVEY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a child ANNUL a marriage?",
                  "word": "ANNUL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do PREMONITIONS always come true?",
                  "word": "PREMONITION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a vain person FLAUNT his knowledge?",
                  "word": "FLAUNT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can manufacturers make plastics to SIMULATE wood?",
                  "word": "SIMULATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would people approve of someone who ENCROACHED upon their rights?",
                  "word": "ENCROACH",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "His words of encouragement ENFEEBLED her to try again.",
                  "word": "ENFEEBLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He told us about his PROFOUND regret that he had never gone to college.",
                  "word": "PROFOUND",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The CRESTFALLEN players realized they just hadn't been good enough to beat the other team.",
                  "word": "CRESTFALLEN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The emperor was friendly despite his EXALTED position.",
                  "word": "EXALT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The wedding was a REGAL affair that would have pleased any king or queen.",
                  "word": "REGAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The ALLURE of gold has caused many men to become prospectors.",
                  "word": "ALLURE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They both decided they couldn't work together, so they parted AMICABLY.",
                  "word": "AMICABLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She gave a high, GUTTURAL giggle and said she was only kidding.",
                  "word": "GUTTURAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Ed was FOLLY about model railroads. He would play with them all day.",
                  "word": "FOLLY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It is hard to CONVEY to you how important I think this subject is.",
                  "word": "CONVEY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The Supreme Court ANNULLED the agreement, stating that the president didn't have the power to enter into it.",
                  "word": "ANNUL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He had a PREMONITION afterwards that he had done poorly on the test.",
                  "word": "PREMONITION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She got an A in every subject and FLAUNTED her report card in front of her classmates.",
                  "word": "FLAUNT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The students SIMULATED an understanding of what the teacher was saying, but it really wasn't clear to them.",
                  "word": "SIMULATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The thieves ENCROACHED her pocketbook in broad daylight.",
                  "word": "ENCROACH",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "ENFEEBLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "weaken",
                    "drain",
                    "frighten"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENFEEBLE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROFOUND",
                  "answers": [
                    "expensive",
                    "deep",
                    "wise"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROFOUND",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CRESTFALLEN",
                  "answers": [
                    "unhappy",
                    "dismayed",
                    "unhealthy"
                  ],
                  "word": "CRESTFALLEN",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXALT",
                  "answers": [
                    "begin",
                    "glorify",
                    "raise"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXALT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REGAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "imperial",
                    "magnificent",
                    "holy"
                  ],
                  "word": "REGAL",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ALLURE",
                  "answers": [
                    "fascinate",
                    "improve",
                    "enchant"
                  ],
                  "word": "ALLURE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AMICABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "amiable",
                    "pleasant",
                    "restful"
                  ],
                  "word": "AMICABLE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GUTTURAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "sharp",
                    "throaty",
                    "harsh"
                  ],
                  "word": "GUTTURAL",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FOLLY",
                  "answers": [
                    "absurdity",
                    "unkindness",
                    "silliness"
                  ],
                  "word": "FOLLY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONVEY",
                  "answers": [
                    "send",
                    "tell",
                    "delay"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONVEY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ANNUL",
                  "answers": [
                    "nullify",
                    "attack",
                    "abolish"
                  ],
                  "word": "ANNUL",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PREMONITION",
                  "answers": [
                    "regret",
                    "warning",
                    "fear"
                  ],
                  "word": "PREMONITION",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FLAUNT",
                  "answers": [
                    "boast",
                    "show off",
                    "pretend"
                  ],
                  "word": "FLAUNT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SIMULATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "copy",
                    "increase",
                    "imitate"
                  ],
                  "word": "SIMULATE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ENCROACH",
                  "answers": [
                    "enter",
                    "intrude",
                    "refuse"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENCROACH",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "5.8",
          "definitions": {
            "BELLOW": {
              "word": "BELLOW",
              "phonetic": "(bel'-0)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to roar </p><p>To BELLOW is to make a loud, deep sound like a bull. </p><p>“The cattle BELLOWED with fear.” </p><p>“The sergeant BELLOWED out some orders to the men.” </p><p>“The drunken man BELLOWED with laughter at any- thing that happened.” </p><p>BELLOW is also a noun. </p><p>“We heard the BELLOW of the angry bull.” </p><p>Many people select <i class=“def-ital\">groan</i> as the meaning of BELLOW. To <i class=“def-ital\">groan</i> is to make a deep sound which indicates pain or sorrow. A BELLOW is also deep, but it is much louder and is done in other situations besides pain and sorrow.</p>"
            },
            "TAUT": {
              "word": "TAUT",
              "phonetic": "(tot)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">tense, tight, stretched tightly </p><p>TAUT means <i class=“def-ital\">tense</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">tightly stretched.</i> Anything like wire, rope, or chains can be pulled TAUT. </p><p>“Keep that cable TAUT; if the tension falls off, we’ll have an accident.” </p><p>“If the wire is too TAUT it will snap under the strain.” </p><p>TAUT is also used about mental tension. </p><p>“Her nerves were TAUT and strained after the hours of waiting.”</p>"
            },
            "HUBBUB": {
              "word": "HUBBUB",
              "phonetic": "{huhb'-uhb)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">confused noise, uproar, din; turmoil, confusion </p><p>A HUBBUB is a mixture of loud sounds and voices, an <i class=“def-ital\">uproar</i> </p><p>“She couldn’t hear a thing above the HUBBUB of children shouting to one another.” </p><p>“This HUBBUB gives me a headache.” </p><p>Sometimes HUBBUB is used about any kind of confused situation. </p><p>“We lost sight of each other in the HUBBUB of the marketplace.”</p>"
            },
            "PITEOUS": {
              "word": "PITEOUS",
              "phonetic": "(pit'-E-:)s)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">deserving pity, sorrowful, distressing, pathetic </p><p>PITEOUS is an adjective from PITY. It means “deserving or arousing PITY.” See <i class=“def-ital\">-ous</i> under Suffixes. Something is PITEOUS if it is so sad and distressing that it almost breaks your heart. </p><p>“He could not ignore their PITEOUS cries for help.” </p><p>“With a last PITEOUS glance behind him he left his home forever.” </p><p>“The ruins of the once-great mansion were truly a PITEOUS sight.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: PITY, n.</p>"
            },
            "MEEK": {
              "word": "MEEK",
              "phonetic": "(mEk)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">mild, modest, humble, tame </p><p>A MEEK person is mild and uncomplaining. He is not likely to stand up for his rights or get angry at anyone. Usually the word suggests that this mildness is bad, and that the MEEK person lacks spirit or confidence. </p><p>“He was a MEEK little man who jumped whenever anyone called his name.” </p><p>“She MEEKLY begged our pardon for having interrupted us.” </p><p>“A salesman should not be MEEK when talking to customers.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Small</i> is the most common incorrect choice on the Pre- test, probably because MEEK people are often pictured as being <i class=“def-ital\">small</i> and weak.</p>"
            },
            "LABYRINTH": {
              "word": "LABYRINTH",
              "phonetic": "(lab'-:)-rinth)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a maze </p><p>In Greek mythology, the LABYRINTH was a bewilderingly complicated network of passages in which a dreaded beast, the Minotaur, was kept. LABYRINTH has come to be used about any similarly complicated structure through which it is difficult to find your way without help, a <i class=“def-ital\">maze.</i> The word is also used about a situation or a state of affairs which is entangled or hard to get through. </p><p>“It was impossible to make your way through the LABYRINTH of plots and subplots in the novel.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: LABYRINTHINE, adj.</p>"
            },
            "HEARTEN": {
              "word": "HEARTEN",
              "phonetic": "(hahr'-tÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to give heart to, encourage, cheer </p><p>HEARTEN comes from the word <i class=“def-ital\">heart.</i> To HEARTEN is to put <i class=“def-ital\">heart</i> into, to give courage, hope, or enthusiasm to. </p><p>“The soldiers were very depressed, but the general’s speech HEARTENED them considerably.” </p><p>“The teacher was HEARTENED by her students’ love for learning.” </p><p>“They were three runs behind, but they were HEARTENED by the thought that their best hitters were coming up.” </p><p>Many people think HEARTEN means <i class=“def-ital\">sadden,</i> which is an opposite. These people may confuse HEARTEN with DISHEARTEN, which means to <i class=“def-ital\">discourage.</i></p>"
            },
            "ACCLAIM": {
              "word": "ACCLAIM",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩklAm')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to praise, applaud; to announce, proclaim </p><p>ACCLAIM comes from a Latin word meaning to <i class=“def-ital\">shout</i>, also the source of the word <i class=“def-ital\">clamor.</i> To ACCLAIM some- thing is to praise it, especially publicly and enthusiastically. </p><p>“The crowd ACCLAIMED the heroes returning from the war.” </p><p>“The critics ACCLAIMED the new movie as one of the greatest ever made.” </p><p>In a different sense, ACCLAIM can mean “to declare publicly and approvingly.” </p><p>“The noblemen ACCLAIMED him their new king.” </p><p>ACCLAIM is also a noun, meaning <i class=“def-ital\">great praise.</i> </p><p>“The play received great ACCLAIM at its first perfor- mance.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: ACCLAMATION, n.</p>"
            },
            "TOIL": {
              "word": "TOIL",
              "phonetic": "(toyl)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">labor, hard work </p><p>TOIL is hard work, labor which wearies or exhausts a person. </p><p>“It took years of TOIL to produce his masterpiece.” </p><p>“She always said that TOIL and trouble build one’s character.” </p><p>TOIL is also used as a verb meaning to <i class=“def-ital\">work hard.</i> </p><p>“The farmer was TOILING in the field under the hot sun.” </p><p>“He TOILED at rebuilding the house.” </p><p>Many people choose <i class=“def-ital\">confusion</i> as the meaning of TOIL, perhaps because TOIL looks like <i class=“def-ital\">turmoil,</i> which means <i class=“def-ital\">disorder, confusion.</i></p>"
            },
            "REVERT": {
              "word": "REVERT",
              "phonetic": "(ri-vert')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to return, turn back </p><p>See <i class=“def-ital\">re-</i> under Prefixes. The <i class=“def-ital\">vert</i> part of the word means <i class=“def-ital\">turn</i> and is found in other words like <i class=“def-ital\">convert</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">avert.</i> To REVERT is to turn back or return to an original con- dition, topic, idea, or the like. </p><p>“After four years of being good he REVERTED to his former evil ways.” </p><p>“I hate to keep REVERTING to my original question, but no one has given me a satisfactory answer yet.” </p><p>In law, REVERT is used about property or rights which return to someone under certain conditions. </p><p>“Upon his death, all his property will REVERT to the state.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: REVERSION, n.</p>"
            },
            "OBLITERATE": {
              "word": "OBLITERATE",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩ-blit'-ÔøΩ-rAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to erase, wipe out, destroy </p><p>To OBLITERATE something is to cover it up or wipe it out completely, so that nothing remains or can be seen. </p><p>“The dark clouds completely OBLITERATED the sun.” </p><p>“The incoming waves OBLITERATED all traces of the drawing he had made in the sand.” </p><p>OBLITERATE is a very strong word. It can mean to <i class=“def-ital\">destroy utterly.</i> </p><p>“The enemy’s bombs OBLITERATED the town.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Break</i> is the most common mistake as the meaning of OBLITERATE. <i class=“def-ital\">Break</i> is a much weaker word than OBLITERATE, though. You can <i class=“def-ital\">break</i> something without OBLITERATING it. </p><p>Other forms of the word: OBLITERATION, n.</p>"
            },
            "ARMAMENT": {
              "word": "ARMAMENT",
              "phonetic": "(ahr'-mÔøΩmgnt)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">weapons, military equipment </p><p>ARMAMENT means <i class=“def-ital\">weapons,</i> especially those used in warfare. It is related to the word <i class=“def-ital\">arms,</i> which can also mean weapons. </p><p>“The warships were provided with all the latest AR- MAMENT.” </p><p>It is often used in the plural for the total military strength of a country. </p><p>“We must have better ARMAMENTS if this nation is to be strong.”</p>"
            },
            "LITERAL": {
              "word": "LITERAL",
              "phonetic": "(lit'-gr-gl)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">exact, true to fact </p><p>LITERAL comes from the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">letter,</i> also the source of the word <i class=“def-ital\">literature.</i> LITERAL means “following the words or the meaning of the original exactly.” A LITERAL translation is an exact translation, one which says precisely what the original writer said in another language. The “LITERAL sense of a word” is its exact original meaning. </p><p>“He was thrown out of the game in the LITERAL sense of the words; two players picked him up and tossed him off the field.” </p><p>The adverb LITERALLY is often used to mean <i class=“def-ital\">actually, truly, without exaggeration.</i> </p><p>“He LITERALLY fell flat on his face the first time he tried to rollerskate.”</p>"
            },
            "SIMPLETON": {
              "word": "SIMPLETON",
              "phonetic": "(sim'-pgl-tgn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a fool, idiot </p><p>A SIMPLETON is a person who is or acts simple-minded. He is silly and easily fooled and sometimes lacks the ability to get along in the world. </p><p>“He was such a SIMPLETON that we didn’t want to take advantage of him.” </p><p>“We felt like SIMPLETONS after he showed how he had fooled us.”</p>"
            },
            "TARRY": {
              "word": "TARRY",
              "phonetic": "(ta'-rE)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to delay, lag, be slow; to remain, stay </p><p>TARRY has two meanings. The first meaning of TARRY is to <i class=“def-ital\">delay</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">hang back,</i> to <i class=“def-ital\">be slow</i> in coming or going, to <i class=“def-ital\">dawdle.</i> </p><p>“He TARRIES so long getting dressed that he’s always late for school.” </p><p>“Her mother called up to her, ‘Don’t TARRY any longer; we’re leaving immediately.’ </p><p>” The other meaning of TARRY is to <i class=“def-ital\">stay</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">remain.</i> </p><p>“We TARRIED at the seashore for a few more days.” </p><p>“Please TARRY awhile; we enjoy hearing about your travels.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Rush</i> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest, perhaps because TARRY sounds like <i class=“def-ital\">hurry.</i></p>"
            }
          },
          "id": "8",
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Heard them BELLOW.",
                  "answers": [
                    "groan",
                    "squeal",
                    "roar",
                    "growl",
                    "whisper"
                  ],
                  "word": "BELLOW",
                  "correct": "roar"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Kept it TAUT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "small",
                    "narrow",
                    "loose",
                    "light",
                    "tense"
                  ],
                  "word": "TAUT",
                  "correct": "tense"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Started the HUBBUB.",
                  "answers": [
                    "explosion",
                    "awful book",
                    "confused noise",
                    "music",
                    "headache"
                  ],
                  "word": "HUBBUB",
                  "correct": "confused noise"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PITEOUS sounds.",
                  "answers": [
                    "sorrowful",
                    "lonely",
                    "harsh",
                    "bothersome",
                    "awful"
                  ],
                  "word": "PITEOUS",
                  "correct": "sorrowful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "A MEEK person.",
                  "answers": [
                    "happy",
                    "mild",
                    "small",
                    "tired",
                    "proud"
                  ],
                  "word": "MEEK",
                  "correct": "mild"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She entered the LABYRINTH.",
                  "answers": [
                    "castle",
                    "pit",
                    "Greek city",
                    "maze",
                    "lane"
                  ],
                  "word": "LABYRINTH",
                  "correct": "maze"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HEARTENED by the news.",
                  "answers": [
                    "bored",
                    "improved",
                    "encouraged",
                    "saddened",
                    "upset"
                  ],
                  "word": "HEARTEN",
                  "correct": "encouraged"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They ACCLAIMED it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "praised",
                    "needed",
                    "hated",
                    "accepted",
                    "desired"
                  ],
                  "word": "ACCLAIM",
                  "correct": "praised"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Constant TOIL.",
                  "answers": [
                    "pleasure",
                    "sorrow",
                    "heat",
                    "confusion",
                    "labor"
                  ],
                  "word": "TOIL",
                  "correct": "labor"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REVERT to savagery.",
                  "answers": [
                    "refer",
                    "lean",
                    "return",
                    "admit",
                    "change"
                  ],
                  "word": "REVERT",
                  "correct": "return"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Wanted to OBLITERATE it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "shorten",
                    "polish",
                    "write",
                    "erase",
                    "break"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBLITERATE",
                  "correct": "erase"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Effective ARMAMENT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "charms",
                    "laws",
                    "methods",
                    "threats",
                    "weapons"
                  ],
                  "word": "ARMAMENT",
                  "correct": "weapons"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LITERAL translations.",
                  "answers": [
                    "exact",
                    "excellent",
                    "learned",
                    "difficult",
                    "loose"
                  ],
                  "word": "LITERAL",
                  "correct": "exact"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They were SIMPLETONS.",
                  "answers": [
                    "farmers",
                    "comedians",
                    "fools",
                    "saints",
                    "bachelors"
                  ],
                  "word": "SIMPLETON",
                  "correct": "fools"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They always TARRY.",
                  "answers": [
                    "forget",
                    "delay",
                    "wonder",
                    "rush",
                    "limp"
                  ],
                  "word": "TARRY",
                  "correct": "delay"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Do mice BELLOW?",
                  "word": "BELLOW",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a person whose nerves are TAUT be calm?",
                  "word": "TAUT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it difficult to hear someone in a HUBBUB?",
                  "word": "HUBBUB",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can PITEOUS sights make a person cry?",
                  "word": "PITEOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Should a boxer be MEEK when he's fighting?",
                  "word": "MEEK",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it easy to go through a LABYRINTH?",
                  "word": "LABYRINTH",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would discouraging news HEARTEN you?",
                  "word": "HEARTEN",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "If people ACCLAIM something do they like it?",
                  "word": "ACCLAIM",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does TOIL often tire people out?",
                  "word": "TOIL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do butterflies REVERT to being caterpillars?",
                  "word": "REVERT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could an earthquake OBLITERATE a city?",
                  "word": "OBLITERATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are a soldier's medals a part of his ARMAMENT?",
                  "word": "ARMAMENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "If a woman is very beautiful, is she LITERALLY a goddess?",
                  "word": "LITERAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are SIMPLETONS bright?",
                  "word": "SIMPLETON",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do people TARRY when they have to get somewhere quickly?",
                  "word": "TARRY",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "They could hear animals BELLOWING in the jungle.",
                  "word": "BELLOW",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The dog pulled his chain so TAUT that he started to choke.",
                  "word": "TAUT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She went on her vacation to a quiet HUBBUB in the woods.",
                  "word": "HUBBUB",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The children cried PITEOUSLY as the soldiers took their father away.",
                  "word": "PITEOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Don't be so MEEK. If you think you're right, say so.",
                  "word": "MEEK",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The palace was a LABYRINTH of secret passages and hidden staircases.",
                  "word": "LABYRINTH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "I was HEARTENED by your kind words.",
                  "word": "HEARTEN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The man ACCLAIMED the money was his because he had found it.",
                  "word": "ACCLAIM",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They TOILED for many years to build the church.",
                  "word": "TOIL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Bob narrowly REVERTED being injured when the stairs collapsed.",
                  "word": "REVERT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The falling snow quickly OBLITERATED all traces of the horse's tracks.",
                  "word": "OBLITERATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The government spends a great deal of the tax money it collects for ARMAMENTS.",
                  "word": "ARMAMENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He prepared a LITERAL translation of the play, so that people would know exactly how it went in the original Spanish.",
                  "word": "LITERAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He stood there like a SIMPLETON, with a stupid grin on his face.",
                  "word": "SIMPLETON",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Joan TARRIED to the store to get there before it closed.",
                  "word": "TARRY",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "BELLOW",
                  "answers": [
                    "shout",
                    "sigh",
                    "howl"
                  ],
                  "word": "BELLOW",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TAUT",
                  "answers": [
                    "pulling",
                    "stretching",
                    "struggling"
                  ],
                  "word": "TAUT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HUBBUB",
                  "answers": [
                    "size",
                    "confusion",
                    "uproar"
                  ],
                  "word": "HUBBUB",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PITEOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "sad",
                    "pathetic",
                    "weird"
                  ],
                  "word": "PITEOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MEEK",
                  "answers": [
                    "humble",
                    "sad",
                    "shy"
                  ],
                  "word": "MEEK",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LABYRINTH",
                  "answers": [
                    "monster",
                    "maze",
                    "tangle"
                  ],
                  "word": "LABYRINTH",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HEARTEN",
                  "answers": [
                    "frighten",
                    "encourage",
                    "comfort"
                  ],
                  "word": "HEARTEN",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ACCLAIM",
                  "answers": [
                    "shout",
                    "expect",
                    "applaud"
                  ],
                  "word": "ACCLAIM",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TOIL",
                  "answers": [
                    "cheapen",
                    "slave",
                    "labor"
                  ],
                  "word": "TOIL",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REVERT",
                  "answers": [
                    "stay",
                    "relapse",
                    "go back"
                  ],
                  "word": "REVERT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OBLITERATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "cover",
                    "destroy",
                    "change"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBLITERATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ARMAMENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "supplies",
                    "threats",
                    "weapons"
                  ],
                  "word": "ARMAMENT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LITERAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "true",
                    "precise",
                    "general"
                  ],
                  "word": "LITERAL",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SIMPLETON",
                  "answers": [
                    "moron",
                    "bully",
                    "idiot"
                  ],
                  "word": "SIMPLETON",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TARRY",
                  "answers": [
                    "wait",
                    "drive",
                    "stay"
                  ],
                  "word": "TARRY",
                  "correct": "1"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "5.9",
          "definitions": {
            "DEROGATORY": {
              "word": "DEROGATORY",
              "phonetic": "(di-rog'-ÔøΩtor-E)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">degrading, detracting, disparaging </p><p>Something that is DEROGATORY tends to take away from the value or reputation of someone or something. The word is usually used about expressions or remarks. </p><p>“The other children made DEROGATORY comments about the odd way he walked.” </p><p>“Many police officers think that the word ’cop’ is DEROGATORY, and they get angry whenever they hear it.” </p><p>“You shouldn’t make DEROGATORY statements about other people’s beliefs.”</p>"
            },
            "RECOUP": {
              "word": "RECOUP",
              "phonetic": "(ri-kUp')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to recover, regain, get back, make up for </p><p>To RECOUP means to <i class=“def-ital\">get back</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">make good on</i> something that has been lost. See <i class=“def-ital\">re-</i> under Prefixes. Often the word suggests getting back not the same thing that has been lost but its equivalent. </p><p>“By shrewd investing he managed to RECOUP the fortune he had lost.” </p><p>“The family never RECOUPED the losses they suffered in the fire.”</p>"
            },
            "INGENUITY": {
              "word": "INGENUITY",
              "phonetic": "(in-jÔøΩ-nyU'-ÔøΩtE",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">cleverness, skillfulness, originality </p><p>INGENUITY is cleverness in coming up with ideas or inventions. It is related to the words <i class=“def-ital\">genius</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">ingenious.</i> </p><p>“He was a man of great INGENUITY. He could figure his way out of any difficulty.” </p><p>“Thanks to her INGENUITY we found a way to buy a new car and save money at the same time.” </p><p>INGENUITY is also used about the idea or invention it- self. </p><p>“The INGENUITY of the device astounded every- one.” </p><p>“Despite the INGENUITY of his theory, we tend to think he is wrong.” </p><p>On the Pretest, many people select <i class=“def-ital\">knowledge</i> as the synonym of INGENUITY. You can know a great deal, how- ever, and lack the INGENUITY to make use of your <i class=“def-ital\">knowledge.</i></p>"
            },
            "SHEEN": {
              "word": "SHEEN",
              "phonetic": "(shEn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">brightness, shine, gloss, luster </p><p>SHEEN is gleaming brightness or luster, like that of well- polished wood. </p><p>“The SHEEN of the bird’s wings glistened in the sun.” </p><p>“Her silk dress had a beautiful SHEEN to it.”</p>"
            },
            "INCOGNITO": {
              "word": "INCOGNITO",
              "phonetic": "(in-kog-nE'-tO)",
              "pos": "adj.,adv.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">disguised, with one’s identity concealed </p><p>INCOGNITO comes originally from a Latin word meaning <i class=“def-ital\">unknown.</i> Someone who is INCOGNITO wants to keep his or her true identity unknown. The word is often used about famous people who travel under an assumed name or in disguise so that they won’t be bothered. </p><p>“The movie star came to the theater INCOGNITO, but his fans recognized him anyway.” </p><p>“The prince went INCOGNITO among the soldiers, trying to discover how they felt about the coming bat- tle.”</p>"
            },
            "STIFLE": {
              "word": "STIFLE",
              "phonetic": "(stl'-fal)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to suffocate, smother; to suppress, keep back </p><p>To STIFLE someone is to kill him by not letting him breathe, to <i class=“def-ital\">suffocate</i> him. </p><p>“The murderer STIFLED his victim with a pillow.” </p><p>STIFLE is also used in a general sense, meaning to <i class=“def-ital\">cut off</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">hold back.</i> </p><p>“She managed to STIFLE a sneeze.” </p><p>“They accused the king of trying to STIFLE all politi- cal parties.” </p><p>“Bill thought his job was STIFLING him; he longed for more excitement and challenge.”</p>"
            },
            "PLUMAGE": {
              "word": "PLUMAGE",
              "phonetic": "(plU'-mij)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">feathers </p><p>A PLUME is a single feather. </p><p>“She stuck a PLUME in her hat.” The suffix <i class=“def-ital\">-age</i> can mean a <i class=“def-ital\">group</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">collection.</i> For example, baggage is a group of bags or suitcases. PLUMAGE, therefore, is a group of feathers. It is the feathers of a bird, taken all together. </p><p>“The peacock has very colorful PLUMAGE.”</p>"
            },
            "PANORAMA": {
              "word": "PANORAMA",
              "phonetic": "(pan-ÔøΩram'-ÔøΩ)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a wide view, a continually changing scene </p><p>PANORAMA was originally the name of a kind of picture that was shown a part at a time by being unrolled in front of the viewer. In this way it could give a complete view of a landscape or a scene. PANORAMA has come to be used about any wide or constantly changing view. </p><p>“From the top of the building you can see a PANORAMA of the city.” </p><p>“His book looks over the PANORAMA of recent American history.” </p><p>“The movie is a real PANORAMA of modern life.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: PANORAMIC, adj.</p>"
            },
            "FLOUNDER": {
              "word": "FLOUNDER",
              "phonetic": "(flown'-dÔøΩr)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to move clumsily, muddle, wallow </p><p>To FLOUNDER is to move clumsily, particularly to fling your arms and legs this way and that in trying to regain your balance or to escape from something. </p><p>“The poor swimmers FLOUNDERED in the deep water, trying to stay afloat.” </p><p>“They FLOUNDERED through the snowdrifts, falling down often.” </p><p>FLOUNDER can also be used in a broader sense. </p><p>“He FLOUNDERED through the speech, constantly forgetting what he was supposed to say next.” </p><p>“She FLOUNDERED about in the kitchen, wishing she knew something about cooking.”</p>"
            },
            "NEGATE": {
              "word": "NEGATE",
              "phonetic": "(nÔøΩgAt')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to rule out, nullify, neutralize </p><p>NEGATE is related to the word <i class=“def-ital\">negative.</i> Both come from a Latin word meaning to <i class=“def-ital\">say no.</i> To NEGATE something is to cause it to have no effect or value. Often the word suggests two things canceling each other out be- cause of their opposite effects. </p><p>“His grand slam homer NEGATED the four runs the other team had scored in the previous inning.” </p><p>“The principal’s opposition NEGATES the possibility of a school outing.” </p><p>“All our work was NEGATED when money ran out and the project ended.” </p><p>“He found it difficult to NEGATE the bad impression he had already made on people.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: NEGATION, n.</p>"
            },
            "PALTRY": {
              "word": "PALTRY",
              "phonetic": "(pol'-trE)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">petty, insignificant, worthless, trivial </p><p>Something that is PALTRY is of very little importance or value. PALTRY is a strong word, and would be used of people or things that are hardly worth noticing. </p><p>“Ten cents is a PALTRY sum of money to have such an argument about.” </p><p>“I wouldn’t bother punishing him for such a PALTRY offense.” </p><p>“Paul’s always late, and he always has some PALTRY excuse.”</p>"
            },
            "INCOHERENT": {
              "word": "INCOHERENT",
              "phonetic": "(in-kO-hEr'-ÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">disorganized, disjointed, unintelligible </p><p>The <i class=“def-ital\">her</i> part of INCOHERENT means to stick; this root is also found in the word <i class=“def-ital\">adhere.</i> Something that is COHERENT sticks together. See <i class=“def-ital\">co-</i> under Prefixes. The word is usually used about people or arguments that make sense, that are logical and organized. </p><p>“He gave a COHERENT summary of everything that happened that day.” </p><p>Someone or something that is INCOHERENT is disorganized, illogical, lacks order or sense. See <i class=“def-ital\">in-2</i> under Prefixes. </p><p>“His explanation of how the complicated machine works was totally INCOHERENT; no one could understand him.” </p><p>“She was so angry she became INCOHERENT and just started shouting and banging the table.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: INCOHERENCE, n.</p>"
            },
            "VERBATIM": {
              "word": "VERBATIM",
              "phonetic": "(ver-bA'-tim)",
              "pos": "adv.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">word for word </p><p>VERBATIM comes from the Latin word that means <i class=“def-ital\">word,</i> also the source of English words like <i class=“def-ital\">verb</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">verbal.</i> VERBATIM means “in exactly the same words.” </p><p>“She has an amazing memory. She can recite an entire poem VERBATIM after looking at it only once.” </p><p>“The secretary took down the entire speech VERBA- TIM and typed it out later.” </p><p>VERBATIM is also used as an adjective. </p><p>“He gave a VERBATIM report of what the general had said.”</p>"
            },
            "TREAD": {
              "word": "TREAD",
              "phonetic": "(tred)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to walk, step; to stamp, crush </p><p>To TREAD is to <i class=“def-ital\">walk</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">step.</i> </p><p>“A slogan during the American Revolution was ‘Don’t TREAD on me.’ ” </p><p>“They TROD through the thick carpet of leaves on the lawn.” </p><p>“Don’t TREAD on that ice. It’s very thin.” </p><p>TREAD often suggests pressure and weight, and gives the idea of crushing or beating down. </p><p>“The thoughtless children TROD all over the beautiful flowers.” </p><p>Usage: TREAD is often followed by on. The past tense of TREAD is TROD.</p>"
            },
            "INSOLENT": {
              "word": "INSOLENT",
              "phonetic": "(in'-sa-lÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">rude, offensive, disrespectful, insulting </p><p>Someone who is INSOLENT lacks proper respect for people. An INSOLENT person is rude and insulting, especially to a person who is in a higher position. </p><p>“The INSOLENT private refused to salute the general.” </p><p>“Some INSOLENT students laughed during the principal’s speech.” </p><p>INSOLENT is also used about the way such a person acts, or what he says. </p><p>“When asked why he was late, he gave an INSOLENT reply.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: INSOLENCE, n.</p>"
            }
          },
          "id": "9",
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "DEROGATORY remarks.",
                  "answers": [
                    "unpopular",
                    "stupid",
                    "degrading",
                    "questioning",
                    "approving"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEROGATORY",
                  "correct": "degrading"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We must RECOUP our investment.",
                  "answers": [
                    "improve",
                    "recover",
                    "stop",
                    "forget",
                    "remember"
                  ],
                  "word": "RECOUP",
                  "correct": "recover"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Her INGENUITY.",
                  "answers": [
                    "stupidity",
                    "knowledge",
                    "confidence",
                    "innocence",
                    "cleverness"
                  ],
                  "word": "INGENUITY",
                  "correct": "cleverness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Lasting SHEEN.",
                  "answers": [
                    "brightness",
                    "anger",
                    "dampness",
                    "value",
                    "roughness"
                  ],
                  "word": "SHEEN",
                  "correct": "brightness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He traveled INCOGNITO.",
                  "answers": [
                    "deep in thought openly",
                    "foolishly",
                    "unexpectedly",
                    "disguised",
                    null
                  ],
                  "word": "INCOGNITO",
                  "correct": "disguised"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To STIFLE him.",
                  "answers": [
                    "toy with",
                    "change",
                    "suffocate",
                    "fight",
                    "treat"
                  ],
                  "word": "STIFLE",
                  "correct": "suffocate"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Looked at its PLUMAGE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "feathers",
                    "leaves",
                    "nest",
                    "tail",
                    "fruit"
                  ],
                  "word": "PLUMAGE",
                  "correct": "feathers"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Admired the PANORAMA.",
                  "answers": [
                    "small picture",
                    "movie",
                    "great outdoors",
                    "wide view",
                    "universe"
                  ],
                  "word": "PANORAMA",
                  "correct": "wide view"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Started to FLOUNDER.",
                  "answers": [
                    "swim",
                    "move clumsily",
                    "hurt",
                    "give up",
                    "do well"
                  ],
                  "word": "FLOUNDER",
                  "correct": "move clumsily"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NEGATE the possibility.",
                  "answers": [
                    "rule out",
                    "delay",
                    "change",
                    "bring up",
                    "lessen"
                  ],
                  "word": "NEGATE",
                  "correct": "rule out"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PALTRY amounts.",
                  "answers": [
                    "forgotten",
                    "secret",
                    "necessary",
                    "petty",
                    "huge"
                  ],
                  "word": "PALTRY",
                  "correct": "petty"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The report was INCOHERENT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "unnecessary",
                    "untrue",
                    "too long",
                    "disorganized",
                    "clear"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCOHERENT",
                  "correct": "disorganized"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Gave the message VERBATIM.",
                  "answers": [
                    "differently",
                    "word for word",
                    "out loud",
                    "after a while",
                    "immediately"
                  ],
                  "word": "VERBATIM",
                  "correct": "word for word"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Where did she TREAD?",
                  "answers": [
                    "walk",
                    "work",
                    "sew",
                    "stay",
                    "drive"
                  ],
                  "word": "TREAD",
                  "correct": "walk"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INSOLENT children.",
                  "answers": [
                    "stupid",
                    "angry",
                    "rude",
                    "polite",
                    "poor"
                  ],
                  "word": "INSOLENT",
                  "correct": "rude"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Do people usually dislike hearing DEROGATORY remarks about themselves?",
                  "word": "DEROGATORY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it possible to RECOUP your health after an illness?",
                  "word": "RECOUP",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does it require INGENUITY to add two and two?",
                  "word": "INGENUITY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does polishing metal give it a SHEEN?",
                  "word": "SHEEN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a movie star who wanted to avoid photographers travel INCOGNITO?",
                  "word": "INCOGNITO",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do loudspeakers STIFLE the sound of a record?",
                  "word": "STIFLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do cows have PLUMAGE?",
                  "word": "PLUMAGE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a book about the Civil War present a PANORAMA of American history?",
                  "word": "PANORAMA",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "If you know very little French, will you FLOUNDER when you try to speak it?",
                  "word": "FLOUNDER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a small tax increase NEGATE a large pay raise?",
                  "word": "NEGATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a million dollars a PALTRY sum of money?",
                  "word": "PALTRY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are INCOHERENT speeches easy to listen to?",
                  "word": "INCOHERENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a VERBATIM report be very accurate?",
                  "word": "VERBATIM",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you TREAD on air?",
                  "word": "TREAD",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do adults usually disapprove of INSOLENT children?",
                  "word": "INSOLENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "These courses are DEROGATORY; everyone must take them.",
                  "word": "DEROGATORY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The gambler tried to RECOUP his losses by betting more heavily.",
                  "word": "RECOUP",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We were amazed by the INGENUITY of his new invention.",
                  "word": "INGENUITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The polished oak table had a golden SHEEN.",
                  "word": "SHEEN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We were told to travel to the meeting INCOGNITO, so we wore disguises and we didn't use our real names.",
                  "word": "INCOGNITO",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The coach STIFLED them to try even harder during the second half.",
                  "word": "STIFLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We admired the bird's fancy PLUMAGE.",
                  "word": "PLUMAGE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They drove to the city in the PANORAMA.",
                  "word": "PANORAMA",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The company was FLOUNDERED in 1922.",
                  "word": "FLOUNDER",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "That one destructive storm completely NEGATED our months of work on the barn.",
                  "word": "NEGATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "I can't be bothered with such PALTRY tasks; give me something important to do.",
                  "word": "PALTRY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The man was so frightened that he trembled and his speech was INCOHERENT.",
                  "word": "INCOHERENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She repeated the boss's orders VERBATIM.",
                  "word": "VERBATIM",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The workers TROD through the kitchen in their muddy boots.",
                  "word": "TREAD",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The young man was so INSOLENT we told him to leave the room.",
                  "word": "INSOLENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "DEROGATORY",
                  "answers": [
                    "insulting",
                    "terrifying",
                    "mocking"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEROGATORY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RECOUP",
                  "answers": [
                    "regain",
                    "repay",
                    "recover"
                  ],
                  "word": "RECOUP",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INGENUITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "skill",
                    "originality",
                    "oddness"
                  ],
                  "word": "INGENUITY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SHEEN",
                  "answers": [
                    "gleam",
                    "blush",
                    "polish"
                  ],
                  "word": "SHEEN",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INCOGNITO",
                  "answers": [
                    "anonymous",
                    "masked",
                    "titled"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCOGNITO",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "STIFLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "stop",
                    "hold back",
                    "deny"
                  ],
                  "word": "STIFLE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PLUMAGE",
                  "answers": [
                    "covering",
                    "feathers",
                    "beaks"
                  ],
                  "word": "PLUMAGE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PANORAMA",
                  "answers": [
                    "scene",
                    "picture",
                    "sign"
                  ],
                  "word": "PANORAMA",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FLOUNDER",
                  "answers": [
                    "struggle",
                    "wallow",
                    "bend"
                  ],
                  "word": "FLOUNDER",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NEGATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "offset",
                    "loosen",
                    "deny"
                  ],
                  "word": "NEGATE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PALTRY",
                  "answers": [
                    "small",
                    "safe",
                    "trivial"
                  ],
                  "word": "PALTRY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INCOHERENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "messy",
                    "untrue",
                    "unclear"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCOHERENT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VERBATIM",
                  "answers": [
                    "exact",
                    "accurate",
                    "constant"
                  ],
                  "word": "VERBATIM",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TREAD",
                  "answers": [
                    "dive",
                    "step",
                    "trample"
                  ],
                  "word": "TREAD",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INSOLENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "insulting",
                    "discourteous",
                    "downcast"
                  ],
                  "word": "INSOLENT",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        }
      ],
      "reviewTest": {
        "wordList": [
          {
            "word": "ALLURE",
            "answer": "allured"
          },
          {
            "word": "CRESTFALLEN",
            "answer": "crestfallen"
          },
          {
            "word": "INGENUITY",
            "answer": "ingenuity"
          },
          {
            "word": "MEEK",
            "answer": "meek"
          },
          {
            "word": "SIMULATE",
            "answer": "simulated"
          },
          {
            "word": "AMICABLE",
            "answer": "amicable"
          },
          {
            "word": "FLAUNT",
            "answer": "flaunt"
          },
          {
            "word": "INSOLENT",
            "answer": "insolent"
          },
          {
            "word": "NEGATE",
            "answer": "negated"
          },
          {
            "word": "STIFLE",
            "answer": "stifle"
          },
          {
            "word": "ARMAMENT",
            "answer": "armaments"
          },
          {
            "word": "FLOUNDER",
            "answer": "floundered"
          },
          {
            "word": "LABYRINTH",
            "answer": "labyrinth"
          },
          {
            "word": "PLUMAGE",
            "answer": "plumage"
          },
          {
            "word": "TARRY",
            "answer": "tarry"
          },
          {
            "word": "BELLOW",
            "answer": "bellowed"
          },
          {
            "word": "GUTTURAL",
            "answer": "guttural"
          },
          {
            "word": "LITERAL",
            "answer": "literally"
          },
          {
            "word": "REVERT",
            "answer": "reverted"
          },
          {
            "word": "TOIL",
            "answer": "toil"
          },
          {
            "word": "CONVEY",
            "answer": "convey"
          },
          {
            "word": "ACCLAIM",
            "answer": "acclaimed"
          },
          {
            "word": "EXALT",
            "answer": "exalted"
          },
          {
            "word": "INCOHERENT",
            "answer": "incoherent"
          },
          {
            "word": "PREMONITION",
            "answer": "premonition"
          },
          {
            "word": "SIMPLETON",
            "answer": "simpleton"
          },
          {
            "word": "ANNUL",
            "answer": "annul"
          },
          {
            "word": "FOLLY",
            "answer": "folly"
          },
          {
            "word": "OBLITERATE",
            "answer": "obliterated"
          },
          {
            "word": "PROFOUND",
            "answer": "profound"
          },
          {
            "word": "TAUT",
            "answer": "taut"
          },
          {
            "word": "DEROGATORY",
            "answer": "derogatory"
          },
          {
            "word": "HEARTEN",
            "answer": "heartened"
          },
          {
            "word": "PALTRY",
            "answer": "paltry"
          },
          {
            "word": "RECOUP",
            "answer": "recoup"
          },
          {
            "word": "TREAD",
            "answer": "tread"
          },
          {
            "word": "ENCROACH",
            "answer": "encroached"
          },
          {
            "word": "HUBBUB",
            "answer": "hubbub"
          },
          {
            "word": "PANORAMA",
            "answer": "panorama"
          },
          {
            "word": "REGAL",
            "answer": "regal"
          },
          {
            "word": "VERBATIM",
            "answer": "verbatim"
          },
          {
            "word": "ENFEEBLE",
            "answer": "enfeebled"
          },
          {
            "word": "INCOGNITO",
            "answer": "incoherent"
          },
          {
            "word": "PITEOUS",
            "answer": "piteous"
          },
          {
            "word": "SHEEN",
            "answer": "sheen"
          }
        ],
        "questions": [
          {
            "part1": "We got completely lost in the",
            "part2": "of trails and paths in the park.",
            "correct": "labyrinth",
            "word": "LABYRINTH"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The bird's",
            "part2": "was so beautiful that we wished we had a feather or two.",
            "correct": "plumage",
            "word": "PLUMAGE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We all know you're smart; there's no need to",
            "part2": "it.",
            "correct": "flaunt",
            "word": "FLAUNT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "After a life of nothing but",
            "part2": "he enjoyed the chance to relax and take things easy.",
            "correct": "toil",
            "word": "TOIL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Ann was so excited she",
            "part2": "jumped for joy.",
            "correct": "literally",
            "word": "LITERAL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Joe had a(n)",
            "part2": "relationship with his classmates; they all liked and respected each other.",
            "correct": "amicable",
            "word": "AMICABLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The injury to their star player",
            "part2": "any possibility that they could win the game Saturday.",
            "correct": "negated",
            "word": "NEGATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Due to his",
            "part2": "the criminal was able to avoid being caught for many years.",
            "correct": "ingenuity",
            "word": "INGENUITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We used trucks to",
            "part2": "the equipment from the old building to the new one.",
            "correct": "convey",
            "word": "CONVEY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "As the boring lecture dragged on and on, it became more difficult for the students to",
            "part2": "their yawns.",
            "correct": "stifle",
            "word": "STIFLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We cannot",
            "part2": "for lengthy goodbyes; our plane is leaving in ten minutes.",
            "correct": "tarry",
            "word": "TARRY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The cattle",
            "part2": "with fear during the thunderstorm.",
            "correct": "bellowed",
            "word": "BELLOW"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He",
            "part2": "great admiration for the child's painting, although he really thought it was very poor.",
            "correct": "simulated",
            "word": "SIMULATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Linda is so",
            "part2": "she apologizes for everything she does.",
            "correct": "meek",
            "word": "MEEK"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The explorer",
            "part2": "in the quicksand as he struggled to avoid drowning in it.",
            "correct": "floundered",
            "word": "FLOUNDER"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Janet was polite for several weeks, but then she",
            "part2": "to her usual rude manner.",
            "correct": "reverted",
            "word": "REVERT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The beauty of the tropic islands",
            "part2": "many people.",
            "correct": "allured",
            "word": "ALLURE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He made a low,",
            "part2": "sound deep in his throat when he was in pain.",
            "correct": "guttural",
            "word": "GUTTURAL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Pat was so excited when she heard she could come with us; she will be",
            "part2": "when we tell her there isn't enough room.",
            "correct": "crestfallen",
            "word": "CRESTFALLEN"
          },
          {
            "part1": "If we are to win this war, we must destroy the enemy's weapon factories and the other sources of its",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "armaments",
            "word": "ARMAMENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The worker made some",
            "part2": "remarks to his boss and was fired on the spot.",
            "correct": "insolent",
            "word": "INSOLENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The actress didn't want anyone to know she was on the plane, so she used a false name and traveled",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "incognito",
            "word": "INCOGNITO"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The rope snapped and broke because it was stretched so",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "taut",
            "word": "TAUT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The disease so",
            "part2": "him that for months he didn't have the strength to sit up.",
            "correct": "enfeebled",
            "word": "ENFEEBLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We were discouraged at first, but then we were",
            "part2": "by the progress we started to make.",
            "correct": "heartened",
            "word": "HEARTEN"
          },
          {
            "part1": "What a(n)",
            "part2": "crowd! There's only a few hundred people in the entire stadium.",
            "correct": "paltry",
            "word": "PALTRY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The king",
            "part2": "the poor farmer by making him a duke.",
            "correct": "exalted",
            "word": "EXALT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The crowds created such a(n)",
            "part2": "that we had to shout to hear each other.",
            "correct": "hubbub",
            "word": "HUBBUB"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We had to",
            "part2": "carefully past our parents' room to keep from waking them up.",
            "correct": "tread",
            "word": "TREAD"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The huge explosion completely",
            "part2": "all traces of human activity. Nothing remained but ashes.",
            "correct": "obliterated",
            "word": "OBLITERATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The learned professor had many",
            "part2": "things to say about the nature of man.",
            "correct": "profound",
            "word": "PROFOUND"
          },
          {
            "part1": "She polished the table every day to bring out its beautiful",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "sheen",
            "word": "SHEEN"
          },
          {
            "part1": "They climbed the mountain to see the",
            "part2": "of the farms and plains below.",
            "correct": "panorama",
            "word": "PANORAMA"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He will never be able to",
            "part2": "all the money he has lost by gambling.",
            "correct": "recoup",
            "word": "RECOUP"
          },
          {
            "part1": "She's such a(n)",
            "part2": "; she believes anything you tell her.",
            "correct": "simpleton",
            "word": "SIMPLETON"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The teacher made some",
            "part2": "comments about the students who had been misbehaving.",
            "correct": "derogatory",
            "word": "DEROGATORY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Vicky had a(n)",
            "part2": "that the house would burn down, but she didn't pay any attention to it.",
            "correct": "premonition",
            "word": "PREMONITION"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We let him build the fence even though it",
            "part2": "on our land.",
            "correct": "encroached",
            "word": "ENCROACH"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The king was moved by her",
            "part2": "tale of all the troubles her family had suffered.",
            "correct": "piteous",
            "word": "PITEOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Bill repeated the conversation",
            "part2": "to make sure we understood exactly what had been said.",
            "correct": "verbatim",
            "word": "VERBATIM"
          },
          {
            "part1": "That ceremony was",
            "part2": "; it was fit for a king.",
            "correct": "regal",
            "word": "REGAL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "It was an act of",
            "part2": "to go out into the snowstorm without a coat.",
            "correct": "folly",
            "word": "FOLLY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "After a few drinks he became",
            "part2": "and just started babbling nonsense.",
            "correct": "incoherent",
            "word": "INCOGNITO"
          },
          {
            "part1": "It is impossible to",
            "part2": "the contract unless both parties agree that it should end.",
            "correct": "annul",
            "word": "ANNUL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "All our friends",
            "part2": "the show. They said that everything about it was wonderful.",
            "correct": "acclaimed",
            "word": "ACCLAIM"
          }
        ],
        "type": "fitb"
      }
    },
    {
      "wordsets": [
        {
          "title": "5.10",
          "definitions": {
            "JOVIAL": {
              "word": "JOVIAL",
              "phonetic": "(jO'-vE-::,1)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">jolly, merry, good-humored </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Jove</i> is another name for the ancient Roman god <i class=“def-ital\">Jupiter,</i> after whom the planet Jupiter is named. In astrology, Jupiter is supposed to be the source of joy and happiness. Someone who is JOVIAL is influenced by Jupiter, is full of good humor and fun. See <i class=“def-ital\">-al</i> under Suffixes. </p><p>“He is a JOVIAL old man, always laughing and making jokes.” </p><p>“She pretended to be JOVIAL when she found out she had failed the test, but we could tell she was disappointed and unhappy.” </p><p>During the Pretest, many people think JOVIAL means <i class=“def-ital\">friendly.</i> A person could be <i class=“def-ital\">friendly,</i> however, without being merry and jolly. </p><p>Other forms of the word: JOVIALITY, n.</p>"
            },
            "ANECDOTE": {
              "word": "ANECDOTE",
              "phonetic": "(an'-ik-dOt)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a brief tale, story </p><p>An ANECDOTE is a short, true story, usually amusing, about a person or an event. An ANECDOTE is told to give a picture of a famous person’s character, to illustrate some truth, or just to entertain. </p><p>“The musician told us several humorous ANEC- DOTES about famous singers for whom he had played.” </p><p>“The first chapter in the book is just a series of ANEC- DOTES of Harry Truman’s childhood.” </p><p>“The speaker began by telling us a couple of ANEC- DOTES about his travels in India.”</p>"
            },
            "ANNIHILATE": {
              "word": "ANNIHILATE",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩ-nl'-::>-IAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to destroy completely, demolish </p><p>See <i class=“def-ital\">ad-</i> under Prefixes and <i class=“def-ital\">-ate1</i> under Suffixes. The <i class=“def-ital\">nihil</i> part of ANNIHILATE is the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">nothing.</i> To ANNIHILATE something is to turn it into nothing, to destroy it so completely that nothing remains. </p><p>“The general said he didn’t want just to defeat the enemy, he wanted to ANNIHILATE them.” </p><p>“The city was ANNIHILATED by the atomic explosion.” </p><p>“They ANNIHILATED the other football team; the score was 69-6!” </p><p>Other forms of the word: ANNIHILATION, n.</p>"
            },
            "PANDEMONIUM": {
              "word": "PANDEMONIUM",
              "phonetic": "(pan-d::>-mO'-nE-::>m)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">uproar, wild disorder, tumult, chaos </p><p>PANDEMONIUM was made up from two Greek words meaning “all the demons.” The word was first used by John Milton in his poem <i class=“def-ital\">Paradise Lost</i> as the name of the capital of Hell. Since then it has come to be used about any scene of wild noise and disorder. </p><p>“PANDEMONIUM broke out in the stands when we won the championship.” </p><p>“There was PANDEMONIUM in the classroom when- ever the teacher left.” </p><p>“Stay away from that part of town. It’s utter PANDEMONIUM on Saturday nights.”</p>"
            },
            "CIRCUITOUS": {
              "word": "CIRCUITOUS",
              "phonetic": "(s::>r-kyU'-::>-tÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">roundabout, indirect </p><p>CIRCUITOUS is an adjective from the word CIRCUIT. See <i class=“def-ital\">-ous</i> under Suffixes. Both words are related to the word <i class=“def-ital\">circle.</i> The basic meaning of CIRCUIT is “a journey or route around something.” </p><p>“We made a CIRCUIT around the flooded area.” </p><p>CIRCUITOUS is used about routes, trips, and the like and means “taking the long way round,” <i class=“def-ital\">roundabout.</i> </p><p>“We got lost and ended up taking a somewhat CIRCUITOUS route, but we still managed to get there on time.” </p><p>“They took a CIRCUITOUS journey through the mountains; they were more interested in seeing the scenery than in going quickly.” </p><p>The word can also be used in a general sense to mean <i class=“def-ital\">indirect, not straightforward.</i> </p><p>“We had difficulty following his CIRCUITOUS reasoning, but at last he began to make sense.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: CIRCUIT, n.</p>"
            },
            "DISSIPATE": {
              "word": "DISSIPATE",
              "phonetic": "(dis'-ÔøΩ-pAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to scatter, disperse, waste </p><p>DISSIPATE means to <i class=“def-ital\">scatter</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">dissolve.</i> </p><p>“The hot sun DISSIPATED the early morning fog.” </p><p>“He never got anything done. His time just seemed to DISSIPATE.” </p><p>Very often DISSIPATE has the sense of scattering fool- ishly, of <i class=“def-ital\">wasting.</i> </p><p>“Because of his gambling, William managed to DISSIPATE his inheritance within a year.” </p><p>The noun DISSIPATION means a <i class=“def-ital\">wasting</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">scattering</i>; it is usually used in descriptions of wasted lives. </p><p>“We hadn’t seen him in several years. He was terribly changed by the life of DISSIPATION he had led.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: DISSIPATION, n.</p>"
            },
            "DEFRAUD": {
              "word": "DEFRAUD",
              "phonetic": "(di-frod')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to cheat, trick, get by fraud </p><p>A FRAUD is an act of trickery. </p><p>“He posed as a jewelry expert and got the ring from her by FRAUD.” </p><p>To DEFRAUD someone is to take something away from him by FRAUD, to <i class=“def-ital\">cheat</i> him. See <i class=“def-ital\">de-</i> under Prefixes. “One of the partners DEFRAUDED the others of their share of the profits.” </p><p>“The young man was DEFRAUDED of his inheritance by the dishonest lawyers.” </p><p>“The crook DEFRAUDED several people of their life’s savings.”</p>"
            },
            "HUE": {
              "word": "HUE",
              "phonetic": "(hyU)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">color, tint, shade </p><p>HUE means just about the same thing as color. </p><p>“Her dress included all the HUES of the rainbow.” </p><p>“For the ceiling, he chose a paint of a slightly lighter HUE.” </p><p>“The sky turned a strange HUE, and we all knew there was bad weather coming.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Smell</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">sight</i> are the most commonly chosen incorrect answers. People who pick these words probably know that HUE has something to do with the senses, but aren’t exactly sure what. </p><p>Usage: HUE is usually used in poetic or literary kinds of writing.</p>"
            },
            "DISCORD": {
              "word": "DISCORD",
              "phonetic": "(dis'-kord)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">conflict, strife, disagreement, lack of harmony </p><p>In music, a <i class=“def-ital\">chord</i> is a combination of two or more tones sounded together. DISCORD is related to <i class=“def-ital\">chord</i>. A DISCORD in music is a chord which has a harsh or unpleas- ant sound. See <i class=“def-ital\">dis-</i> under Prefixes. DISCORD is also used generally about situations where people or things are not in harmony with one another. </p><p>“There was a great deal of DISCORD at the meeting; no one could agree about anything.” </p><p>“Jill couldn’t stand the DISCORD among the members of her family.” </p><p>“The long years of DISCORD between the two countries finally resulted in war.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: DISCORDANT, adj.</p>"
            },
            "BEDLAM": {
              "word": "BEDLAM",
              "phonetic": "(bed'-lÔøΩm)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a madhouse, insane asylum; confused noise </p><p>BEDLAM was the name of an insane asylum in London; from this the word came to mean any madhouse or insane asylum. Then, because a madhouse was supposed to be a place full of noise and screaming, BEDLAM took on the meaning of“a scene of noise, uproar, and confusion.” </p><p>“Everyone in the room began to yell at once; the place turned into a BEDLAM.” </p><p>“The playground was a BEDLAM of little children shouting and running every which way.” </p><p>“It was BEDLAM around here until our parents returned.”</p>"
            },
            "CASTE": {
              "word": "CASTE",
              "phonetic": "(kast)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a social class </p><p>In India, CASTES are the various social classes that people are born into. Which CASTE you belong to can limit the occupations you can have and the people you can deal with. Thus a CASTE is a separate and exclusive class of society. </p><p>“He belonged to the highest CASTE, so he felt such a job was beneath him.” </p><p>“The people who knew how to cure illnesses formed a separate CASTE within their society.” </p><p>“If you were born into the lowest CASTE, you could not expect to become very successful.”</p>"
            },
            "DEVISE": {
              "word": "DEVISE",
              "phonetic": "(di-viz')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to invent, formulate, plan, contrive </p><p>To DEVISE something is to make it up or <i class=“def-ital\">invent it,</i> usually through a new arrangement of ideas or parts that already exist. </p><p>“He DEVISED a new method for filing the cards.” </p><p>“They DEVISED a scheme to cheat the insurance company.” </p><p>“Jim DEVISED a good radio out of some spare parts on his workbench.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Change</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">fix</i> are common choices as the correct mean- ing of DEVISE. This may be due to confusing DEVISE with revise. To DEVISE something is to invent it. To <i class=“def-ital\">revise</i> something is to change it with the idea of making it better. </p><p>“After he DEVISED the system he revised it several times in order to improve it.”</p>"
            },
            "CONSPICUOUS": {
              "word": "CONSPICUOUS",
              "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-spik'-yU-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">obvious, noticeable, striking </p><p>CONSPICUOUS comes from a Latin word meaning to see, also the source of other English words like <i class=“def-ital\">spy<i class=“def-ital\"></i> and <i class=“def-ital\">spectacles.</i> Something that is CONSPICUOUS is very easy to see. It stands out from everything around it. </p><p>“Put the <i class=“def-ital\">No Smoking</i> sign in a CONSPICUOUS place so that everyone will notice it.” </p><p>“She was very CONSPICUOUS in her huge orange hat.” </p><p>In a slightly different sense, CONSPICUOUS means “at- tracting attention,” because something is out of the ordinary in some way. </p><p>“He received a medal for his CONSPICUOUS bravery during the battle.” </p><p>“The team’s most CONSPICUOUS problem is its complete inability to score goals.”</p>"
            },
            "DWINDLE": {
              "word": "DWINDLE",
              "phonetic": "(dwin'-dÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to shrink, decrease, decline </p><p>To DWINDLE is to become smaller in size, number, or importance. </p><p>“The number of students applying to that college has been steadily DWINDLING for several years, until now almost no one wants to go there.” </p><p>“The importance of railroads started to DWINDLE with the development of a national highway system.” </p><p>“The snowman DWINDLED as the sun shone on it, until finally it all melted away.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Waste time</i> is the most commonly wrong answer on the Pretest, probably because of confusion with the word <i class=“def-ital\">dawdle.</i></p>"
            },
            "GIST": {
              "word": "GIST",
              "phonetic": "(",
              "pos": "jist)",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">n.: the main part, main idea, essence, general sense </p><p>GIST is a legal term, meaning “the grounds for a legal action\"-that is, the basic reason or point of a case. In general use GIST has the same idea: it is the main point, the central idea of something. </p><p>“Don’t repeat the whole speech to me. I just want the GIST of what he said.” </p><p>“There was a lot more to it, but the GIST of his decision is that you can’t come.”</p>"
            }
          },
          "id": "10",
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "JOVIAL people.",
                  "answers": [
                    "sad",
                    "clever",
                    "young",
                    "jolly",
                    "friendly"
                  ],
                  "word": "JOVIAL",
                  "correct": "jolly"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Another ANECDOTE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "doctor",
                    "novel",
                    "game",
                    "speech",
                    "tale"
                  ],
                  "word": "ANECDOTE",
                  "correct": "tale"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The army was ANNIHILATED.",
                  "answers": [
                    "stopped",
                    "harmed",
                    "destroyed",
                    "attacked",
                    "saved"
                  ],
                  "word": "ANNIHILATE",
                  "correct": "destroyed"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Complete PANDEMONIUM.",
                  "answers": [
                    "evil",
                    "stillness",
                    "happiness",
                    "uproar",
                    "victory"
                  ],
                  "word": "PANDEMONIUM",
                  "correct": "uproar"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CIRCUITOUS route.",
                  "answers": [
                    "direct",
                    "complicated",
                    "dangerous",
                    "roundabout",
                    "unexpected"
                  ],
                  "word": "CIRCUITOUS",
                  "correct": "roundabout"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The opposition will DISSIPATE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "scatter",
                    "lose",
                    "take part",
                    "grow",
                    "hold back"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISSIPATE",
                  "correct": "scatter"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Tried to DEFRAUD him.",
                  "answers": [
                    "convince",
                    "attack",
                    "cheat",
                    "disturb",
                    "support"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEFRAUD",
                  "correct": "cheat"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "An unpleasant HUE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "smell",
                    "shape",
                    "sight",
                    "paint",
                    "color"
                  ],
                  "word": "HUE",
                  "correct": "color"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Continuous DISCORD.",
                  "answers": [
                    "agreement",
                    "despair",
                    "singing",
                    "conflict",
                    "removal"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISCORD",
                  "correct": "conflict"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "A real BEDLAM.",
                  "answers": [
                    "rest",
                    "crowd",
                    "disaster",
                    "madhouse",
                    "ceremony"
                  ],
                  "word": "BEDLAM",
                  "correct": "madhouse"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Lowest CASTE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "population",
                    "class",
                    "brace",
                    "public opinion",
                    "country"
                  ],
                  "word": "CASTE",
                  "correct": "class"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DEVISE the engine.",
                  "answers": [
                    "destroy",
                    "change",
                    "check",
                    "invent",
                    "fix"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEVISE",
                  "correct": "invent"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Too CONSPICUOUS.",
                  "answers": [
                    "unclear",
                    "obvious",
                    "secret",
                    "silly",
                    "unusual"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONSPICUOUS",
                  "correct": "obvious"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Began to DWINDLE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "grow",
                    "change",
                    "become worse",
                    "shrink",
                    "waste time"
                  ],
                  "word": "DWINDLE",
                  "correct": "shrink"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "What was the GIST?",
                  "answers": [
                    "cause",
                    "delay",
                    "result",
                    "funny story",
                    "main idea"
                  ],
                  "word": "GIST",
                  "correct": "main idea"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Is Santa Claus supposed to be JOVIAL?",
                  "word": "JOVIAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is the play Hamlet an ANECDOTE?",
                  "word": "ANECDOTE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could an atom bomb ANNIHILATE a city?",
                  "word": "ANNIHILATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are people calm during PANDEMONIUM?",
                  "word": "PANDEMONIUM",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a CIRCUITOUS route the fastest one?",
                  "word": "CIRCUITOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can money be DISSIPATED?",
                  "word": "DISSIPATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you go to jail for DEFRAUDING someone?",
                  "word": "DEFRAUD",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is red a HUE?",
                  "word": "HUE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a DISCORD pleasant to hear?",
                  "word": "DISCORD",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it easy to sleep in a BEDLAM?",
                  "word": "BEDLAM",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It is usual for many people to belong to a CASTE?",
                  "word": "CASTE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "When you DEVISE something, do you split it in half?",
                  "word": "DEVISE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a hidden passage be CONSPICUOUS?",
                  "word": "CONSPICUOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does a person walking toward you appear to DWINDLE in size?",
                  "word": "DWINDLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would the GIST of a story be added to the end of it?",
                  "word": "GIST",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "This problem is too JOVIAL for us to bother about.",
                  "word": "JOVIAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Our uncle told us an ANECDOTE about the time he had lunch with a movie star.",
                  "word": "ANECDOTE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His punch didn't hurt, it just ANNIHILATED me a little.",
                  "word": "ANNIHILATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They are two respectable citizens who enjoy playing PANDEMONIUM.",
                  "word": "PANDEMONIUM",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His arguments were CIRCUITOUS, and no one could quite understand where they were all leading.",
                  "word": "CIRCUITOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Her DISSIPATION in this project has helped us immensely.",
                  "word": "DISSIPATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He DEFRAUDED them to everyone as the criminals they really were.",
                  "word": "DEFRAUD",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We smelled the wonderful HUE of the rose.",
                  "word": "HUE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "There was considerable DISCORD as a result of the school board's decision to make the school year longer.",
                  "word": "DISCORD",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BEDLAM broke out in the classroom.",
                  "word": "BEDLAM",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It was impossible for her to move into a higher CASTE.",
                  "word": "CASTE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The scientist DEVISED a better method for treating cancer.",
                  "word": "DEVISE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Try not to be too CONSPICUOUS in the store. I don't want anyone to know we're there.",
                  "word": "CONSPICUOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She's been out of work for over a year and her savings have DWINDLED considerably.",
                  "word": "DWINDLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The GIST of his argument is that we did it before, so we can do it again.",
                  "word": "GIST",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "JOVIAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "pretty",
                    "merry",
                    "happy"
                  ],
                  "word": "JOVIAL",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ANECDOTE",
                  "answers": [
                    "story",
                    "lecture",
                    "joke"
                  ],
                  "word": "ANECDOTE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ANNIHILATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "wipe out",
                    "abolish",
                    "cover"
                  ],
                  "word": "ANNIHILATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PANDEMONIUM",
                  "answers": [
                    "excitement",
                    "loudness",
                    "goodness"
                  ],
                  "word": "PANDEMONIUM",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CIRCUITOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "winding",
                    "clever",
                    "crooked"
                  ],
                  "word": "CIRCUITOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DISSIPATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "lose",
                    "contribute",
                    "ruin"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISSIPATE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DEFRAUD",
                  "answers": [
                    "lie",
                    "steal",
                    "wound"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEFRAUD",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HUE",
                  "answers": [
                    "color",
                    "sound",
                    "tint"
                  ],
                  "word": "HUE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DISCORD",
                  "answers": [
                    "hostility",
                    "disappointment",
                    "disagreement"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISCORD",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BEDLAM",
                  "answers": [
                    "insanity",
                    "sneakiness",
                    "noise"
                  ],
                  "word": "BEDLAM",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CASTE",
                  "answers": [
                    "level",
                    "sign",
                    "class"
                  ],
                  "word": "CASTE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DEVISE",
                  "answers": [
                    "plan",
                    "contrive",
                    "repair"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEVISE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONSPICUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "outstanding",
                    "distinct",
                    "new"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONSPICUOUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DWINDLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "diminish",
                    "despair",
                    "decrease"
                  ],
                  "word": "DWINDLE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GIST",
                  "answers": [
                    "core",
                    "best",
                    "essence"
                  ],
                  "word": "GIST",
                  "correct": "1"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "5.11",
          "definitions": {
            "IMPEDIMENT": {
              "word": "IMPEDIMENT",
              "phonetic": "(im-ped'-ÔøΩ-mÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">an obstacle, obstruction, hindrance </p><p>The verb IMPEDE comes from the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">foot,</i> which is also the source of the English words <i class=“def-ital\">pedal</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">pedestrian.</i> The original Latin meaning of IMPEDE was “to snare the feet.” Today it means more generally “to obstruct the progress of,” to <i class=“def-ital\">hinder.</i> </p><p>“The constant floods IMPEDED their journey.” An IMPEDIMENT is something which IMPEDES, an <i class=“def-ital\">obstacle.</i> </p><p>“Lack of money was the main IMPEDIMENT to the successful completion of the project.” </p><p>“He had a speech IMPEDIMENT that kept him from talking easily.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: IMPEDE,v.</p>"
            },
            "DORMANT": {
              "word": "DORMANT",
              "phonetic": "(dor'-mÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">inactive </p><p>DORMANT comes originally from a Latin word meaning to <i class=“def-ital\">sleep,</i> also the source of the word <i class=“def-ital\">dormitory.</i> DORMANT means lying asleep or as if asleep. It is used about things which are inactive now, but are capable of becoming active in the future. </p><p>“During the winter, trees become DORMANT. In the spring they seem to come alive again and put out new leaves.” </p><p>“After years of being DORMANT the volcano suddenly erupted.” </p><p>“Her ability to paint lay DORMANT for many years. She didn’t start to draw and sketch until she was past fifty.”</p>"
            },
            "DIMINISH": {
              "word": "DIMINISH",
              "phonetic": "(dÔøΩ-min'-ish)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to lessen, decrease, dwindle </p><p>To DIMINISH is to make less, or to become less. </p><p>“Nothing could DIMINISH my interest in history.” </p><p>“The value of our house DIMINISHED when they decided to build an expressway next to it.” </p><p>“His wealth DIMINISHED as a result of poor investments.” </p><p>“Our food supply was greatly DIMINISHED by the end of the day.” </p><p>The most common wrong answer on the Pretest is <i class=“def-ital\">stop.</i> </p><p>To DIMINISH something is not to <i class=“def-ital\">stop</i> it, though,only to lessen it.</p>"
            },
            "JAUNT": {
              "word": "JAUNT",
              "phonetic": "(jont)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a short trip, excursion </p><p>A JAUNT is a short, casual trip taken for pleasure. </p><p>“We took a quick JAUNT to the beach.” </p><p>“They went on a JAUNT to see the city sights.” </p><p>JAUNT can also be used as a verb. </p><p>“She liked to JAUNT through the lovely parks. ”</p>"
            },
            "TUMULT": {
              "word": "TUMULT",
              "phonetic": "(tU'-mÔøΩlt)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">an uproar, noise, disturbance, commotion </p><p>A TUMULT is any sort of uproar or disturbance. </p><p>“The politician was greeted with a TUMULT of cheers.” </p><p>“There was a sudden silence in the midst of the TUMULT.” </p><p>TUMULT is often used about highly disturbed emotions. </p><p>“Her feelings were in a TUMULT as she waited for the door to open.” </p><p>The adjective form of TUMULT is TUMULTUOUS, which means <i class=“def-ital\">noisy</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">disorderly.</i> </p><p>“The star received TUMULTUOUS applause when he came on stage.” </p><p>“The teacher tried to calm the TUMULTUOUS crowd of children.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: TUMULTUOUS,adj.</p>"
            },
            "CLAD": {
              "word": "CLAD",
              "phonetic": "(klad)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">dressed, clothed </p><p>CLAD is an old form of the past tense of the verb to <i class=“def-ital\">clothe.</i> When the word is used in this way, it usually has an old-fashioned flavor. </p><p>“The princess was CLAD in the finest Japanese silk.” </p><p>Usually CLAD is an adjective, used with another word as part of a phrase. </p><p>“Poorly CLAD beggars roamed the streets of the town.” </p><p>An IRONCLAD ship is covered with iron plates, usually as armor. From this IRONCLAD has come to be used about anything that is impossible to break. </p><p>“We had an IRONCLAD agreement to help each other.”</p>"
            },
            "MERCANTILE": {
              "word": "MERCANTILE",
              "phonetic": "(mer'-kÔøΩn-tll)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">related to trade, commercial </p><p>A MERCHANT is someone who buys and sells a product for profit. MERCANTILE is an adjective from MERCHANT and means “of or related to MERCHANTS or trading.” </p><p>“It was a MERCANTILE city, famous for its many large businesses.” </p><p>“The MERCANTILE interests in the legislature sup- ported all bills that would help increase trade.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: MERCHANT, n.</p>"
            },
            "ANGUISH": {
              "word": "ANGUISH",
              "phonetic": "(ang'-gwish",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">suffering, sorrow, distress, woe, agony </p><p>ANGUISH is extreme suffering. The suffering can be either mental or physical. </p><p>“Her son’s death in an automobile accident caused her great ANGUISH.” </p><p>“Nothing we could do could relieve her ANGUISH when her house burned down.” </p><p>“The soldier was in ANGUISH until the doctor came to treat his wound.” </p><p>ANGUISH is also a verb. </p><p>“Mary ANGUISHED over the loss of her home and belongings in the fire.” </p><p>ANGUISHED is the adjective from ANGUISH. </p><p>“Her ANGUISHED cries told us that something was terribly wrong.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Rage</i> is the incorrect answer that is most often chosen. This is probably due to a confusion between ANGUISH and <i class=“def-ital\">anger.</i> Other forms of the word: ANGUISHED, adj.</p>"
            },
            "DEPLORABLE": {
              "word": "DEPLORABLE",
              "phonetic": "(di-plor'-ÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">wretched, bad, causing grief or regret </p><p>To DEPLORE something is to feel great regret, disapproval, or sorrow about it. </p><p>“He DEPLORED the conditions in which the miners had to work.” </p><p>DEPLORABLE is the adjective from DEPLORE. See <i class=“def-ital\">-able</i> under Suffixes. Something which is DEPLORABLE is <i class=“def-ital\">wretched,</i> bad enough to cause strong disapproval. </p><p>“When we arrived at our new apartment we found that the people living there before us had left it in a DE- PLORABLE condition.” “Wendy’s grandmother told her that her manners were DEPLORABLE.” </p><p>Sometimes the word is used about something that causes sorrow rather than disapproval. </p><p>“The people wept bitterly upon hearing of the DEPLORABLE death of their president.” </p><p>“They had never before witnessed such a DEPLORABLE accident.” Other forms of the word: DEPLORE, v.</p>"
            },
            "EFFERVESCENT": {
              "word": "EFFERVESCENT",
              "phonetic": "(ef-ÔøΩr-ves'-ÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">bubbling, exuberant, lively </p><p>The <i class=“def-ital\">ferv</i> part of EFFERVESCENT comes from a Latin word meaning to <i class=“def-ital\">boil,</i> also the source of the word <i class=“def-ital\">fervent.</i> To EFFERVESCE is to give off bubbles of gas the way a carbonated soft drink or champagne does.EFFERVES- CENT is the adjective from EFFERVESCE. The word is usually used in a general sense about people who are so lively and excitable that they seem to bubbleover with enthusiasm, joy, or ideas. </p><p>“Her EFFERVESCENT enthusiasm made everyone else try twice as hard.” </p><p>“His EFFERVESCENT personality would enliven any party.” </p><p>“Jane’s EFFERVESCENT imagination came up with a hundred ways of solving the problem.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: EFFERVESCE, v. EFFERVESCENCE, n.</p>"
            },
            "ORNATE": {
              "word": "ORNATE",
              "phonetic": "(or-nAt')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">elaborately or excessively decorated, showy </p><p>ORNATE is related to the word <i class=“def-ital\">ornament.</i> Something which is ORNATE is highly decorated or ornamented. </p><p>“The chair was very ORNATE, covered with scrolls and designs and patterns.” </p><p>“We stared at the ORNATE design on the ceiling of the church.” </p><p>ORNATE is often used about writing which is full of flowery language. </p><p>“Some people like this ORNATE style of writing. I like writing to be simple and clear.”</p>"
            },
            "SOMBER": {
              "word": "SOMBER",
              "phonetic": "(som'-bÔøΩr)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">gloomy, dark, dark colored, dismal </p><p>SOMBER means <i class=“def-ital\">gloomy, dark,</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">shadowy.</i> It is used about things and people’s moods. </p><p>“It was customary for relatives of the dead person to dress in SOMBER clothes for at least a year.” </p><p>“SOMBER clouds filled the sky.” </p><p>“She put on a SOMBER look, even though she was secretly pleased.” </p><p>“He couldn’t shake off his SOMBER mood.” </p><p>Many people think SOMBER means <i class=“def-ital\">bored.</i> SOMBER, however, emphasizes gloominess and depression rather than boredom.</p>"
            },
            "JURISDICTION": {
              "word": "JURISDICTION",
              "phonetic": "(jUr-is-dik'-shÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">authority, power, control </p><p>JURISDICTION comes from the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">law,</i> also the source of <i class=“def-ital\">jury.</i> JURISDICTION is the legal power to administer justice and decide cases. “Our courts have JURISDICTION over foreigners living in the United States.” </p><p>“The judge said it wasn’t within his JURISDICTION to decide this question.” </p><p>The word can be used in a broader sense for any authority or power that has well-defined limits. </p><p>“Your complaint does not come within our JURISDICTION. Try another department.” </p><p>The most popular wrong answer is <i class=“def-ital\">decision.</i> People who choose this probably know that JURISDICTION has something to do with the law, but don’t know exactly what. JURISDICTION is the authority to make a legal decision, not the decision itself.</p>"
            },
            "NARRATIVE": {
              "word": "NARRATIVE",
              "phonetic": "(nar'-ÔøΩ-tiv)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a story, tale To NARRATE a story is to tell it. </p><p>“He NARRATED a story about a boy and his dog living on a farm.” </p><p>A NARRATIVE is a story, the telling of a series of events. </p><p>A NARRATIVE can be either true or made up. </p><p>“They read an exciting NARRATIVE about pirates and buried treasure.” </p><p>“We listened to the NARRATIVE of the first space- flight.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: NARRATE, v. NARRATOR, n.</p>"
            },
            "REALM": {
              "word": "REALM",
              "phonetic": "(relm)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a kingdom, territory, region </p><p>REALM is a fancy or poetical word for <i class=“def-ital\">kingdom.</i> </p><p>“The king searched throughout his REALM for one honest man.” </p><p>The word is also used in a general sense for <i class=“def-ital\">region, territory, or range.</i> </p><p>“He lived entirely within the REALM of his own imagination.” </p><p>If something is “within the REALM of possibility,” it is possible, it can happen. </p><p>The most commonly chosen wrong answer is tale, possibly because REALM is connected in people’s minds with stories and legends rather than with everyday speech.</p>"
            }
          },
          "id": "11",
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPEDIMENT to learning.",
                  "answers": [
                    "threat",
                    "disadvantage",
                    "end",
                    "obstacle",
                    "aid"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPEDIMENT",
                  "correct": "obstacle"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It was DORMANT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "inactive",
                    "forgotten",
                    "uncertain",
                    "painful",
                    "powerful"
                  ],
                  "word": "DORMANT",
                  "correct": "inactive"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To DIMINISH it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "change",
                    "stop",
                    "lessen",
                    "use",
                    "refuse"
                  ],
                  "word": "DIMINISH",
                  "correct": "lessen"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "During the JAUNT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "comedy",
                    "short trip",
                    "mountain climb",
                    "expedition",
                    "train ride"
                  ],
                  "word": "JAUNT",
                  "correct": "short trip"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "In the middle of the TUMULT.",
                  "answers": [
                    "silence",
                    "contest",
                    "discussion",
                    "fire",
                    "uproar"
                  ],
                  "word": "TUMULT",
                  "correct": "uproar"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Well-CLAD children.",
                  "answers": [
                    "dressed",
                    "protected",
                    "cared-for",
                    "behaved",
                    "disguised"
                  ],
                  "word": "CLAD",
                  "correct": "dressed"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MERCANTILE interests.",
                  "answers": [
                    "unclear",
                    "legal",
                    "trade",
                    "government",
                    "communist"
                  ],
                  "word": "MERCANTILE",
                  "correct": "trade"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Her ANGUISH.",
                  "answers": [
                    "pleasure",
                    "nervousness",
                    "insanity",
                    "suffering",
                    "rage"
                  ],
                  "word": "ANGUISH",
                  "correct": "suffering"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DEPLORABLE conditions.",
                  "answers": [
                    "unusual",
                    "wretched",
                    "improper",
                    "remarkable",
                    "unnecessary"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEPLORABLE",
                  "correct": "wretched"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EFFERVESCENT personality.",
                  "answers": [
                    "bubbling",
                    "lovable",
                    "unique",
                    "dull",
                    "constant"
                  ],
                  "word": "EFFERVESCENT",
                  "correct": "bubbling"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ORNATE style.",
                  "answers": [
                    "showy",
                    "modern",
                    "pleasing",
                    "plain",
                    "perfect"
                  ],
                  "word": "ORNATE",
                  "correct": "showy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SOMBER attitude.",
                  "answers": [
                    "critical",
                    "cruel",
                    "eager",
                    "gloomy",
                    "bored"
                  ],
                  "word": "SOMBER",
                  "correct": "gloomy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Question their JURISDICTION.",
                  "answers": [
                    "ability",
                    "wisdom",
                    "interest",
                    "authority",
                    "decision"
                  ],
                  "word": "JURISDICTION",
                  "correct": "authority"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "During the NARRATIVE.",
                  "answers": [
                    "story",
                    "concert",
                    "meeting",
                    "class",
                    "conversation"
                  ],
                  "word": "NARRATIVE",
                  "correct": "story"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Faraway REALM.",
                  "answers": [
                    "island",
                    "castle",
                    "banquet",
                    "tale",
                    "kingdom"
                  ],
                  "word": "REALM",
                  "correct": "kingdom"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Example",
                  "word": "IMPEDIMENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a train be IMPEDED by a truck on the tracks?",
                  "word": "IMPEDE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are some bears DORMANT during the winter?",
                  "word": "DORMANT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does your supply of money DIMINISH when you spend some?",
                  "word": "DIMINISH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could someone go on a JAUNT to the zoo?",
                  "word": "JAUNT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a riot be considered a TUMULT?",
                  "word": "TUMULT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a well-CLAD person have holes in his socks?",
                  "word": "CLAD",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would someone who sells furniture be called a MERCHANT?",
                  "word": "MERCHANT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do people enjoy being in ANGUISH?",
                  "word": "ANGUISH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do people DEPLORE murder?",
                  "word": "DEPLORE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are EFFERVESCENT people usually bored?",
                  "word": "EFFERVESCENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a sidewalk usually ORNATE?",
                  "word": "ORNATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are people generally SOMBER at a wedding?",
                  "word": "SOMBER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does the teacher have JURISDICTION in the classroom?",
                  "word": "JURISDICTION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a NARRATIVE be very short?",
                  "word": "NARRATIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does a king rule a REALM?",
                  "word": "REALM",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "If there are no unexpected IMPEDIMENTS, we should be finished on time.",
                  "word": "IMPEDIMENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "My talent for writing was DORMANT for many years until a friend in publishing persuaded me to write a book.",
                  "word": "DORMANT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The wrecking crew completely DIMINISHED the building in a few hours.",
                  "word": "DIMINISH",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Magellan's JAUNT around the world lasted several years.",
                  "word": "JAUNT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They were so ashamed of themselves that they just stood there in TUMULTUOUS silence.",
                  "word": "TUMULT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The knight was CLAD in shining armor.",
                  "word": "CLAD",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Some commercial banks discourage small savings accounts; they prefer to deal with large MERCANTILE outfits.",
                  "word": "MERCANTILE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "I will never forget the ANGUISHED look on his face when his dog died.",
                  "word": "ANGUISH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She thought the dirty language in the movie was DEPLORABLE.",
                  "word": "DEPLORABLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "These problems are EFFERVESCENT; I don't think we'll ever solve them.",
                  "word": "EFFERVESCENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The stained glass window was beautifully ORNATE. It would take you hours to notice all the details.",
                  "word": "ORNATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The hotel was filled with SOMBER, poorly lit passageways that made us feel a little frightened.",
                  "word": "SOMBER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "After many days of debate the jury finally reached a JURISDICTION.",
                  "word": "JURISDICTION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": ". They listened to the exciting NARRATIVE of his adventures.",
                  "word": "NARRATIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The teacher said that my getting an A in English was not within the REALM of possibility.",
                  "word": "REALM",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPEDIMENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "destruction",
                    "hindrance",
                    "obstruction"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPEDIMENT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DORMANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "sleeping",
                    "stupid",
                    "inactive"
                  ],
                  "word": "DORMANT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DIMINISH",
                  "answers": [
                    "reduce",
                    "end",
                    "decline"
                  ],
                  "word": "DIMINISH",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "JAUNT a ) outing",
                  "answers": [
                    "ship",
                    "trip",
                    ""
                  ],
                  "word": "JAUNT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TUMULT",
                  "answers": [
                    "confusion",
                    "shouting",
                    "robbery"
                  ],
                  "word": "TUMULT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CLAD a ) costumed",
                  "answers": [
                    "attired",
                    "lashed",
                    ""
                  ],
                  "word": "CLAD",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MERCANTILE",
                  "answers": [
                    "commercial",
                    "financial",
                    "private"
                  ],
                  "word": "MERCANTILE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ANGUISH",
                  "answers": [
                    "unhappiness",
                    "anger c ) misery",
                    ""
                  ],
                  "word": "ANGUISH",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DEPLORABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "awful",
                    "disgusting",
                    "unexpected"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEPLORABLE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EFFERVESCENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "jolly",
                    "kind",
                    "excited"
                  ],
                  "word": "EFFERVESCENT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ORNATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "exciting b ) elaborate",
                    "flowery",
                    ""
                  ],
                  "word": "ORNATE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SOMBER",
                  "answers": [
                    "old b ) dark",
                    "sad",
                    ""
                  ],
                  "word": "SOMBER",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "JURISDICTION",
                  "answers": [
                    "power",
                    "opportunity",
                    "control"
                  ],
                  "word": "JURISDICTION",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NARRATIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "telling",
                    "reply",
                    "account"
                  ],
                  "word": "NARRATIVE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REALM",
                  "answers": [
                    "town",
                    "area",
                    "empire"
                  ],
                  "word": "REALM",
                  "correct": "0"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "5.12",
          "definitions": {
            "DICTATORIAL": {
              "word": "DICTATORIAL",
              "phonetic": "(dik-tÔøΩtor'-E-ÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">like a DICTATOR, overbearing, oppressive </p><p>A DICTATOR is a person who rules a country by himself, usually in a cruel way. DICTATORIAL is the adjective from DICTATOR and means “like a DICTATOR.” See <i class=“def-ital\">-al</i> under Suffixes. The word suggests a person who is so used to power that he expects everyone to obey him. </p><p>“Her father’s DICTATORIAL attitude bothered Cathy. He would punish her if she didn’t obey him immediately.” </p><p>“The teacher believes you don’t have to be DICTATO- RIAL to make students learn. Being pleasant and un- derstanding often works better.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: DICTATOR, n.</p>"
            },
            "RELISH": {
              "word": "RELISH",
              "phonetic": "(rel'-ish)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to enjoy, take delight in </p><p>To RELISH something is to enjoy it greatly, to take de- light in it. </p><p>“They RELISH singing. They sing every chance they get.” </p><p>“I RELISH the idea of going to camp this summer.” </p><p>“I don’t RELISH the thought of having to sweep the floor.” </p><p>RELISH is also a noun, meaning enjoyment. </p><p>“She led the parade with great RELISH.” </p><p>“I have little RELISH for getting up so early.”</p>"
            },
            "DON": {
              "word": "DON",
              "phonetic": "(don)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to put on, dress in </p><p>DON is used about clothing, and means to <i class=“def-ital\">put on.</i> </p><p>“The king DONNED his finest robes when he went to meet them.” </p><p>“She DONNED a brand new hat for Easter.” </p><p>“Jane DONNED her favorite gown to go to the dance.” </p><p>Most people who get this word wrong on the Pretest choose <i class=“def-ital\">take off</i> as its meaning. This is the exact opposite of DON. A similar-sounding word, <i class=“def-ital\">doff,</i> means to <i class=“def-ital\">take off,</i> and this may cause some of the confusion. “He DONNED his coat when he went outside, then <i class=“def-ital\">doffed</i> it when he came back in again.” Usage: DON is a rather old-fashioned word and would not usually be used in ordinary conversation.</p>"
            },
            "LIVELIHOOD": {
              "word": "LIVELIHOOD",
              "phonetic": "(llv'-IE-hud)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a means of support, living </p><p>A LIVELIHOOD is a way of making a living, a means of earning money. The word can apply to the money you earn in order to live, or to the job or career from which you earn the money. </p><p>“He gained his LIVELIHOOD by selling from door to door.” </p><p>“Raising sheep provided them with a decent LIVELI- HOOD.” </p><p>Many people think LIVELIHOOD means <i class=“def-ital\">hobby.</i> A <i class=“def-ital\">hobby</i> is something you do for fun, though, not to make a living. </p><p>“Her parent didn’t mind acting as a <i class=“def-ital\">hobby,</i> but they disapproved of it as a LIVELIHOOD.”</p>"
            },
            "ASSERT": {
              "word": "ASSERT",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩsert')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to declare, state, affirm, maintain </p><p>To ASSERT something is to state positively that it is true, usually without proof. </p><p>“The defendant ASSERTED his innocence.” </p><p>“Father ASSERTED that we were too young to see that movie.” </p><p>“John ASSERTED that he was strong enough to carry the box.” </p><p>In a similar sense, ASSERT means “to put forward boldly.” “If you want people to pay attention to you, you must ASSERT yourself’-that is, you must demand to be recognized or listened to. </p><p>The most common mistake is to choose <i class=“def-ital\">believe</i> as the meaning of ASSERT. You would usually <i class=“def-ital\">believe</i> something that you ASSERT, but ASSERT adds the idea of declaring your belief publicly and forcefully. Other forms of the word: ASSERTION, n. ASSERTIVE, adj.</p>"
            },
            "INVOKE": {
              "word": "INVOKE",
              "phonetic": "(in-vOk')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to call upon, call for, appeal to, entreat, summon </p><p>See <i class=“def-ital\">in-1</i> under Prefixes. The <i class=“def-ital\">voke</i> part of the word means to <i class=“def-ital\">call.</i> To <i class=“def-ital\">revoke</i> is to call back, to <i class=“def-ital\">convoke</i> is to call together, to <i class=“def-ital\">evoke</i> is to call forth. INVOKE has several different uses, all of which basically mean to <i class=“def-ital\">call in</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">call upon.</i> To INVOKE God’s name is to call upon it-for ex- ample, in support of what you are saying. To INVOKE someone’s mercy is to call for it, to beg for it. To IN- VOKE an investigation is to cause it, to call it forth. To INVOKE evil spirits is to call them forth, to summon them by magic. </p><p>Other forms of the word: INVOCATION, n.</p>"
            },
            "UTILITY": {
              "word": "UTILITY",
              "phonetic": "(yU-til'-::l-tE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">usefulness </p><p>UTILITY is the quality of being useful, the ability to be of use. </p><p>“This invention might not have much UTILITY right away, but in a few years it will be very useful.” </p><p>“The teachers had an argument over the UTILITY of teaching arithmetic this way.” </p><p>A “public UTILITY” is a company that supplies an essential public service like water or electricity. </p><p>To UTILIZE something is to make use of it. </p><p>“Bill UTILIZED many old pieces of lumber in building the barn.” </p><p>“She has so many talents that it is difficult for her to UTILIZE them all.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: UTILIZE, v.</p>"
            },
            "PARTITION": {
              "word": "PARTITION",
              "phonetic": "(pahr-tish'-gn)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to divide, split, separate into parts </p><p>You can see the word <i class=“def-ital\">part</i> in PARTITION. PARTITION means “to split or separate into parts.” The word can be used with almost anything that can be made into smaller spaces. </p><p>“After World War II, Germany was PARTITIONED into East Germany and West Germany.” </p><p>“They PARTITIONED the living room to allow for a dining area.” </p><p>“The box is PARTITIONED to hold different sizes of bottles.” </p><p>A PARTITION is something that divides or separates. </p><p>“They used movable PARTITIONS to create separate offices in the large open space.”</p>"
            },
            "GROPE": {
              "word": "GROPE",
              "phonetic": "(grOp)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to feel about blindly, feel one’s way, search blindly or uncertainly </p><p>To GROPE for something is to feel about for it as if you were blind and could only use your hands. </p><p>“He GROPED for the flashlight in the dark.” </p><p>“She GROPED for the ball that had rolled beneath the couch.” </p><p>“They GROPED their way through the dark tunnel.” </p><p>GROPE is also used in a more general sense for any kind of uncertain or hesitant search. </p><p>“He GROPED for an answer to the difficult math problem.” </p><p>“She GROPED for the proper words to say how thank- ful she was.”</p>"
            },
            "FALLACY": {
              "word": "FALLACY",
              "phonetic": "(fal'-::l-sE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a false or mistaken idea; false reasoning </p><p>In logic, a FALLACY is an incorrect line of reasoning which leads to a mistaken conclusion. For example, the following is a FALLACY: </p><p>“If a man is shot through the head, he will die. Smith died; therefore he was shot through the head.” </p><p>Being shot through the head is obviously not the only way a man can die. A particular error in logic has been made which makes the conclusion false. These errors are called, in general, FALLACIES. </p><p>In everyday use, a FALLACY is an idea which is false or mistaken, usually because of faulty reasoning. </p><p>“The theory that boys are smarter than girls has repeatedly been shown to be a FALLACY.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: FALLACIOUS, adj.</p>"
            },
            "REPRIMAND": {
              "word": "REPRIMAND",
              "phonetic": "(rep'-rÔøΩmand)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to scold, rebuke, censure, reprove </p><p>To REPRIMAND someone is to scold him severely for having done something wrong. </p><p>“Her parents REPRIMANDED her for staying out so late without permission.” </p><p>REPRIMAND usually has the sense of an official, formal censure. </p><p>“The soldier was officially REPRIMANDED for not following orders.” </p><p>REPRIMAND is also a noun. </p><p>“The president of the company sent him a letter of REPRIMAND for missing work.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Arrest</i> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer. REPRIMANDING a person falls far short of <i class=“def-ital\">arresting</i> him and putting him in jail, however.</p>"
            },
            "PRESUMPTUOUS": {
              "word": "PRESUMPTUOUS",
              "phonetic": "(pri-zuhmp'-chU-as)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">overconfident, arrogant, audacious </p><p>To PRESUME to do something is to dare to do it, to take the liberty of doing it. </p><p>“The bold soldier PRESUMED to call the general by his first name.” Someone who is PRESUMPTUOUS PRESUMES too much. He is too bold and confident and assumes he has the right to do things when he really hasn’t. See <i class=“def-ital\">-ous</i> under Suffixes. </p><p>“It was PRESUMPTUOUS of him to think that I would go along with whatever he decided.” </p><p>“The PRESUMPTUOUS assistant decided he knew what to do and wouldn’t wait for the boss’s orders.” </p><p>“He was never PRESUMPTUOUS, but always waited patiently for the permission of his superiors to do anything.” </p><p>The most commonly chosen incorrect answer is <i class=“def-ital\">impolite.</i> PRESUMPTUOUS people might often be <i class=“def-ital\">impolite,</i> but PRESUMPTUOUS has a much more specific meaning than that. Other forms of the word: PRESUME, v. PRESUMPTION, n.</p>"
            },
            "HURTLE": {
              "word": "HURTLE",
              "phonetic": "(her'-tÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to rush violently, move rapidly; to drive, fling </p><p>To HURTLE is to move rapidly and violently. The word usually emphasizes speed, noise, and violence. </p><p>“Tons of snow HURTLED down the mountainside during the avalanche.” </p><p>“The rocket HURTLED through the air at five times the speed of sound.” </p><p>To HURTLE something is to drive it forward rapidly or violently. </p><p>“The new train HURTLED its passengers across the country in record time.”</p>"
            },
            "TALON": {
              "word": "TALON",
              "phonetic": "(tal'-ÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a claw </p><p>A TALON is a <i class=“def-ital\">claw,</i> especially the claw of a bird of prey like a hawk. </p><p>“The eagle swooped down and seized the rabbit in its TALONS.” </p><p>“The bird curved its TALONS around its perch.”</p>"
            },
            "ENDEAVCR": {
              "word": "ENDEAVCR",
              "phonetic": "(en-dev'-3r)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to try, make an effort, attempt, strive </p><p>ENDEAVOR means to <i class=“def-ital\">try.</i> The word usually adds to <i class=“def-ital\">try</i> a sense of determined effort or struggle. </p><p>“No matter how much they ENDEAVORED, they couldn’t finish in time.” </p><p>“They ENDEAVORED to clean up the house before their mother returned.” </p><p>ENDEAVOR when used as a noun emphasizes even more strongly this idea of difficulty and determination. </p><p>“They made a serious ENDEAVOR to solve these important problems.” </p><p>“The ENDEAVOR was worthwhile, even if it did not succeed.”</p>"
            }
          },
          "id": "12",
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "DICTATORIAL manner.",
                  "answers": [
                    "meek",
                    "convincing",
                    "royal",
                    "overbearing",
                    "businesslike"
                  ],
                  "word": "DICTATORIAL",
                  "correct": "overbearing"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We RELISH it.",
                  "answers": [
                    "dislike",
                    "need",
                    "study",
                    "approve of",
                    "enjoy"
                  ],
                  "word": "RELISH",
                  "correct": "enjoy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DON the coat.",
                  "answers": [
                    "put on",
                    "finish",
                    "brush",
                    "take off",
                    "choose"
                  ],
                  "word": "DON",
                  "correct": "put on"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Typical LIVELIHOOD.",
                  "answers": [
                    "fast dance",
                    "hobby",
                    "criminal",
                    "investment",
                    "means of support"
                  ],
                  "word": "LIVELIHOOD",
                  "correct": "means of support"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "To ASSERT that it is true.",
                  "answers": [
                    "believe",
                    "pretend",
                    "hope",
                    "declare",
                    "deny"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASSERT",
                  "correct": "declare"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INVOKE his mercy.",
                  "answers": [
                    "hope for",
                    "expect",
                    "call upon",
                    "accept",
                    "refuse"
                  ],
                  "word": "INVOKE",
                  "correct": "call upon"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Discussed its UTILITY.",
                  "answers": [
                    "power",
                    "usefulness",
                    "importance",
                    "result",
                    "uselessness"
                  ],
                  "word": "UTILITY",
                  "correct": "usefulness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They PARTITIONED the area.",
                  "answers": [
                    "divided",
                    "sought",
                    "destroyed",
                    "united",
                    "surrounded"
                  ],
                  "word": "PARTITION",
                  "correct": "divided"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GROPE for them.",
                  "answers": [
                    "go out",
                    "wish",
                    "ask angrily",
                    "feel blindly",
                    "wait"
                  ],
                  "word": "GROPE",
                  "correct": "feel blindly"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "A common FALLACY.",
                  "answers": [
                    "false idea",
                    "understanding",
                    "lie",
                    "old saying",
                    "truth"
                  ],
                  "word": "FALLACY",
                  "correct": "false idea"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We must REPRIMAND him.",
                  "answers": [
                    "arrest",
                    "forbid",
                    "scold",
                    "reward",
                    "honor"
                  ],
                  "word": "REPRIMAND",
                  "correct": "scold"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PRESUMPTUOUS people.",
                  "answers": [
                    "timid",
                    "rich",
                    "quick-witted",
                    "overconfident",
                    "nasty"
                  ],
                  "word": "PRESUMPTUOUS",
                  "correct": "overconfident"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HURTLE down the street.",
                  "answers": [
                    "walk slowly",
                    "crawl",
                    "look quickly",
                    "rush violently",
                    "hop"
                  ],
                  "word": "HURTLE",
                  "correct": "rush violently"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Examined the TALON.",
                  "answers": [
                    "claw",
                    "lawyer",
                    "wing",
                    "beak",
                    "criminal"
                  ],
                  "word": "TALON",
                  "correct": "claw"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ENDEAVOR to serve.",
                  "answers": [
                    "hope",
                    "try",
                    "remember",
                    "refuse",
                    "like"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENDEAVCR",
                  "correct": "try"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a DICTATORIAL boss fun to work for?",
                  "word": "DICTATORIAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do most people RELISH the idea of going hungry?",
                  "word": "RELISH",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would you DON your shoes when you're going to bed?",
                  "word": "DON",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does a person who is unemployed have a good LIVELIHOOD?",
                  "word": "LIVELIHOOD",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a person ASSERT that something is true when it really isn't?",
                  "word": "ASSERT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a witch INVOKE evil spirits?",
                  "word": "INVOKE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does an automobile have any UTILITY?",
                  "word": "UTILITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a desk drawer be PARTITIONED?",
                  "word": "PARTITION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a person GROPE for words?",
                  "word": "GROPE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Should you believe a FALLACY?",
                  "word": "FALLACY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would you REPRIMAND someone for being a hero?",
                  "word": "REPRIMAND",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do PRESUMPTUOUS people think they know a lot?",
                  "word": "PRESUMPTUOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do turtles usually HURTLE?",
                  "word": "HURTLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do fish have TALONS?",
                  "word": "TALON",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do runners ENDEAVOR to break records?",
                  "word": "ENDEAVOR",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "The DICTATORIAL secretary was extremely fast at taking shorthand.",
                  "word": "DICTATORIAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He told the story of his opponent's arrest with obvious RELISH.",
                  "word": "RELISH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Jack DONNED his new suit for his first day on the job.",
                  "word": "DON",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He lost his LIVELIHOOD when the factory closed down.",
                  "word": "LIVELIHOOD",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The patriot openly ASSERTED his love for his country.",
                  "word": "ASSERT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They INVOKED Bill's license because of his many speeding tickets.",
                  "word": "INVOKE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We'll never UTILIZE all this equipment. You'll have to take some back.",
                  "word": "UTILITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They PARTITIONED us to come with them.",
                  "word": "PARTITION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Joe GROPED in the closet for the old pair of shoes.",
                  "word": "GROPE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He said the belief that airlines were unsafe was a FALLACY.",
                  "word": "FALLACY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "You will only receive a REPRIMAND this time; next time you will be put in jail.",
                  "word": "REPRIMAND",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It was PRESUMPTUOUS of you to think you could take the car without asking me first.",
                  "word": "PRESUMPTUOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The kitten HURTLED across the room when it saw its supper being prepared.",
                  "word": "HURTLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The bird curved its TALONS around the thin branch.",
                  "word": "TALON",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The ENDEAVOR to put a man on the moon was finally successful.",
                  "word": "ENDEAVCR",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "DICTATORIAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "dominating",
                    "tyrannical",
                    "studious"
                  ],
                  "word": "DICTATORIAL",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RELISH",
                  "answers": [
                    "satisfaction",
                    "delight",
                    "understanding"
                  ],
                  "word": "RELISH",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DON",
                  "answers": [
                    "wear",
                    "dress",
                    "bury"
                  ],
                  "word": "DON",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LIVELIHOOD",
                  "answers": [
                    "earnings",
                    "career",
                    "hobby"
                  ],
                  "word": "LIVELIHOOD",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ASSERT",
                  "answers": [
                    "expect",
                    "insist",
                    "claim"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASSERT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INVOKE",
                  "answers": [
                    "summon",
                    "remember",
                    "appeal"
                  ],
                  "word": "INVOKE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "UTILITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "value",
                    "suitability",
                    "comedy"
                  ],
                  "word": "UTILITY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PARTITION",
                  "answers": [
                    "cut",
                    "separate",
                    "destroy"
                  ],
                  "word": "PARTITION",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GROPE",
                  "answers": [
                    "feel",
                    "throw",
                    "search"
                  ],
                  "word": "GROPE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FALLACY",
                  "answers": [
                    "falsehood",
                    "exception",
                    "mistake"
                  ],
                  "word": "FALLACY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REPRIMAND",
                  "answers": [
                    "kill",
                    "criticize",
                    "blame"
                  ],
                  "word": "REPRIMAND",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PRESUMPTUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "vam",
                    "bold",
                    "stupid"
                  ],
                  "word": "PRESUMPTUOUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HURTLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "worry",
                    "rush",
                    "drive"
                  ],
                  "word": "HURTLE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TALON",
                  "answers": [
                    "toe",
                    "knee",
                    "claw"
                  ],
                  "word": "TALON",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ENDEAVOR",
                  "answers": [
                    "struggle",
                    "escape",
                    "attempt"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENDEAVCR",
                  "correct": "1"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        }
      ],
      "reviewTest": {
        "wordList": [
          {
            "word": "ANGUISH",
            "answer": "anguish"
          },
          {
            "word": "CLAD",
            "answer": "clad"
          },
          {
            "word": "ENDEAVOR",
            "answer": "endeavor"
          },
          {
            "word": "LIVELIHOOD",
            "answer": "livelihood"
          },
          {
            "word": "PARTITION",
            "answer": "partitioned"
          },
          {
            "word": "ASSERT",
            "answer": "asserted"
          },
          {
            "word": "CONSPICUOUS",
            "answer": "conspicuous"
          },
          {
            "word": "GIST",
            "answer": "gist"
          },
          {
            "word": "NARRATIVE",
            "answer": "narrative"
          },
          {
            "word": "PRESUMPTUOUS",
            "answer": "presumptuous"
          },
          {
            "word": "CASTE",
            "answer": "castes"
          },
          {
            "word": "DICTATORIAL",
            "answer": "dictatorial"
          },
          {
            "word": "INVOKE",
            "answer": "invoked"
          },
          {
            "word": "ORNATE",
            "answer": "ornate"
          },
          {
            "word": "REPRIMAND",
            "answer": "reprimanded"
          },
          {
            "word": "CIRCUITOUS",
            "answer": "circuitous"
          },
          {
            "word": "DON",
            "answer": "donned"
          },
          {
            "word": "JURISDICTION",
            "answer": "jurisdiction"
          },
          {
            "word": "PANDEMONIUM",
            "answer": "pandemonium"
          },
          {
            "word": "SOMBER",
            "answer": "somber"
          },
          {
            "word": "ANECDOTE",
            "answer": "anecdotes"
          },
          {
            "word": "DEVISE",
            "answer": "devise"
          },
          {
            "word": "DWINDLE",
            "answer": "dwindle"
          },
          {
            "word": "HURTLE",
            "answer": "hurtle"
          },
          {
            "word": "REALM",
            "answer": "realm"
          },
          {
            "word": "ANNIHILATE",
            "answer": "annihilated"
          },
          {
            "word": "DIMINISH",
            "answer": "diminished"
          },
          {
            "word": "EFFERVESCENT",
            "answer": "effervescent"
          },
          {
            "word": "IMPEDIMENT",
            "answer": "impediment"
          },
          {
            "word": "RELISH",
            "answer": "relish"
          },
          {
            "word": "BEDLAM",
            "answer": "bedlam"
          },
          {
            "word": "DISCORD",
            "answer": "discord"
          },
          {
            "word": "FALLACY",
            "answer": "fallacy"
          },
          {
            "word": "JAUNT",
            "answer": "jaunt"
          },
          {
            "word": "TALON",
            "answer": "talons"
          },
          {
            "word": "DEFRAUD",
            "answer": "defraud"
          },
          {
            "word": "DISSIPATE",
            "answer": "dissipated"
          },
          {
            "word": "GROPE",
            "answer": "groped"
          },
          {
            "word": "JOVIAL",
            "answer": "jovial"
          },
          {
            "word": "TUMULT",
            "answer": "tumult"
          },
          {
            "word": "DEPLORABLE",
            "answer": "deplorable"
          },
          {
            "word": "DORMANT",
            "answer": "dormant"
          },
          {
            "word": "HUE",
            "answer": "hue"
          },
          {
            "word": "MERCANTILE",
            "answer": "mercantile"
          },
          {
            "word": "UTILITY",
            "answer": "utility"
          }
        ],
        "questions": [
          {
            "part1": "His",
            "part2": "methods upset everyone. If he'd just ask nicely instead of demanding to be obeyed he'd be a lot better off.",
            "correct": "dictatorial",
            "word": "DICTATORIAL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Jim's mother",
            "part2": "him because his room was such a mess.",
            "correct": "reprimanded",
            "word": "REPRIMAND"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The news that her son was missing in action caused her great",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "anguish",
            "word": "ANGUISH"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The people of India's lowest",
            "part2": "are traditionally called the \"Untouchables.\"",
            "correct": "castes",
            "word": "CASTE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Everyone stared at the strangely",
            "part2": "man wearing a clown's hat, a red cape, and long pointed shoes.",
            "correct": "clad",
            "word": "CLAD"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He kept us spellbound during the",
            "part2": "of his escape from the cannibals.",
            "correct": "narrative",
            "word": "NARRATIVE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Tom was so",
            "part2": "in his wild costume that people could easily spot him from the other side of the hall.",
            "correct": "conspicuous",
            "word": "CONSPICUOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "At the height of the party it was utter",
            "part2": "around here. I thought for sure the police would come.",
            "correct": "pandemonium",
            "word": "PANDEMONIUM"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He asked only for the",
            "part2": "of your statement, not an explanation of every word in it.",
            "correct": "gist",
            "word": "GIST"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The champion publicly",
            "part2": "that he was the best boxer in the world.",
            "correct": "asserted",
            "word": "ASSERT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "They",
            "part2": "the area to make several smaller offices out of the one large space.",
            "correct": "partitioned",
            "word": "PARTITION"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The salesman's",
            "part2": "depended on people's believing what he told them.",
            "correct": "livelihood",
            "word": "LIVELIHOOD"
          },
          {
            "part1": "She told them they must all",
            "part2": "to lose weight, no matter how difficult it would be.",
            "correct": "endeavor",
            "word": "ENDEAVOR"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The judge said that, since the events had taken place in another state, he didn't have any",
            "part2": "in the case.",
            "correct": "jurisdiction",
            "word": "JURISDICTION"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Alice",
            "part2": "her heaviest coat when she went out into the snowstorm.",
            "correct": "donned",
            "word": "DON"
          },
          {
            "part1": "They",
            "part2": "the Bill of Rights as support for their argument.",
            "correct": "invoked",
            "word": "INVOKE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The main road was closed, so we had to take a rather",
            "part2": "route to get home.",
            "correct": "circuitous",
            "word": "CIRCUITOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His language was",
            "part2": ", full of long sentences and elaborate descriptions.",
            "correct": "ornate",
            "word": "ORNATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "assistant thought he knew best, so he never bothered to ask his boss for permission before he did anything.",
            "correct": "presumptuous",
            "word": "PRESUMPTUOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The judge had a(n)",
            "part2": "expression on his face as he explained why he had to sentence the man to die.",
            "correct": "somber",
            "word": "SOMBER"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The idea that man couldn't fly because he didn't have wings was a common",
            "part2": "in the old days.",
            "correct": "fallacy",
            "word": "FALLACY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The argument over who owned the land created a great deal of",
            "part2": "between the two neighbors.",
            "correct": "discord",
            "word": "DISCORD"
          },
          {
            "part1": "That weekend they went on a short",
            "part2": "to the mountains.",
            "correct": "jaunt",
            "word": "JAUNT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "They",
            "part2": "around in the dark trying to find her earring.",
            "correct": "groped",
            "word": "GROPE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Buying and selling is the everyday business of",
            "part2": "companies.",
            "correct": "mercantile",
            "word": "MERCANTILE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Our army",
            "part2": "the enemy's forces. There was nothing left of them by the end of the battle.",
            "correct": "annihilated",
            "word": "ANNIHILATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Jane didn't",
            "part2": "the thought of making the long trip home by herself.",
            "correct": "relish",
            "word": "RELISH"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Bill accused them of trying to",
            "part2": "him of his money with their real-estate scheme.",
            "correct": "defraud",
            "word": "DEFRAUD"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Amy didn't like the vivid",
            "part2": "of the dress, so she decided to return it to the store.",
            "correct": "hue",
            "word": "HUE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The house was in",
            "part2": "condition. No one had fixed or cleaned anything in years.",
            "correct": "deplorable",
            "word": "DEPLORABLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "In one year he",
            "part2": "his life's savings on gambling and drinking.",
            "correct": "dissipated",
            "word": "DISSIPATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Mark's",
            "part2": "personality seemed to light up any room he entered.",
            "correct": "effervescent",
            "word": "EFFERVESCENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "This piece of furniture is pretty to look at but it doesn't have much",
            "part2": ". I don't think It would ever come in handy.",
            "correct": "utility",
            "word": "UTILITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His musical talent lay",
            "part2": "until he began composing in his forties.",
            "correct": "dormant",
            "word": "DORMANT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Bad weather was a serious",
            "part2": "to rescuing the shipwrecked sailors.",
            "correct": "impediment",
            "word": "IMPEDIMENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "I can 't stand all this",
            "part2": "; I have to go someplace where there's peace and quiet.",
            "correct": "bedlam",
            "word": "BEDLAM"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The racing cars",
            "part2": "around the track at over two hundred miles an hour.",
            "correct": "hurtle",
            "word": "HURTLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "It would be impossible to",
            "part2": "a more efficient system than the one we have now.",
            "correct": "devise",
            "word": "DEVISE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "People came from throughout his",
            "part2": "to see the crowning of the new king.",
            "correct": "realm",
            "word": "REALM"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We watched the burning candles",
            "part2": "until there was nothing left of them.",
            "correct": "dwindle",
            "word": "DWINDLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The bird's sharp",
            "part2": "dug into the soft bark of the tree.",
            "correct": "talons",
            "word": "TALON"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The population of the town",
            "part2": "year after year until finally there were only a few people left.",
            "correct": "diminished",
            "word": "DIMINISH"
          },
          {
            "part1": "She was such a(n)",
            "part2": "woman that everyone around her became happy and full of fun too.",
            "correct": "jovial",
            "word": "JOVIAL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "There was",
            "part2": "outside the bar until the police came and quieted things down.",
            "correct": "tumult",
            "word": "TUMULT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We listened with delight to his many",
            "part2": "about famous people he had met.",
            "correct": "anecdotes",
            "word": "ANECDOTE"
          }
        ],
        "type": "fitb"
      }
    }
  ]
}